Timing and subtitles brought to you by The Imperial Coroners @ Viki.com
The Prefect's mansion is on fire.
Take me there.
Once Li Zhang was into trouble,
then the people who dressed like soldiers of the Military Commissioner
set the Prefect's Mansion on fire.
Jing Yi got poisoned and went crazy the night he entered the military camp.
I assume Duke Chang is related to it.
Your Highness, it's datura flower.
Is there something hiding about General Leng's illness?
Chu Chu, do you still remember
the two people who tried to kill Xu Rugui?
Yes.
I remember you said after the autopsy that they were both soldiers.
Your Highness, why do you mention this?
These people are also soldiers.
Jinli found out that before we went into the mountain with Li Zhang,
more than twenty soldiers left the camp to buy supplies
under Wu Chen's order.
This is exactly the number of soldiers who showed up in the Prefect's mansion.
But Wu Chen doesn't have the power to dispatch troops.
Therefore, it must be someone very powerful behind this.
What's more, from the traces of the scene in the wood house that day,
except for the Shence Army who came to kill Xu Rugui,
there was another group of people who wanted to capture Xu Rugui alive.
Your Highness, why do you think
it's General Leng who sent people to arrest Xu Rugui?
It's just my speculation.
At this point, if they want Xu Rugui,
it must be for his value as a bargaining chip
instead of his identity.
I shouldn't say these things to bore you.
It's late. Go to bed.
I want to stay with you.
[The Imperial Coroner]
[Episode 29]
Jinyu, I've found out that it was Hou Bin who sent those people out to buy herbs.
They used to be bandits and they were incorporated into the army.
Take me to him.
This one.
My child... My child...!
Hou Bin!
Hou Bin! Hou Bin!
- Get a doctor now!
- Yes!
- Hou Bin. Hou Bin!
- My child...
- Hang in there.
Hou Bin! Hou Bin!
Hou Bin!
What happened?
I'm late.
He stabbed himself.
If I had come earlier,
I could have stopped him.
Chu Chu, can you find out what he just ate?
There is no food residue in his mouth.
I can't tell now.
Have you two been guarding here?
Yes, Your Highness.
Has anyone been here after General Hou came back?
No.
After General Hou came back from the infirmary,
he has been staying in the barracks by himself.
The two of us are keeping watch outside.
We never left.
What's going on here?
General Hou was poisoned.
Poisoned?
Chu Chu, examine his body carefully
and find the source of his toxins as soon as possible.
Your Highness, General Hou's belly has been cut open by himself.
The evidence may disappear in a while.
Can I perform an autopsy on him now?
Autopsy?
How can you cut him while his remains are scarcely cold yet?
What are you yelling about?
Don't you know the military rules?
How dare you obstruct Commandery Prince An's investigation?
- Get out and take fifty floggings!
- Yes.
Hold on.
General Leng, they are not obstructing the investigation.
No relatives or friends of the deceased
are willing to let anyone perform an autopsy on the deceased.
But General Hou was murdered.
I promise I will restore his body after the autopsy.
We've known our mistakes. We are willing to be punished.
Take General Hou to the mortuary first, then take your punishment.
Yes.
Miss Chu, please.
Hou, how is your injury now?
When did you get injured again?
Just a flesh wound.
It doesn't matter.
How does it not matter?
Isn't it your flesh?
It doesn't matter?
I heard from Wu Chen that your injury hasn't healed yet.
You are even having malignant sores.
You don't even apply the ointment Doctor Qi gave you on time.
Are you trying to show how tough you are or are you just stupid?
All right. All right.
You two big men are even more naggy than my wife.
It doesn't look like an arrow made by the Tang armies.
No, this was used by the bandits.
I was young and aggressive when I just joined the army.
I followed Hou Bin to suppress the bandits once.
I was eager to make achievements and I fell for their trick.
Hou Bin got shot by many arrows upon saving me.
This arrow was so close to his heart that he missed death by an inch.
I wanted to keep this arrow to remind myself.
But he insisted on keeping it.
He said if I get impulsive again, he will remind me of this with it.
Now I get impulsive again, but he is gone.
General Leng valued him a lot during the past year.
Last year, the Vice Military Commissioner stepped down due to illness.
Zhao Jie should have been promoted by seniority.
But Hou Bin got promoted in the end.
And I found out it was he who sent those people out to buy herbs.
Also, it was he who took the bandits in.
So I started to suspect him.
Before General Hou died...
My child... My child...!
He seemed to be saying something about his child.
Do you know what that is about?
He should be talking about his wife and son.
About three or four years ago, his wife died in childbirth.
He lost his wife and his son.
He and his wife loved each other very much.
It hit him quite hard.
Does it have anything to do with his death?
Maybe it does.
Jinli.
Does General Hou also play with dung beetles?
It's a folk prescription in the Southwest.
Dung beetles in honey with some vinegar.
It's for treating malignant sores.
We use it a lot in the army.
Is there anything wrong with it?
General Zhao, there is blood on your hand.
It's fine.
I guess I got it from General Zhao when we were standing together.
Prepare some water. I'll take a bath.
Yes.
Your Highness.
The new wound on General Hou's abdomen was the one
that he cut from left to right
[Autopsy Report]
with his right hand holding a knife.
But that wound is different from a normal one.
What's the difference?
Whether it's cut by others or by oneself, that person will feel pain
when his flesh is cut.
And he will dodge when he feels pain.
The wound will vary in depth.
Especially when you cut yourself.
No matter how tough you are,
you will use less strength because of the pain.
The wound is deep when you insert the sword but shallow when you draw it out.
Bur General Hou's wound is different.
There is almost no change in the depth of his wound.
As if he couldn't feel pain.
Yes.
Did he do something else after he cut open his abdomen,
as if he was looking for something in his abdomen
and trying to take it out?
Your Highness, how do you know that?
I couldn't believe it at first.
But I checked it many times.
His viscera are in a mess.
He reached in and pulled them around.
Chu Chu, does General Hou have malignant sores?
Yes. There are many marks of old wounds on his body.
Especially the one that runs through his chest.
It hasn't fully healed.
Looks like he relapsed many times.
There are two malignant sores on his back around the perforated wound.
It was treated sloppily.
There was a sour smell on the surface with some fine powder.
I guess he used a folk prescription in Qianzhou.
The prescription of dung beetles in honey?
You even know the folk prescription in the Southwest?
You are so good.
It's just my speculation.
Chu Chu, did the three dead soldiers
also have malignant sores on them?
I can't tell from the man who burned himself.
But there are malignant sores on the men who were drowned and strangled to death.
Did they also use this prescription?
The drowned soldier was submerged.
I can't tell if he used it.
But the strangled soldier's wound is broken.
Obviously he used it.
Your Highness, what's wrong?
Is there any problem?
No, that's right.
I know how they were poisoned.
You'd better stay quiet.
Something happened tonight.
No one has time to take care of you.
You are not like Xiao Jinyu's people at all.
I did it for your own good.
After everything is over, I will release you.
You are a rebel!
You know nothing about it.
Did you see that?
My life is coming to an end.
What did I go through these troubles for?
I did it all for you, for the Leng clan!
Bah!
The Leng clan has been guarding the Southwest for Tang for generations and we are brave and loyal.
If it wasn't for your greed for power,
how would the emperor grant a marriage to me and Xiao Jinli?
All these years I've been trying to escape from such a fate.
Now you are saying you did it for me and for the Leng clan?
I will never believe you.
The Leng clan will never believe you!
You can kill me now, or after I untie the ropes,
I will kill you by myself even to be blamed as the black sheep of our family!
Fine.
I'll give you what you want!
General Leng!
What are you doing?
Your Highness.
- Chu Chu.
- Get up.
This is my family affair.
It's none of your concern.
There is no family affair between us.
Commandery Prince An, do you need anything?
I didn't see Leng Yue and I was a little worried.
I was going to see Wu Chen, the secretary
in charge of military supplies, and ask him a few questions.
I passed by and vaguely heard Leng Yue's voice.
So I came here to have a look.
Your Highness, I asked him why he concealed his illness from the court.
He knocked me out with his hand and tied me up.
He said he will release me after everything is over.
Your Highness.
General Leng, it's your family affair
and it's about your military business, I shouldn't ask too much.
But considering what happened tonight, to avoid misunderstanding,
I want to ask you one question.
Did you really not report your illness to the court?
What do you mean?
You may not know that the Minister of War, Feng Jie, was murdered
when he arrived in Chang'an.
There was a special volume of inspection notes missing.
What?
After I learned about your condition, I asked Jinli about it
and he remembered that you once talked to Minister Feng alone
for half a day during his inspection.
That's right. I did tell my condition to Feng Jie on that day.
It concerns the military power in the Southwest
and the future of the Leng family after my death.
It also concerns the safety of the Southwest border in Tang.
I know how important it is.
I've discussed with Feng Jie that I would keep my condition a secret
so as to stabilize the military spirit
and prevent the bandits from creating a disturbance in the Southwest.
Feng Jie would write down my condition
and present it to His Majesty in person
to come up with a good solution.
I didn't know Feng Jie died so suddenly as he arrived in Chang'an.
I didn't receive any imperial edict.
I thought His Majesty would appoint a new Minister of War
and that's why Xue Rucheng came to Qianzhou.
But he didn't set foot in my camp.
He just returned to Chang'an like that.
So there were several mysterious deaths in the camp
when I asked Leng Yue to send you a letter and greet you.
It was such a coincidence.
No wonder you got suspicious.
Then you sent me a letter and invited me to investigate the case
to find out if I was up to other things
and to make sure Leng Yue was safe. Right?
You want me to find out the fact, but you don't trust me that much.
So you are not going to tell me the truth.
But Leng Yue acted impulsively and had a fight with you.
You had no choice but to keep her in your barracks
to keep her safe after everything becomes clear.
Am I right?
You are smart indeed.
General Leng, is the moxa stick yours?
Yes.
I had rheumatism once.
Nothing worked.
The doctor asked me to burn a moxa stick and keep using it.
Although rheumatism can't be totally cured,
at least it can alleviate the pain.
Your Highness, there is something wrong with the moxie.
- What's wrong?
- This moxa is a little darker than the normal moxa.
And there is a strange smell.
Let me take a look.
- There is cinnabar in it.
- Cinnabar?
This moxa is mixed with cinnabar.
The burning cinnabar is poisonous.
It's hard to be noticed while being mixed in the moxa.
Grandpa, there is a reason that you became ill.
It's because of the moxa.
Where did you get the moxa?
Wu Chen.
It's still warm. He just left.
- Soldiers.
- Yes.
Pass down my order. Guard all the entrances and the exits.
Search every corner of the camp. You must find Wu Chen out.
Yes.
General Leng, are you sure that Wu Chen gave the moxa to you?
Are you looking for the evidence that he tried to kill me?
I'm here to find the evidence that he poisoned the soldiers.
He poisoned the soldiers?
Did he kill Hou Bin?
I'm afraid he is responsible for the recent events in the army.
What a bold bastard!
If I get him, I will skin him alive.
Jinyu.
I've found it out.
Feng Li who strangled himself has someone in his family who also hanged himself.
Wang Chi, who drowned himself, had some relatives who drowned
in a flood in his hometown.
And General Xu who rushed into the fire, his old house caught fire
and his mother died in theflames.
The three of them are just like General Hou.
They were away from home when something happened to their loved ones.
They had been feeling guilty.
Your Highness, this was found in the ashes of the incense burner.
Show it to me.
Your Highness, this is the powder made from the seeds of datura flower.
General Leng, this is what makes the soldiers in the camp go crazy for no reason.
Wu Chen used it as a drug enhancer
which can make the victims see illusions.
These illusions are associated with
the long-suppressed painful experiences of the victims.
As long as the murderer knows enough about these people's experiences,
he can guess what kind of illusions
they will see when the poison starts to work.
Then he can design the way they kill themselves.
How did he do it?
I thought at first that maybe someone used poison.
We used a lot of methods
to ensure the safety of food and drinking water in the army.
Where else could he put the poison in?
He mixed the datura flower powder
in the medicine for treating malignant sores.
[Sterculia lychnophora]
Those who have malignant sores will be poisoned when they apply it.
Commandery Prince An and I have checked it.
All the soldiers who have gone crazy all had malignant sores
and they all used the same prescription to treat the malignant sore.
But Jing...
But Dog doesn't have any malignant sores.
How did he get poisoned?
He doesn't have malignant sores.
But he touched the most critical ingredient for treating malignant sores.
What?
The living dung beetles raised in the infirmary.
Dung beetles?
Chu Chu and I have checked the infirmary.
I think Wu Chen mixed the datura powder
into the baked dung beetle powder when he counted the medicinal supplies.
Because the jar of dung beetle powder
was next to the jar of living dung beetles,
some powder floated into the jar of the living dung beetles.
Dog accidentally got some powder on his hand
during the dung beetle race with the wounded soldiers without knowing it.
I guess he got excited and then he just took the water and drank it.
That's how he got poisoned.
The seeds of the datura flower are hard to get.
There are tight restrictions on entering and leaving the camp.
I asked Jinli to check the records.
The only person who touched the jar of dung beetle powder
and is able to bring the datura flower powder back to the camp
is Wu Chen in charge of military supplies.
Your Highness, please check this out.
Your Highness, this is the kind of moxa used by my grandpa.
The moxa should be brought here in a whole box.
The moxa sticks in General Leng's barracks
can only cover three or four days.
Yes.
These moxa sticks are not enough to replenish a whole box.
According to Jinli, those who left to buy supplies won't be back in ten days,
which means Wu Chen didn't plan to keep poisoning you.
Did he stop because he knew we were coming here?
No.
General Leng, I was taking a bath in my barracks.
Sorry, I'm late.
Take your men to search for Wu Chen.
You must find him out before dawn.
Search for Wu Chen? What's wrong?
- Hurry up!
- Yes.
Hold on.
General Zhao, please remind the soldiers
that he might dress up as a soldier and blend in the search team.
Got it.
All these soldiers can't even find a civil official.
Can he fly or go under the ground?
General Leng, one night has passed.
I think they have searched all the places in the camp
where he can hide himself.
General Leng, please order your men to pay attention to the places
where only the dead can stay.
You mean...
Wu Chen is dead?
If he hasn't escaped from the army and he isn't among the soldiers,
then there is only one possibility left.
General Leng. Commandery Prince An.
We have found Wu Chen.
These two cooks found Wu Chen's body in the well
when they went to draw water this morning.
Has anyone been here before?
I have asked them.
They were searching all night.
Countless people passed here.
The footprints are messy.
The bottoms of their shoes are the same. We can't tell anything.
The deceased male is over 30.
His mouth and eyes are slightly open. There is a swelling on his abdomen.
There are bruises caused by struggling.
There is foam in his nose and mouth.
He was drowned.
[Nasal cavity Oral cavity]
But his body has been soaked in water,
it's hard to determine the exact time of his death.
I assume he died between 1:00 and 5:00 a.m.
Between 1:00 and 5:00?
That's when Hou Bin died and we were searching for him.
Could he have jumped into the well in desperation
when we were looking for him?
He might have been holding this rope and hiding in the well.
He didn't expect that we would search for him all night.
He lost his strength gradually, so he fell into the well and drowned.
This place is not close to the three entrances and exits of the camp.
And it's not on the way from his barracks to the exit.
Even when he was fleeing from us, he shouldn't hide here.
Are you suspecting that Wu Chen was murdered?
Chu Chu, perform a thorough autopsy on him.
Go ahead and do what you need to do. I'll sign the approval paper for you.
Okay.
But, Your Highness, I need something first.
Miss Chu, just tell us what you need.
As long as we have it, we will give it to you.
Thank you, General Leng.
I need green onion, pepper, salt, white plum, lees (deposits of dead yeast or residual yeast), vinegar,
one garlic mortar, and two mats.
Please find an open space in the camp for me.
I need to dig a two-meter pit and burn some firewood in the pit.
Are you going to cook?
I want to braise him.
Chu Chu, are you going to eat him?
No, no.
I'm not going to eat him.
Braising him with my method
can let us know if he jumped into the well by himself.
General Leng, Chu Chu is from a family of coroners.
She often uses some unusual but really useful methods.
I think you should let her try it.
- Cooks.
- Yes!
Bring the stuff Miss Chu needs.
Yes.
Thank you, General Leng.
Zhao Jie. Jinli.
Yes.
Do whatever Miss Chu says.
Leng Yue, stay here and help Chu Chu.
Okay.
Commandery Prince An, can we talk in your room?
General Leng, please.
Please.
[Jiangshan Hall]
You've read the memorial of Commandery Prince An.
The Prefect of Qianzhou, Li Zhang, has been brought to justice.
But Commandery Prince An thinks
Li Zhang is not the main culprit behind the illegal minting of coins.
What do you think?
[Memorial]
I think what Commandery Prince An said is reasonable.
Minister Wang,
what Commandery Prince An wrote in the memorial,
except for the arrest of Li Zhang,
the evidence of the rest of the events has all been destroyed.
It can just be his side of the story.
How is it reasonable?
Your Majesty, I think Commandery Prince An is putting himself off and fooling you.
Now he has gone to the camp of the Military Commissioner of Qianzhou
in the name of investigating the case.
He is meddling in military affairs and acting beyond his authority.
Minister Han, when I went to the Southwest,
Commandery Prince An mentioned this case to me.
The case of illegal minting of coins is really complicated.
It's understandable that Commandery Prince An
couldn't make it clear for the moment.
Minister Xue, you two are really interesting.
You are his teacher and the head of the Ministry of War.
You were ordered to go to the Southwest to inspect military affairs.
You found out nothing about the military affairs.
But now you are meddling in the affairs of the Three Judicial Offices.
Commandery Prince An is the head of the Three Judicial Offices.
There is no end to his investigation of the illegal minting of coins.
Now he is meddling in the military affairs of the Southwest.
The both of you acted beyond your authority.
Does Commandery Prince An have a bad influence on his noble teacher
or did you mislead your clever student?
Commandery Prince An only mentioned a few words about the illegal minting when we were chatting.
As for why he went to General Leng's army,
I believe he will give us an explanation.
General Leng has always ruled his army rigorously.
He won't let others lay a hand on military affairs that easily.
You are so interested in the affairs of the Three Judicial Offices,
then you should bring back the rebels who survived.
But you didn't bring back the person you should bring back,
you even lost the person you shouldn't bring back.
Commandery Prince An was ordered to investigate the illegal minting case.
Now it turns out like this.
Shouldn't he thank his teacher for that?
The illegal minting of coins has always been a major case.
Commandery Prince An has the right to act at his discretion,
but he went to the Southwest this time to look for his father.
He didn't take much luggage and many attendants.
Maybe he just needs some help.
Ask the Military Commissioner for help?
What does he want to do?
The Commandery Prince entered the camp of the Military Commissioner in private.
Minister Xue, you've taught a wonderful student.
Minister Xue is the teacher of Commandery Prince An.
It's normal that they mentioned a few words about official business
when they were chatting.
But what Minister Han said is true.
There is no solid evidence in the memorial.
No matter what, Li Zhang is still a prefect of a state.
Even he wants to arrest him, he should have irrefutable proof.
Right now, Commandery Prince An couldn't find out the truth.
So he claimed that there is someone else behind Li Zhang.
He is smart indeed.
Minister Xue, am I right?
Your Majesty.
Commandery Prince An failed in his task, made decisions without authorization,
deceived his superior and subordinates, intervened in military affairs, and acted beyond his authority.
He should be brought back to Chang'an and be punished.
Minister Jing, what do you think?
I think there is another possibility that's why
Commandery Prince An only mentioned his speculation
but not any solid evidence.
It's not because there is no real evidence.
Commandery Prince An worries that some treacherous men
might take the letter away and cause unnecessary troubles.
Commandery Prince An has always been thoughtful and cautious.
Your Majesty, I think you can order him to come back first.
After Commandery Prince An returns to Chang'an,
if there is no real evidence
to prove his speculation in this memorial,
you can punish him at that time.
Yes, Senior Jing has a point.
Your Majesty, I think what Senior Jing said is reasonable.
If you are going to punish Commandery Prince An,
you should punish him after he returns to Chang'an.
Your Majesty, I also agree with what Senior Jing said.
All right, let me think about it.
You can leave now.
Yes, Your Majesty.
Timing and subtitles brought to you by The Imperial Coroners @ Viki.com
♫  Nothing can stop me  ♫
♫  From missing you all the time  ♫
♫  The moonlight appears, cold in the late night,
as the world changes  ♫
♫  Only with you by my side can I embrace my yearning for you  ♫
♫  When I close my eyes I meet you once again  ♫
♫  I'll gently brush your hair by your ear  ♫
♫  Life is long, with love and regrets in this world  ♫
♫  With you by my side, no matter how far I go,
we'll never be apart  ♫
♫  With your smile, in this moment, let me
cherish this lifetime  ♫
♫  Only for you, I have to worry about the end of this life  ♫
♫  I’m still young, with my love not yet realized for you, but I'm
willing to be here for you till the end
♫  You can rely on me in this lifetime  ♫
♫  Hope to spend this beautiful lifetime together  ♫