Timing and subtitles brought to you by The Imperial Coroners @ Viki.com
Xu Rugui used Chu Chu's identity
and induced Chu He to help him escape.
I don't know if he is alive now.
I am a survivor of the rebellious party.
But Commandery Prince An jumped into the river to save me without hesitation.
I didn't realize how special Chu Chu was to me.
But Chu He is also...
You must go home when I ask you to.
If you really see yourself as the coroner of Three Judicial Offices,
you must follow my orders.
If you think of my words as unworthy of your attention,
you shouldn't keep working for me.
Three Judicial Offices will be fine with one less coroner.
Come on, Miss Chu.
Let's go, come on.
Three Judicial Offices will be fine with one less coroner?
You too. Out.
[The Imperial Coroner]
[Episode 19]
Take it.
Come again.
I won't charge you if it's not tasty.
General Xiao, what's wrong with His Highness?
He...
Is he angry with me because I jumped into the water to save my brother?
- I'm good at swimming.
- Take a look.
He saw it.
Do you only see Chu He as your brother?
Of course.
What about Commandery Prince An?
What do you think of him?
- I think of him as a prince.
- Umbrella!
General Xiao, what do you want to say?
Umbrella!
Forget it. It's too complicated to be explained in a few words.
Miss Chu!
Deputy Magistrate Tan.
Is my brother awake?
General Xiao.
Miss Chu, don't worry.
It's not about Chu He.
Miss Chu, I don't know if it is convenient for you to have a few words with me.
Deputy Magistrate Tan, what's the matter?
Delicious rice noodles!
Since that thing happened in the Xu Mansion,
I have always wanted to talk to you but have never gotten the chance.
Deputy Magistrate Tan, you can just tell me.
When Xu Zongfang took you to the Xu Mansion,
there were only my father, Xu Zongfang and you in that room.
Now my father is gone
and Xu Zongfang is missing,
I can only ask you about what happened on that day.
- Well...
- Miss Chu, my father died a tragic death.
As his son, I don't even know the cause.
I've been anxious during these days
and I don't know how to face my mother.
Please let me know what happened.
Deputy Magistrate Tan, get up.
Xu Zongfang said that day that he wanted to avenge my mother.
If you want to avenge your mother, I can do it for you.
Then he killed Butler Tan.
My mother died an unfair death.
But I never wanted to avenge her in such a way.
Miss Chu, don't worry.
I don't blame you at all.
Thank you for telling me the truth.
I hope you can do me another favor.
Please don't tell Commandery Prince An about our conversation today.
Why?
I'm the Deputy Magistrate and the son of the deceased.
It's nothing wrong with asking that.
But for the sake of my career,
I think I should avoid arousing suspicion.
Okay.
Thank you, Miss Chu.
Vice Minister Jing.
- Are you going home?
- Yes.
From the County Office to the Xu Mansion, you shouldn't go this way.
Vice Minister Jing, do you have any instructions?
I asked you to send out the message.
Why haven't I gotten any news from you?
Vice Minister Jing, I'll let you know immediately if I have any news.
Deputy Magistrate Tan, you should know
that I can tell if you are lying.
I... I dare not.
You got some news, but it's not for me.
It's for you, right?
Have you verified Chu Chu's identity?
Senior Jing doesn't want to get you involved.
Please don't waste his good intention.
What kind of things that I can't get involved in?
Are you going to...
Vice Minister Jing,
I've handled such matters many times.
Please don't worry about it.
My family is preparing for the funeral and there are a lot of things to do.
I should leave.
Your Grace.
Today, I got a very interesting endgame by chance.
I thought that you were a master of chess, so I'm here to consult you.
Have you ever seen such an endgame?
No, I haven't.
Please, Senior Jing.
Please, Your Grace.
Senior Jing, I remember when you and your wife got married,
my mother gave you a pair of lily hairpins as a wedding gift.
I wonder if that pair of hairpins is still in your mansion.
Your Grace, that's a hard question for me.
You know my wife well.
She buys a handful of hairpins all the time.
There are more hairpins in my mansion than the chopsticks in the kitchen.
They all look the same.
How can I recognize it?
Why do you suddenly ask about that?
A few days ago when I was at the flower market,
I saw someone wearing a similar one.
It just occurred to me.
I guess maybe Madam Jing gave it to someone else.
I'm just curious.
I'll ask her when I get back, then I'll let you know.
I know you are quite worried about the marriage of General Xiao
and Leng Peishan's daughter.
I want to give you a piece of advice.
I hope you can make this marriage happen as soon as possible.
A good marriage is fated. Why should we rush it?
A good relationship is fated. But human effort is the decisive factor.
This matter should be decided sooner than later.
Thank you for your concern.
I'll find a master and see if their dates of birth and eight characters match.
Then I'll discuss this with the emperor.
Your Grace, you are superb in chess.
I'm truly impressed.
You are flattering me.
Stop looking.
You are in Guanling Yamen now.
Why am I in Guanling Yamen?
Chu Chu?
Where's Chu Chu?
I want to see Chu Chu.
I want to see my sister!
Where is my sister?
Do you still see her as your sister?
Of course, she is my sister. Could it be...
Didn't Chu Chu tell you that her biological father, Yun Yi,
killed Xiao Jinyu and Xiao Jinli's father?
They must want to take revenge on her.
You killed my sister?
Listen!  If you dare do anything to my sister,
I will fight you with my life!
Fight me with your life?
Fight me with this?
You... You keep saying that Chu Chu is your sister.
That's how you put your sister in danger?
Listen! Chu Chu is at home now, telling your family that you are safe.
She is fine.
But she almost got killed in the river because of you.
Commandery Prince An, I did this all by myself.
It has nothing to do with Chu Chu.
It has nothing to do with my family.
What did you do?
I...
I heard the man who kidnapped Chu Chu,
was Chu Chu's uncle, Xu Zongfang.
I wanted to ask him if he was Chu Chu's family
and who else there was in Chu Chu's family.
But...
he told me
Chu Chu's father is the rebel who killed your father.
You two took Chu Chu out to kill her.
You just took that bandit's words?
I didn't.
But I worried...
I worried that you would imprison Chu Chu and interrogate her
if you knew about it.
It happened many years ago.
What can you find out?
His words were clear and logical.
If you take his words
and believe that Chu Chu is the child of your enemy,
she will be wronged.
That's why you gave him this filing blade and help him escape?
Chu Chu is my sister.
She is innocent.
I have to save her.
You were putting her in danger!
Chu He, even you don't trust my conduct,
you should have considered the possibility that the bandit was lying
and inducing you to untie him.
What you did was put Chu Chu in the position of being disloyal!
If what the bandit said were true and you helped him take away Chu Chu,
then Chu Chu would be doubly guilty.
Everyone in the Chu family would be punished.
If that bandit managed to escape, killed everyone in the Chu family
and killed innocent people, can you afford such a result?
Can Chu Chu afford it?
- I...
- As a coroner working in the County Office,
you are also a public servant.
But you acted recklessly.
You don't deserve to be called a faithful and upright subject as Chu Chu said.
You kept saying that what you did was for Chu Chu.
Do you have the nerve to say it again in front of Chu Chu?
Commandery Prince An.
I was too worried to think clearly.
You can punish me as you want.
Please don't punish Chu Chu and my family.
I'm glad you know your mistake.
As a matter of fact, Chu Chu knows what that bandit said
and she told me everything.
What did Chu Chu tell you?
Chu Chu and I are both public servants.
Chu Chu trusts me and I trust her.
I will handle it impartially and clarify the truth.
I won't wrong Chu Chu.
You can rest assured.
You must also remember not to do such stupid things again.
Otherwise, you won't be the only one to be punished.
I won't.
I won't do it again.
Let me ask you. How did you fall into the river?
After I gave the filing blade to Xu Rugui,
I kept an eye on the coffin shop.
I found Xu Rugui escaped after killing people.
There were also two bandits chasing him.
Did you fight with them?
No, no.
I followed them from a distance.
They were particularly cautious and I was almost spotted.
Then I slipped and fell into the river.
Did you see where they were heading for?
The northeast.
It seemed to be the direction of Phoenix Mountain.
Get up first.
Thank you, Commandery Prince An.
What you did is ridiculous, but you sincerely regretted
and almost got killed in the river,
I think you have learned your lesson.
I won't give you any serious punishment.
Let me ask you one thing.
You must answer me truthfully.
Please go ahead, I'll be honest.
I heard from Magistrate Zheng earlier
that the bridge between Guanling County and the outside was built five years ago.
Before that, it was very difficult to get in or leave Guanling County.
Is it true?
Yes, it's true.
The Prefect granted the money to build the bridge.
It was a great thing that benefited everyone in the county.
Do you still remember whether the bridge was finished
when Witch Doctor living in the back of your house left?
Not yet.
I remember it clearly.
My family also found it strange.
Witch Doctor's legs didn't work well.
He couldn't leave Guanling County at all.
How did he disappear suddenly?
Your Grace, you must be tired after playing chess with Senior Jing for so long.
I've asked someone to prepare some hot water
and give you a bath later to relieve your fatigue.
I'm afraid...
that Jing Zhi came here not just to play chess with me.
I can't help but feel worried.
I think Senior Jing came to urge you to promote Miss Leng's marriage.
The more he urges me,
the more it means this marriage won't work.
I hope Mr. Xue can talk the emperor out of this idea
during their trip to Qianzhou.
Your Grace, are you worried that it will involve General Leng's military power
if General Xiao and Miss Leng get married?
Not all because of this.
If we only consider the interests involved in this marriage,
it's safer to let Leng Yue marry Jinyu.
It won't involve the military power of the Leng clan
and can make the Leng clan continue to support Jinyu in the court.
What I care about is still Yue.
She has been following Jinyu since she was a child.
She does everything Jinyu tells her to do.
I guess she had fallen for Jinyu a long time ago.
It's just Jinyu cares about nothing else but official affairs.
I always wanted to find a chance and talk to Jinyu about it.
Tell him not to fail Yue.
Unexpectedly, such a thing happened before I got the chance.
Now Yue is going to be Jinyu's sister-in-law.
Your Grace, be at ease.
We have Mr. Xue's full support in this matter.
Besides, Commandery Prince An is also in Qianzhou.
He has been thoughtful since he was young.
If he knows it, he will figure out a way to solve all the problems.
Have you asked Wu Jiang?
Is there any news about Jinyu recently?
Yes.
Wu Jiang said that His Highness is at Miss Chu's house in Guanling.
Who?
The female coroner.
Coroner?
Have you met that coroner?
What does she look like?
She...
She is delicate.
What if we compare her with Leng Yue?
How can they be compared?
Miss Leng is one of the most beautiful girls in Chang'an.
That girl is cuter than Miss Leng.
But in terms of appearance, she is just delicate.
There is no way to compare her with Leng Yue.
Cute?
I mean, could it be that Jinyu just likes cute girls?
Chu Chu!
His Highness always protects me.
He said I'm the best coroner.
But why did he say that to me?
You must go home when I ask you to.
If you really see yourself as the coroner of Three Judicial Offices,
you must follow my orders.
If you think of my words as unworthy of your attention,
you shouldn't keep working for me.
Three Judicial Offices will be fine with one less coroner.
Chu Chu.
Father.
What are you thinking about?
Nothing.
I'm just thinking where
that man could escape to.
Chu Chu,you know who that person is. Right?
Yes.
That man is my uncle.
You also know it, right?
Your brother accidentally heard a few words said by the people around that lord.
When I sent water to them last night, I took a look at that person.
Although his eyes were covered and his mouth gagged,
I could still recognize him.
That's Master Xu.
I didn't dare to tell your brother because I was afraid that he couldn't hold back his temper and make a big deal out of
I only told your grandpa.
Chu Chu, don't think too much about it.
Xu Zongfang is Xu Zongfang. You are you.
No matter what he did, it has nothing to do with you.
Do you know it?
Yes, I do.
Father, don't worry.
I won't bring shame on the Chu clan.
Of course, you won't.
You are Commandery Prince An's coroner now.
You make the Chu clan proud, right?
Don't think too much about it.
Your Highness, Miss Leng and Magistrate Zheng are here.
- Your Highness.
Magistrate Zheng, please wait inside for a while.
Yes.
What's wrong?
How did you know something was wrong?
If there was nothing wrong,
you would have sent the medicine to the kitchen first.
You wouldn't have come here to stop me.
What is it?
There is a little thing I'm curious about.
I want to ask you casually.
Then I will listen casually.
Your Highness, does the Deputy Magistrate Tan Gui have any relation with you?
What relation?
Like is he your confidant or your spy?
Why do you ask that?
Answer my question first.
No.
Really?
If he were my confidant,
how is it that I didn't know Xu Rugui was Xu Zongfang until now?
All right, you just casually asked me.
And I've casually heard you.
Just take the medicine to the kitchen
and ask someone to decoct it for Chu He.
Get him some food.
Let him go home after he gets better lest the Chu family should worry.
Your Highness, don't you want to ask me why I asked you that?
You will tell me when you figure it out.
You already know it?
Know what?
Know that Jing Yi has been stalking me
and sending messages to Chang'an behind my back?
Or know that you found out the person Jing Yi has been meeting behind my back is Tan Gui?
You know it.
It's nothing strange that I know it.
Jing Yi has been around me for almost 20 years.
It's too obvious for me about what he does and what he doesn't do.
He also knows if I know about what he does.
Your Highness, there must be some misunderstanding here.
You know that Jing Yi will never hurt you.
I know.
The strange thing is how do you know it?
Have you been stalking him?
I... When I was keeping an eye on Chu Chu,
I saw Jing Yi stalking you and Chu Chu.
I thought Jing Yi was after Chu Chu.
I was worried that the Jing family would do something to Chu Chu,
so I stalked him a few times.
Earlier, I found out by chance that he met someone alone.
I didn't see that person's face, but I saw the footprints.
When I saw Tan Gui's just now, I realized that he was
the person Jing Yi met.
Your Highness, what is Jing Yi doing?
Don't worry.
What Jing Yi needs to do in his life
is not only the work I give him.
It's just like I won't let him do all the work.
It's the same.
When it's necessary.
He will give me an explanation.
Your Highness, thank you.
For what?
Thank you for trusting Jing Yi.
Why should you thank me?
Your Highness, you...
Your Highness. Your Highness.
Forgive me for interrupting you.
Just say it.
Something weird happened.
I don't know what to do.
So I'm here to ask you for advice.
Chu He asked me for flogging.
Ask you for what?
Flogging… He wants to get beaten.
He asked me to beat him.
Why does he want to get beaten?
I don't know.
I asked him why, but he wouldn't tell me.
He said he deserves it.
Your Highness,
what should I do?
Just give him what he wants.
What kind of thing is that to give him flogging?
He asked for it.
Flog him as many times as he asks.
Don't beat him too hard.
Just let him suffer a little bit.
Remember not to hurt his bones.
- Yes.
- Also remember, don't let others know what I just said to you.
What are you waiting for?
You've never been here.
Do you understand?
Yes.
I think I understand. I understand.
I understand.
Your Highness, does the medicine for Chu He need to be decocted?
[Shangyang Gate]
Minister Han is perceptive indeed.
That female coroner only took an exam in the Three Judicial Offices,
and you found out her identity
as a survivor of the rebellious party through the details.
Yes. Minister Han is great indeed.
Be careful of your words.
She is suspected of being the daughter of a rebel.
We still need the emperor to make the final decision.
However, as public servants,
we should always remember the teachings of Commandery Prince An.
We can't make any mistake in this matter.
Otherwise, he has a lot of ways to teach us a lesson.
Yes.
Commandery Prince An hasn't realized he opened the door to a dangerous person.
If it wasn't for you to find out who she was,
I'm afraid he can't come back to Chang'an alive.
Commandery Prince An hired the daughter of a rebel.
After he returns to Chang'an,
he should punish himself for hiring the wrong person.
Yes.
It's just Xue Rucheng who took the credit.
If he wasn't ordered to handle affairs in Qianzhou,
how would the emperor ask him to investigate it and catch the rebels by the way?
He took the credit for nothing.
All right, no big deal.
A person points at the rabbit.
A dog catches the rabbit.
The emperor knows who makes what contributions.
We don't need to take this credit.
Moreover, the daughter of a rebel threatens Commandery Prince An's life.
Xue Rucheng dares not neglect it.
It's a good thing for us.
We don't need to confront the Commandery Prince An
and he saved us from the hardship of the trip.
Why shouldn't we feel happy about it?
Brilliant.
Yes.
Hurry. Hurry up.
Set the meal.
Don't delay the meal.
Minister Han.
Eunuch Qin.
Congratulations, you've found out the survivor of the rebellious party.
This is what I should do.
Yes.
What is this?
How can we eat this?
Eunuch Qin, did you serve the wrong dishes?
Yes.
That's what you are going to eat today.
The emperor said it's not easy for Tang to be peaceful.
You are the pillars of the country.
You should be prepared for danger in times of peace.
Don't forget His Majesty's grace and your responsibility
when you get cocky.
Minister Han, am I right?
Yes.
All right, enjoy your meal.
Enjoy your meal. Enjoy your meal.
It isn't so much about Han Ji taking the credit.
It's about Han Ji finishing this tricky matter for us.
You are right, Master.
Ever since the female coroner came to Chang'an,
there hasn't been one day that is not troublesome.
After I get something useful out of her,
I'm going to vent out all of my anger.
I won't let her die easily.
Then you need to hurry up and think about how to kill her.
Listen... It won't take us long to get her.
That's great.
Xiao Jinli?
Leng Yue?
Why are you here?
I found him strange when he stopped Miss Chu on the street
and asked her some questions.
A moment ago, I saw him sneak out from the County Office.
I'm afraid he will do harm to you. So I've been following him.
Then I saw him lying in ambush near the Chu house.
He followed Miss Chu all the way here and tried to attack Miss Chu.
But I didn't expect her to be Leng Yue.
Say it!  What do you want to do?
I want to kill Chu Chu to avenge my father!
No wonder.
You asked Miss Chu how your father died.
She told me. Then I told Commandery Prince An.
Miss Chu is clever.
She said it's only when bad people want to do bad things
that they don't want Commandery Prince An to know it.
You are really up to no good.
Jinyu, we're on the same page this time.
You asked Leng Yue to dress as Chu Chu in order to catch him, right?
Despicable. Shameless.
What did you say? I'll chop your head off.
Xiao Jinli, it has nothing to do with you. You'd better leave.
Why does it have nothing to do with me? I just saved you.
Did I ask you to save me?
- I...
- All right.
We don't need to keep it from him.
Keep me from what?
Tan Gui, you should know why I got someone to dress as Chu Chu.
This method isn't above-board.
But this is the only way to get you out and make things clear for you.
I don't understand what you are saying.
You don't understand?
You went to see Chu Chu in front of Jinli on purpose,
and asked her mysteriously about your father's death.
You even told her not to tell me about it
to make sure I would know it.
You asked about your father's death.
In this way, whether you will make it or not,
it can be the most powerful testimony
to explain why you want to kill Chu Chu.
What do you mean?
- I don't understand.
- Enough!
Stop lying at this point.
What you did is really shameful.
My family asked him to kill Chu Chu.
Vice Minister Jing, you can't...!
- Brother, no!
- Xiao Jinli, are you crazy?
I'm sick of your Jing family's sneaky tactics.
Say it!  What are you up to?
It has nothing to do with Vice Minister Jing.
Shut up!
Say it!  Why do you want to kill Miss Chu?
Say it! Why do you have to kill Chu Chu?
Commandery Prince An. General Xiao.
Chu Chu is the daughter of the person who killed your father.
What?
Vice Minister Jing, do you still remember the hairpin we rubbed?
The one Chu Chu's mother gave to her.
Your mother recognized the pattern on it.
She gave this hairpin to a general's wife as a wedding gift.
That general is Yun Yi, a subordinate of the Military Commissioner of Jiannan.
Chu Chu is Yun Yi's daughter,
which means she is a survivor of the rebellious party.
After I passed the Imperial Examination, I took Senior Jing as my master.
Then I went back to Qianzhou to look for and get rid of
these fugitives to avenge Prince Consort.
Why are you stopping me?
Vice Minister Jing, how should you explain to Senior Jing?
I don't need to explain to him.
He wants to kill Chu Chu for someone who was like a real brother to him.
I won't let him kill Chu Chu
also for someone who is like a real brother to me.
These are two different things. But the feelings are the same.
My father knew I would do this.
That's why he kept it from me and asked you to do these things.
No need to say much. I trust you.
Commandery Prince An, what Senior Jing did is for avenging your father.
That's your father!
Why are you protecting your enemy's daughter?
You can only protect her for a while.
Even if I won't say it and they won't say it,
but someone else will reveal her identity one day.
At that time, you will be convicted of covering up the survivor of the rebellious party.
What's in that for you?
How should you face Prince Consort and Princess Xiping?
General Xiao, are you also going to let her get away with it?
Even if she is a survivor of the rebellious party,
it's the County Office's bushiness to punish her.
Senior Jing can't use lynching.
Deputy Magistrate Tan,
since you work for Senior Jing,
you should know why I came to the Southwest this time.
Senior Jing wants you to kill Chu Chu to avenge my father.
But if my father wants you to let her go,
are you willing to put off killing Chu Chu
and tell Senior Jing about the situation first?
You mean Prince Consort is still...?
Timing and subtitles brought to you by The Imperial Coroners @ Viki.com
♫  Nothing can stop me  ♫
♫  From missing you all the time  ♫
♫  The moonlight appears, cold in the late night,
as the world changes  ♫
♫  Only with you by my side can I embrace my yearning for you  ♫
♫  When I close my eyes I meet you once again  ♫
♫  I'll gently brush your hair by your ear  ♫
♫  Life is long, with love and regrets in this world  ♫
♫  With you by my side, no matter how far I go,
we'll never be apart  ♫
♫  With your smile, in this moment, let me
cherish this lifetime  ♫
♫  Only for you, I have to worry about the end of this life  ♫
♫  I’m still young, with my love not yet realized for you, but I'm
willing to be here for you till the end
♫  You can rely on me in this lifetime  ♫
♫  Hope to spend this beautiful lifetime together  ♫