Timing and subtitles brought to you by The Imperial Coroners @ Viki.com
The eunuchs were reckless
and gave deliberate misrepresentations.
They made up the rebellion of the Military Commissioner of Jiannan
so that twenty thousand loyal soldiers were slaughtered.
My father wanted to vindicate them with his loyal soul.
I'll certainly accomplish this mission.
I'm Li Zhang, Prefect of Qianzhou.
Greetings, Duke Chang.
Don't stand on ceremony, Prefect Li.
You had a long trip.
Did Commandery Prince An find out anything in Qianzhou?
Don't worry, Your Highness.
He found the illegal coins accidentally.
I've taken over the case.
I'll take care of everything.
Be very careful and don't give yourself away.
Your Highness, this is an official document from Chang'an.
When I arrived, I saw the posthouse official sorting and registering the documents.
So that he wouldn't take his time and hold you up,
I urged him to register it, and I brought it to you immediately.
Thank you, Prefect Li.
You're flattering me, Your Highness.
[Han Ji, Minister of Justice]
Arrest Chu Chu?
Chu Chu?
Your Highness, do you mean Yun Yi's daughter?
You also know her?
Yes.
In an official order,
I was asked to help arrest this girl in Qianzhou and bring her back to Chang'an.
However, she stays with Xiao Jinyu every day.
I'm afraid...
What?
I'm afraid if we suddenly go arrest her
and have a head-on confrontation with Commandery Prince An,
it may hinder our big plan.
Let me think about it.
Well then, go to Guanling County with me tomorrow.
Yes, Your Highness. I'll be at your service.
All right. It's getting late.
Go back for some rest.
All right.
I don't think Li Zhang can outwit Xiao Jinyu.
I need a backup plan.
[The Imperial Coroner]
[Episode 22]
[Summon Military Commissioner Chen Ying to Chang'an with his troops.]
It's the secret imperial decree Emperor Wenzong issued.
Summoned by this decree,
Chen Ying took troops back to Chang'an to help Emperor Wenzong.
With this, can we reverse the case of the Military Commissioner of Jiannan?
It's Father's last wish
and it also concerns Miss Chu's life.
Once the truth is revealed,
there'll be a big dispute in the court.
We must be carefully prepared before reserving the case.
Like Father said, if we take one wrong step,
we'll implicate more innocent people.
Don't worry, Chu Chu.
I will vindicate your parents and prove your innocence.
Your Highness, I trust you.
I'll leave my father to you.
I don't care how you report to my father about what happened today.
But you must send this to him.
Vice Minister Jing, now that His Highness has learned
that you and Senior Jing send letters
as well as about our relationship,
why do you still send letters through me?
I'm not guarding against Commandery Prince An.
Who is it?
The real enemy.
You must be very careful.
Yes.
Vice Minister Jing,
I've executed nine subordinates of the Military Commissioner of Jiannan.
They all claimed they were innocent before they died.
But I never asked them
what exactly happened that year.
Even if you asked, they couldn't tell you much.
No one knew the secret truth, except for a few generals.
The more well-trained the soldiers are,
the more accustomed they are to taking orders.
I guess when General Chen Ying gave an order,
they followed him immediately.
They didn't know what exactly happened
even when you executed them.
So when they said they were innocent...
they were truly innocent.
Vice Minister Jing,
I know I'm not very talented or virtuous.
I don't dare to call myself a good official.
But I never expected that I alone have executed some loyal soldiers.
No matter how I'm punished,
I won't complain.
All right. A lot of people owe them.
I hope we can make it up a bit.
Go ahead.
Chu Chu, you're a coroner.
You got along with him for years
and you just inspected him.
You know all his wounds.
Isn't that right?
How badly was he wounded?
Why didn't he ever recover?
Five years ago, he was in his early forties.
How did he know he was dying?
Don't ask, Your Highness.
He didn't want you to know these things.
Chu Chu, he was my father.
Just like how much you want to know
what happened to your mother before she died,
I also want to know exactly how he knew...
that he was dying?
In his old notes,
he always said life was precious.
He poured scorn on people who killed themselves.
He wouldn't kill himself unless he had to.
Tell me, please.
There were many old wounds on his body that I didn't know of before.
But the wounds healed quickly.
His broken leg kept torturing him.
His leg was so badly wounded
that even his bones were injured.
You told me that
his leg was badly wounded,
but there was hope to cure it.
It was held up and didn't heal
simply because of delayed treatment.
But it could only stop him from walking.
Why did he die?
If he fell and was wounded, he wouldn't die.
But his leg was gashed.
He used to tell people that
he fell off a mountain and broke his leg.
He let no one check on it,
including the physicians or my family.
So... before I checked his leg today,
I believed he had really fallen and broken his leg.
Now I realize he didn't want others to know
his leg was gashed,
or someone might track him down.
So...  he tolerated it.
If bones are broken,
what's the difference between falling and being gashed?
There's a difference.
There's a wound closure for a fracture.
[Intact skin with fracture]
But when a man is gashed,
there's an open wound on the bone.
[Open and neat wound]
[Blade]
An open wound
would easily be infected
and cause disease on the bones.
Such a disease can hardly be removed.
Also, the Witch Doctor didn't allow a doctor to check on him.
He used his own medicine.
As time went by, the disease went into the bones
and then throughout his body.
[Disease invades the bones and then the entire body.]
By then he couldn't be cured.
How...
How did he feel?
I think he felt pain.
But the pain didn't last.
It happened from time to time.
It repeated unless it was cured.
When there was pain on unaffected bones,
he...
he knew he was dying.
He allowed no one to check on his wound
and he told no one about it.
So, all that time,
no one knew that he was suffering.
What are you doing?
General Zhou, you've got more fragrance on you.
You must have visited girls very recently.
You know, I thought of taking you with me when I went,
but I realized that you couldn't have fun with girls.
All right, I'll report it to Eunuch Qin.
He couldn't, either.
Can't you take a joke?
I'm not joking.
Eunuch Qin said
you should think about where you got the money
to pay for your happy hours with girls.
I know.
I went to Pingkang Residence for intel.
That's where all kinds of men visit.
It's a perfect place to get intel.
Men from Three Judicial Offices go there, too.
In such a good place, what intel did you get?
Time and luck are needed to gain some intel.
Luck?
I think it's your greatest luck
when Eunuch Qin hasn't killed you yet.
You'd better behave yourself.
Check out what Master asked you to do and report on your mission soon.
I understand.
Speaking of it,
His Majesty also cares about Duke Chang.
Why doesn't Eunuch make use of him and check the case?
- Who should be made use of?
- His Majesty.
- His Majesty?
-Yes.
What's in your mind? Rubbish?
Did you get your head caught in the door when you left home this morning?
Why are you so talkative today?
Just do what you're asked to.
Tell me. Is there any news from the Southwest?
Speaking of that, there's really something fishy with the Military Commissioner of Qianzhongdao.
I urged many times, but there's no reply yet.
But some of our men escorted Xue Rucheng to Qianzhou, didn't they?
As estimated, they have arrived in Qianzhou already.
- Xue Rucheng?
- Right.
Xiao Jinyu, Xiao Jinyu, look at you.
You hired a female coroner and ruined my plan.
Now she's a rebel's daughter.
When I catch her, you'll leave Qianzhou soon.
Grandfather.
Do you miss your mother?
Yes.
I'm thinking about why did my mother like my father and why did she marry him?
When she married him, she didn't expect what would happen, did she?
If she knew what would happen,
would she still want to marry him?
Silly girl, what are you imagining?
Your parents were a sweet couple.
After your father's family was ruined,
she didn't hate him.
Grandfather, how do you know that?
When your mother died, she was pregnant for eight months.
With you in her body,
she came all the way to Qianzhou along mountain roads.
If she hadn't protected you carefully,
you would have died.
If she hated your father,
before your father's family was ruined,
she would have aborted you.
She was beautiful and young.
Without the baby, she would easily marry someone else.
I inspected my mother's corpse.
Based on her pelvis, she didn't give birth before she had me.
I'm her first and her only child.
She escaped all the way here to give birth to me.
Maybe...
Maybe she really loved my father
and tried to keep his last family member
as the only connection with him.
The last family member?
Chu Chu, do you know anything about your father?
What happened to his family?
Why were you his last family member?
Nothing. I don't know anything.
I just...
I just guessed.
But I know my father must be a good man.
It's getting late.
I'll go make lunch.
Wait.
I have something to ask you.
I can tell that His Highness thinks highly of you.
He wants you to work for him.
But he's going back to Chang'an.
What's your plan?
I...
I haven't made up my mind yet.
I'm going to make lunch.
All right.
Father left such an important mission.
I'll accomplish it!
Your Highness, a message from Chang'an.
[Lord Xue came to arrest Chu Chu, under the command of His Majesty.]
Go ask General Xiao to take his soldiers to the Chu family.
Without my permission, let no one take anyone of the Chu family away from their house!
Yes!
[Guanling Yamen]
Sir, you had a long trip.
It's my honor to fulfill His Majesty's order.
Where's General Xiao?
He's away for some business.
He'll be back and see you later.
Magistrate Zheng.
Here.
Looks like I'll stay here for days.
It's my honor.
What do you need, My Lord?
Please find me a quiet place
so that His Highness and I can have a word alone.
All right. I'll find it immediately.
This way, Sir.
Come.
[Lord Xue came to arrest Chu Chu, under the command of His Majesty]
Sir, congratulations on becoming Minister of War.
His Majesty showed grace on me.
I don't know whether it's luck or a curse.
If I guess correctly,
you sent your brother away on purpose. Right?
Yes.
Sir, I don't dare to deceive you.
I've heard about what happened in the court.
Now that you know it,
I feel much relieved.
On my way here, I was thinking
about how to tell you about this.
When you've already heard about it,
I'll get to the point.
Jinli can't marry Leng Yue.
You don't agree with this marriage?
His Majesty wants them to get married,
not simply because he wants them to be a good couple.
Do Jinli and Leng Yue know about  it?
I haven't told them yet.
I know it's hard for you.
Leng Yue's adored you since she was little.
It's quite difficult for you to tell her about that.
No, that's not it.
You got it wrong, Sir.
Leng Yue and I are only cousins.
We don't love each other.
I haven't told them about it,
because it was quite unexpected.
I doubt there's another reason for it.
Now that you suspect,
you must have guessed about it.
I guess that His Majesty wants them to get married
to restrain the military power of the Leng family.
Sir, they have garrisoned the Southwest for so many years.
I've never heard about their disloyalty.
Why does His Majesty suddenly want to restrain them?
Sir?
I don't know the details, either.
Senior Jing suggested to his His Majesty to allow Jinli to marry Leng Yue
so that Jinli could get back Leng Peishan's military power.
But the Leng family has settled in the Southwest for generations
and has been leading the troops.
As the head of the Leng family,
Leng Peishan wouldn't easily give up his military power.
As far as I see, you'd better go back to Chang'an quickly
so that you can discuss with your mother
on how to reject the marriage.
There's another thing.
That's why I came all the way to see you before His Majesty orders them to get married.
- What's it, Sir?
- Tell me the truth.
When you checked on Feng Jie's case,
what did you exactly get?
Sir, why do you suddenly ask?
I didn't know it until I took over the Ministry of War.
Feng Jie made a summary when patrolling in the Southwest,
but it was missing when he went back to Chang'an.
No one knew what was recorded in it.
If Feng Jie was murdered,
the summary must be very important.
Now that you asked about Feng Jie,
you must have had a general conjecture
about what he recorded.
I came all the way along the route Feng Jie patrolled
and got nothing useful.
If I keep moving forward,
I'll be reaching the military town where Leng Peishan is stationed.
I stayed with my brother these days,
but he didn't tell me there was anything wrong in the army.
Jinyu.
Sir, do you even suspect my brother?
I watched Jinli grow up.
I know what kind of person he is.
He's very upright, but not meticulous.
If someone makes use of him,
he may not know.
Well, I'm just guessing.
I hope I'm having groundless worry.
There seems to be trouble in Qianzhou.
In case Princess Xiping worries, you'd better go back to Chang'an early.
[Jiangshan Hall]
Your Majesty, I'd like to check the case in Qianzhou.
Your Majesty, it's a long trip to Qianzhou.
If we send men there,
it'll take a lot of days before they arrive.
Also, no one in the Ministry of Revenue or the other three ministries
knows much about what happened in Qianzhou.
It's not a good plan to send them.
What do you think, Jing?
I remember Commandery Prince An is in Qianzhou now.
The illegal coin case is serious.
Our enemies will be alerted if we take any careless actions.
The wisest way is to let His Highness check the case, according to circumstances.
Senior Jing makes sense.
I agree with him, too.
You interrupted me,
so that I totally forgot Commandery Prince An was in Qianzhou.
Fine, then. Ask Hanlin Academy to draft the decree
that Commandery Prince An shall investigate the case, without fail.
Yes, Your Majesty.
Who's that? Who dares to make trouble in my place?
Xiao Jinli?
What are you coming for?
I don't know.
You don't know?
You don't know why you came?
It's hard to explain.
Why do you always say that?
What can your tongue be used for?
Can't you say something sweet?
You can do nothing, but eat. Look at your fat waist.
Give it to me!
Well done, Xiao Jinli.
You even dare to grab my food?
I haven't dealt with you for how you bullied Jing Yi last time.
What does it concern you when I bullied Jing Yi?
Give it to me!
What's going on?
- It's General Xiao.
- Give it to me!
He and Miss Leng are fighting for a drumstick.
Why? There're more drumsticks.
Keep eating. I'll see if anyone marries you!
This is none of your business!
Why are you fighting for a drumstick?
He asked for that!
Jing Yi, let me ask you. Isn't she fatter than she was two years ago?
Stop, Xiao Jinli.
Trust me. You're really asking for that.
Anyway, is the Chu family defended?
Come on. What exactly do you want?
[Lord Xue came to arrest Chu Chu, under the command of His Majesty.]
Wu Jiang wrote it.
All right, you're not fat.
Don't interrupt.
What exactly happened?
Lord Xue came to arrest Chu Chu, under the command of His Majesty.
What?
Sir, do you come here personally
with another mission?
I didn't know Three Judicial Offices could get intel
as fast as the Jing family.
Sir, I heard
that ten men from the Imperial Army came to Qianzhou with you.
I asked about them when I came,
but I was told that they didn't come here.
I also heard that
Prefect Li Zhang of Qianzhou also came here with you.
When you're talking to me,
he's on his way to arrest Chu Chu with the Imperial Amy, right?
Jinyu, I'm sure you knew that.
The female coroner you hired is a rebel's daughter.
Prefect Li and I didn't mean to catch her without letting you know.
We simply wanted to keep you safe.
There's a lot of criticism about you.
But after all, you were deceived.
I don't think His Majesty will blame you for that.
Sir, Chu Chu isn't a rebel's daughter.
She isn't?
But Han Ji was very sure when he told His Majesty about it.
Sir, I have irrefutable evidence.
Stop!
Isn't that Li Zhang?
Why is he coming?
Why do they stop me, General Xiao?
We have some dealings in business.
What?
Your subordinates can't even recognize me?
At the behest of His Majesty,
I come to arrest the rebel's daughter!
Whoever is irrelevant should leave!
Vice Minister Jing. Miss Leng. I've got urgent business to do.
I can't play the game with you that you pretend to be Commandery Prince An.
The rebel's daughter?
Prefect Li, you must make it clear.
Who's the rebel's daughter?
She is. She's the rebel Yun Yi's daughter.
Miss, surrender yourself in case of being tortured!
What nonsense are you talking about?
She's my granddaughter!
What Yun Yi? What rebel?
You're in the wrong place!
Sir, if you keep fighting,
you'll be sorry.
Take her down!
- Be careful!
- Father!
Stop!
Chu Chu!
- Go away!
- Father!
Father!
Chu Chu!
Let go of me!
How dare you wound me!
Sorry, Lord Li, that was an accident.
You!
Stop!
Minister Xue!
Minister Xue! Your Highness!
Your Highness.
Chu Chu, are you all right?
Prefect Li, why were you fighting against Vice Minister Jing and General Xiao?
Minister Xue, I was trying to arrest the rebel's daughter,
but they wounded me!
Look.
Minister Xue, it wasn't our fault.
Prefect Li came here with these unidentified men
and he had no certificate at all.
But we're guarding this place, under the command of His Highness.
We wouldn't let them break in.
You!
Why does Prefect Li have so many tiny scars on his hand?
Minister Xue! It's some misunderstanding.
Prefect Li, thank you for coming.
Now that His Highness has come,
we'll take care of the thing about the rebel's daughter.
Why don't you go back and take care of your wound?
Fine, then.
Minister Xue. Your Highness.
See you.
Go!
Leng Yue. Jing Yi. Guard here.
Yes.
Sir, come, please.
- Grandfather.
- We're all right.
Don't worry.
This is Prince Consort?
Yes.
It's a petition Father left before he died.
It was decoded with a reverse phonetic notation
according to two poems on the casket.
It revealed the truth of the rebellion of Military Commissioner Chen Ying.
When did he die?
Five years ago.
Sir.
Come on.
This is a very serious case where a lot of people are involved.
Once other officials know it,
I'm afraid there'll be another conflict between ministers and eunuchs.
We must have a perfect plan and we mustn't act rashly.
I understand.
Why do you keep his corpse here?
As you said, this is a serious case.
I don't trust anyone else.
Father was close to the Chu family before he died.
The Chu family are upright and kind,
and they all work as coroners.
They know how to preserve corpses.
So, I keep my father's corpse here.
Sir, what do you think we should do?
Go back to Chang'an with me immediately
and report to His Majesty.
When the truth is revealed in the court,
Chu Chu can be exonerated from being a rebel's daughter.
Sir, I'm afraid we can't go back to Chang'an now.
You asked to come to Qianzhou to look for Prince Consort.
Now that you found him,
why do you still want to stay?
A relevant criminal is fleeing in Qianzhou.
I must hunt him down
and make him a witness for this case.
- Who do you mean?
- Xu Rugui.
The criminal who is wanted across the nation?
Do you know where he is?
Kind of.
As Jinyu asked,
I've sent some soldiers to guard all entrances and exits to Guanling County,
and sent other soldiers to search Phoenix Mountain secretly disguised as local people.
We haven't found him yet, but we found some traces.
Phoenix Mountain?
It's a mountain within Guanling County.
Tomorrow morning, I'll go up the mountain with my brother and search for him together.
All right.
You must be very careful.
Yes.
Jinli, I have something to ask Commandery Prince An.
Tell me the truth.
When did you fall in love with Chu Chu?
Timing and subtitles brought to you by The Imperial Coroners @ Viki.com
♫  Nothing can stop me  ♫
♫  From missing you all the time  ♫
♫  The moonlight appears, cold in the late night,
as the world changes  ♫
♫  Only with you by my side can I embrace my yearning for you  ♫
♫  When I close my eyes I meet you once again  ♫
♫  I'll gently brush your hair by your ear  ♫
♫  Life is long, with love and regrets in this world  ♫
♫  With you by my side, no matter how far I go,
we'll never be apart  ♫
♫  With your smile, in this moment, let me
cherish this lifetime  ♫
♫  Only for you, I have to worry about the end of this life  ♫
♫  I’m still young, with my love not yet realized for you, but I'm
willing to be here for you till the end
♫  You can rely on me in this lifetime  ♫
♫  Hope to spend this beautiful lifetime together  ♫