In His Highness's heart,
am I only a tool to look for Sir Witch Doctor?
From Chang'an to Qianzhou,
[The ninth day of the tenth month]
did he pay attention to me, simply for this pendant?
He investigated my family background
and threatened me with my families.
What do I mean to him?
The pendant is quite important.
I have to check on it.
But anyway, I feel sorry for her.
Maybe this is where we have to leave each other.
Timing and subtitles brought to you by The Imperial Coroners @ Viki.com
My Lord, it just rained.
But you came out in such a rush?
Why don't you go until it clears up?
I haven't made dealings with Commandery Prince An before.
But considering how he deals with criminal cases of different states,
he certainly knows everything very well before making any decision.
This time, he asked me to handle the illegal coining case.
I feel quite agitated.
Qianzhou is within your jurisdiction.
Commandery Prince An can't work well when he first comes to a strange place.
It makes sense when he asked you to take care of the case.
You have no idea.
Xiao Jinyu never plays by the rules.
What shall we do, then?
Let's get back to Yamen first.
[The Imperial Coroner]
[Episode 13]
Look carefully and keep it in mind!
Isn't he Shen Yu, the new Capital Liaison Representative of Qianzhou?
I'm telling you.
Keep a close eye on him as soon as he arrives in the capital.
- Pay special attention to whomever he contacts.
- Yes.
- Sun Mingde.
Go check the sheet again.
Sheet?
Of Rugui House? What shall I check?
Anything about the Southwest and Qianzhou.
Master, why do you suddenly want that?
Ask no questions!
I still feel something fishy.
Keep a close eye on Princess Xiping's Mansion, Xue's Mansion, Jing's Mansion,
and the Three Judicial Offices.
Yes.
As for Xiao Heng...
When I say he's dead,
he's completely dead!
- Yes.
[Princess Xiping's Mansion]
Jinyu and Jinli are still young.
I don't want them to be famous, but to always be safe.
Unexpectedly, the court is quite changeable.
When I'm not a part of the court, I can hardly defend them.
Sir, I hope you can help them.
Don't flatter me, Your Grace.
I'll spare no effort to pay you back.
I'm confused about something.
Can you enlighten me?
Be free to ask me, Your Grace.
You're now the Minister of War.
Have you heard of anything from the Southwest Army?
The Southwest Army?
Do you mean General Leng in Qianzhongdao?
I...
I haven't heard of anything about the Southwest.
Your Grace, what kind of intel do you want?
Anything unusual.
Unusual?
This is very serious.
Please pay attention while in the Ministry of War.
I understand your concern.
Rest assured.
I'll try to get enough information.
Thank you, Mr. Xue.
Grandfather, it's all my fault.
I got our family in trouble.
What are you talking about, Chu Chu?
It's our destiny to meet your mother.
It means you're destined to be one of our family.
This is our fate, too.
What exactly happened?
Tell me about it.
I won't let anyone bully you!
No, Grandfather.
He... He isn't an ordinary official.
He's Commandery Prince An.
Commandery Prince An?
You mean Commandery Prince An
who takes care of Three Judicial Offices and all criminal cases?
Commandery Prince An...
I was too heady.
He's such an important official
that even the Minister of Justice and Vice Minister
of the Court of Judicial Review take orders from him.
But I annoyed him so greatly.
It was my fault.
Chu Chu, I'll go beg him.
If he feels unhappy, I'll ask him to punish me!
Grandfather. Father. Brother.
You raised me up.
Over the past years, you've been protecting me.
For me, you lived with anxiety and were gossiped about.
I've grown up now.
I should take responsibility for what I did.
This time, I'll protect our family!
Miss Chu, Jinyu asked to see you.
Don't be scared. I'll go with you!
Jinyu wants to see her alone.
This is my family!
Chu He!
Brother, don't worry.
I'll handle that.
Greetings, Your Highness.
Raise your head.
Look at me.
Today, I made clear about your family background.
Considering your performance in the Coroner Qualification Test,
you can have the certificate of coroner.
The relevant paper will be issued in a couple of days.
Certificate of coroner?
I lied a few times to you.
But about this, I'm not lying.
You're indeed a great coroner.
When I first met you at the test, I wanted to hire you.
But, Chu Chu,
an official like me must be very cautious.
Every decision I make concerns the safety of the people around me.
So, I can't make a choice, depending on my likes or dislikes.
There's a lot about you that confuses me.
It doesn't mean I don't trust you.
But I have to be very cautious.
If I want to keep you with me, I must know everything about you,
for their good, and also for your own good.
For my own good?
Jinyu is really all right?
He is. He was just exhausted and then annoyed.
He simply needs some good rest.
Wasn't he doing all right just now?
Who annoyed him so greatly?
He...
It's a long story.
Come on. Can you really treat him?
He felt sick all the way here.
Shall I get a doctor from town and have him checked?
He's all right. Don't mess about.
Just ask him to get more rest.
But I'm still worried.
Why is he so weak?
He even spat out blood out of anger.
Think about it. What food should I feed him?
Just stay and take good care of him.
But...
What shall I feed him for nutrition?
People think I consider everything very carefully.
In fact, I simply know a bit more before I make any decision.
The more I know, the better my plan will work.
I still don't know what the man behind it wants.
You also hide a lot from me, instead of telling me the truth.
I couldn't stop worrying on my way and I couldn't even sleep;
in case I have an imperfect plan, make a mistake,
and then get you in irreparable trouble, simply because I don't know enough about you.
Everyone has their secrets.
I don't blame you when you refuse to tell me.
But I must figure everything out in other ways.
I know what I did would make you unhappy.
But compared to your safety, I prefer...
I prefer to make you hate me.
No, I don't hate you.
You think I threatened you with your family.
Aren't you hating me already?
You don't trust me anymore.
If I force you to work for me, it'll do nothing good for us.
I'll sign the paper to prove you as a coroner.
I can recommend you, no matter where you want to work.
You're wrong, Your Highness.
I don't hate you. I just...
Your Highness, you're perfect.
You're smart and upright.
Especially when you solve a case, you're almost shining like the sun.
Such a good man like you treats me so nicely.
Except for the Chu family, no one has been so nice to me before.
I'm just scared.
What if it's an illusion?
Chu Chu, I'm nice to you
because you're worth it.
Your Highness, I'm not going anywhere.
I want to work for you.
Let me take the test again.
I'll work hard.
I'll trust you and I won't annoy you again.
Don't bother.
Your Highness.
- Don't bother to take another test.
- Really?
When you agreed to work for me, that's exactly what I wanted.
- Don't trust me again?
- I do. I trust you.
I'll work hard and become the world's best coroner.
So, you'll no longer punish my family?
Stand up.
Do something for me.
After you make it, I'll let them go.
What is it, Your Highness? I'll make it.
I want some chicken soup.
Don't make it oily.
No blood foam. No grease.
It should taste strong, but also light. Can you do that?
Yes. I'm going right away.
- Brother.
- Chu Chu,
are we really safe now?
I was so stupid that I misunderstood His Highness.
Luckily, he forgave me.
When I can work for him, our family will be safe.
That's great.
I feel like I was in a dream.
Have you made up your mind to work for him ever after?
Then...
After you go back to Chang'an with him,
will you not come back again?
I will. This is my home.
Why would I never come back again?
Brother, this is forever my home.
I'll look after Grandfather and Father, together with you.
I'll also work hard as a coroner.
I won't ever humiliate our family.
What are you talking about?
- Nothing, Father.
- Father.
She's making chicken soup.
Be quick. Be quick.
Miss Chu is an orphan?
What her family said makes me think she's poor, but also lucky.
It's said that everyone in this world
cares for nothing, but profit.
The Chu family live such a poor life,
but they still raise up an orphan who brings no profit to them.
Those rich families where siblings fight for money should be ashamed.
Only these kind men in the Chu family managed to cultivate Chu Chu
to be such an upright and brave girl.
Yes.
But look at you.
When she annoyed you, you could have scolded her.
Why were you so angry?
I don't know, either.
What?
Now, I don't think I should have been so angry.
When I asked Jing Yi to check on her,
I knew she would blame me.
I expected that.
I shouldn't have been so angry.
I don't know the reason, either.
Sorry for making you laugh.
You think I can still laugh?
I was scared to death.
I think you're exhausted.
Leng Yue said you needed some good rest.
Why don't we live in the government office?
The conditions there are better for your recovery.
I don't know how Jing Yi is doing with his mission.
Let's not decide before asking him.
You haven't found Xu Rugui yet?
Not yet.
Haven't you gotten anything useful from the men we captured?
They were simply ordered to kill me and kidnap Chu Chu.
They don't know why they had to.
They also don't know who Xu Rugui exactly is.
Jinyu, I wonder if I should say something now.
- But...
- Brother, if I even have to guess what you are trying to say,
I'll be exhausted to death.
Don't say that.
I mean now that Miss Chu is straightforward
and there's nothing fishy with her background,
why doesn't she tell us about our father?
Come in.
Your Highness.
Take your time. I'll leave you alone.
General Xiao, there's a lot of chicken soup in the kitchen.
Why don't you go have some?
All right.
After hiding Chu Chu's secret for so many years, we finally told her.
I never expected to tell her in this way.
Luckily, she understood.
Also, Commandery Prince An is sensible.
Everything will not change.
That's great.
You're wrong.
What did you say?
Father, Chu Chu now knows who she is.
Something will change.
She hasn't thought about it carefully.
After she does, she'll look for her own father.
Didn't I tell you?
Her father died because his family suffered from disaster,
and then her mother fled to our village.
What about other relatives?
Blood is thicker than water, anyway.
I can understand
if she wants to look for her relatives.
Father, you saved her life.
If she really wants to leave for her other relatives,
do you want to let her go?
I don't, but what can I do?
I can't stop her from finding her other relatives.
I adopted her because she was helpless and poor.
Over the past years, I've never wanted anything from her.
I'll be relieved as long as she lives a good life.
Father, I don't mean I want anything from her.
I... I have a way to satisfy both.
What is it?
Let me marry her.
Then she'll be my wife.
Whether she wants her own family or not, she'll be one of our family.
Chu He, do you know what you're talking about?
No, Father. Don't get me wrong.
I don't simply mean keeping her to our family.
I really like her.
Since when?
I don't know.
When I was little, I knew she wasn't my real sister.
I had pity on her and took good care of her.
But a few days ago,
she went to Chang'an for the Coroner Qualification Test.
You and Grandfather told her that
if female coroners were not accepted in Chang'an,
just like other places, she would come back
and marry someone who was nice to her.
At that time, I thought
if only she would marry me!
Chu He, even if you like her,
she won't marry you unless she likes you, too.
I know.
Anyway, I'll take care of her forever.
General Xiao,
what do you need?
I came to get some chicken soup.
It's being simmered. Let me get some for you.
No. I suddenly have something else to do.
Don't bother.
That's all we can do.
It's been days since Commandery Prince An and Vice Minister Jing left the capital.
They should have arrived in Qianzhou, I guess.
Senior Jing, have you heard from them?
Not at all.
Minister Wang, you know the way Commandery Prince An always behaves.
He's very strict in sending messages.
Since Jing Yi left the capital, he hasn't even sent one single letter home.
You're right.
Since His Highness found the murderer who killed Yan Ming,
he's been tightly encircling Three Judicial Offices,
as if guarding against someone.
Senior Jing, everybody,
after Yan Ming died,
I heard that he had talked wildly during the banquet,
saying he found evidence that
Emperor Wuzong's son, Duke Chang was still alive.
Minister Xue, didn't you hear of that, too?
I heard about it.
But Yan Ming simply talked nonsense after he was drunk.
As far as I know, Yan Ming never talks nonsense.
If it's true,
Yan Ming must have been killed for that.
Minister Han, you know more about his case.
What are you talking about?
How can I know more?
Commandery Prince An solved the case.
I simply know how much he said.
You heard him, too.
He said that the murderer poisoned himself in prison of the Court of Judicial Review.
But why was Yan Ming killed?
There wasn't even an answer until His Highness left the capital.
This time, he has gone to the Southwest,
packing light with a few attendants,
looking for his father who was dead there.
Could he...
What?
Why don't you understand, Minister Xue?
Qianzhou was Duke Chang's fief.
Master!
Wang Jun said that Duke Chang was still alive.
Duke Chang?
That's what he said.
Ridiculous!
How dare he say that!
To be honest, Master, I've heard a lot about that in the palace these days.
But I found it ridiculous so that I didn't tell you.
Our men out of the palace also brought us some news.
Xiao Jinyu's Chief Guardsman Wu Jiang has been surreptitious lately.
We can't figure out what he's doing.
Did Xiao Jinyu not close Yang Ming's case
because of Duke Chang?
You sound more ridiculous.
They're risking their necks!
What the hell!
Duke Chang?
He's been dead for so many years.
Why is he suddenly brought up again?
Go check in the palace
and find out who started such rumors.
Go!
Did Xiao Jinyu go to Qianzhou for another reason?
[Princess Xiping's Mansion]
Your Highness, over the past years, I haven't had a mother.
Because of that, a lot of people bullied me.
Now I know who my mother is, though I am not familiar with her.
But when I know where she is,
I feel quite relieved after being confused for such a long time.
Thank you, Your Highness.
I know you want to find your father.
I promised Sir Witch Doctor that
I wouldn't tell anyone else about him.
But now that you're his son, you're not anyone else.
You're right.
It's Sir Witch Doctor who told me the stories
and gave me the pendant.
I have nothing valuable, but this pendant.
I kept it for many years.
Now, I give it to you as a souvenir.
Souvenir? Why?
Sir Witch Doctor, you're leaving?
Where are you going?
Where can I go?
I'm not going anywhere.
Keep it carefully.
I will keep it carefully.
Also, you must remember.
Do not...
I'll remember. I'll remember.
I won't tell anyone about you.
He went missing five years ago.
This is what he left me.
It's been five years and I've been keeping this letter.
[To Chu Chu]
Sir Witch Doctor?
Where is he?
I said I would come for another story.
[To Chu Chu]
Chu Chu, I'm going on a long trip for an emergency.
I didn't have time to bid farewell face to face.
Then I leave you this letter.
Practice your skills carefully and believe that
you can achieve anything with efforts.
You'll become a coroner.
I had thought he would come back.
But he hasn't come back yet.
When I was little, I believed that the Handsome Judge existed.
I want to bring him back.
I always think when I bring him back,
I'll know where Sir Witch Doctor has gone.
Your Highness, this is all I know.
Thank you for telling me this.
Can you find him with so little information?
I will find him.
I trust you.
Chu Chu.
Grandfather.
Your Highness, thank you for sparing us.
We don't know how to pay you back.
If you need any help, we'll help even at the risk to our lives.
Thank you, Sir.
Chu Chu, I have something for you.
This is what your mother carried.
When I put her in the coffin,
I asked someone to get it from your mother's bun.
I had planned to give it to you at your wedding,
as if it were your mother's gift.
Now that you already know,
I'd like to give it to you now.
Thank you, Grandfather.
May I have a look?
I don't know much about your mother.
No one talked about her before.
I took a quick look at her
on the night she was buried.
She looked pretty and fair-skinned.
Obviously, she was from a rich family, but she looked a bit thinner.
I guess she had suffered a lot
after her husband died.
Chu Chu, anyway, she carried you for months
so that you came into this world.
Though she tried to kill herself while carrying you,
she must have been in great trouble.
Don't hate her.
Don't worry, Grandfather.
My mother came all the way here, carrying me.
I'm sure she wanted to give birth to me.
No matter what happened, she was my mother for months.
I didn't know this before.
But now I do.
I'll keep her in my mind carefully.
You've grown up, Chu Chu.
Don't worry, Grandfather.
All right. All right.
Chu Chu.
Besides this hairpin, is there anything else from Chu Chu's mother?
The Xu family told us that all her stuff had to be buried with her.
Your Highness, are you looking for some clues?
No.
I was just asking.
Don't bother about it.
All right. All right.
Your Highness, are you drawing this hairpin?
Why?
It doesn't look like something from an ordinary family.
But I know very little about girls' things.
I'm drawing it and then will ask people in the capital to investigate it.
Maybe we'll find some clues about your parents.
About my parents?
Don't you want to know who your father is?
Don't you want to know what he had suffered
that made your mother come all the way here?
My father died of disaster, didn't he?
Your Highness, what are you suspecting?
I simply feel a bit confused.
When you were born, there wasn't any natural disaster in Jiannan
that could ruin a whole clan.
So, it couldn't be a disaster like a flood or an earthquake.
It was more likely to be a man-caused disaster.
Man-caused? What do you mean?
Calm down.
I'm simply guessing.
After we find out who your parents are, we'll know the truth.
Later, go to the government office with me to check the household register.
Now that the Xu family is a big family,
there must be a detailed record.
We can easily check out who your mother married.
If there's something fishy with your father's death,
I'll figure it out.
Thank you, Your Highness.
Now that Sir Witch Doctor is your father,
do you know where Six Gates is and who the Handsome Judge is?
What?
Shortly after you work for me,
you want to go somewhere else and find another job?
No, no.
I really want to work for you.
However good the Handsome Judge is, he isn't you.
He never said I was the best coroner.
He didn't rush into the fire, regardless of his own safety.
He didn't make autopsy tools for me.
He didn't live in my home without any unwillingness
or treat my family as his own family.
I know this isn't what a judge must do for a coroner.
You did all this for me.
Looks like I can't let you play around with Jing Yi or Leng Yue.
After so few days, they've made you thick-skinned.
Anyway, I know you're nice to me.
Very nice to me.
Your Highness, I won't work for anyone else, unless you expel me!
Then why do you still want to find Six Gates and the Handsome Judge?
I... I'm simply curious to know more.
When I was little, Sir Witch Doctor told me stories about Six Gates.
If it weren't for finding the Handsome Judge
or being a coroner in Six Gates,
I wouldn't have been brave enough to go to Chang'an.
I wouldn't have met you, either.
Also, you look so much like the Handsome Judge.
But you're right.
When I first heard his story, I was six years old.
You were also a child then.
You can't be the Handsome Judge.
Even if Sir Witch Doctor is your father,
he wouldn't know what you would look like.
That's odd.
It's not odd.
Just some coincidences.
Coincidences?
I read carefully the notes you gave me.
I had read about many stories before that.
But when I read about them, they were not legends,
but real recorded cases.
Really?
Who solved the cases, then?
He's the constable, isn't he?
No.
My father solved the cases when he served as a censor.
- Then isn't he the...?
- He isn't.
I guess the Handsome Judge is a man
my father expected to exist in this world.
What do you mean?
You asked me why I knew what the Handsome Judge said.
I read about them in some old notes my father left me.
The Ten Commandment Hall was set up according to the record in his notes.
The Handsome Judge you admire...
I guess he's the ideal judge in my father's heart
and he's that kind of man my father wants all judges to be.
That explains it.
Sir Witch Doctor told me that all stories in Six Gates were real,
but he never wanted me to look for the Handsome Judge.
Your Highness, in my heart,
you're the best judge that other judges should imitate.
Keep the hairpin carefully.
[Jiangshan Hall]
What...?
Your Majesty, what happened?
- What's the time now?
- Your Majesty, it's nearly midnight.
Time to go to bed.
Go get me some tea.
I'll go to bed after completing this.
Yes, Your Majesty.
Master, what do you think happened?
Why was His Majesty so scared?
He was so scared possibly
because he heard that Duke Chang might still be alive.
I thought His Majesty was wise.
At first, almost everyone in the palace thought he was insane.
Even Eunuch Ma didn't see him through and was kept in ignorance.
Only the late emperor thought His Majesty was pretending to be insane.
He then tried every possible means to kill His Majesty.
Unexpectedly, His Majesty took the throne at last.
Everything that the late emperor predicted came true.
Did His Majesty dream that
the late emperor's son Duke Chang came back to life
and would take back the throne?
Timing and subtitles brought to you by The Imperial Coroners @ Viki.com
♫  Nothing can stop me  ♫
♫  From missing you all the time  ♫
♫  The moonlight appears, cold in the late night,
as the world changes  ♫
♫  Only with you by my side can I embrace my yearning for you  ♫
♫  When I close my eyes I meet you once again  ♫
♫  I'll gently brush your hair by your ear  ♫
♫  Life is long, with love and regrets in this world  ♫
♫  With you by my side, no matter how far I go,
we'll never be apart  ♫
♫  With your smile, in this moment, let me
cherish this lifetime  ♫
♫  Only for you, I have to worry about the end of this life  ♫
♫  I’m still young, with my love not yet realized for you, but I'm
willing to be here for you till the end  ♫
♫  You can rely on me in this lifetime  ♫
♫  Hope to spend this beautiful lifetime together  ♫