Timing and subtitles brought to you by The Imperial Coroners @ Viki.com
When there was a fire in the archive of the Guanling Yamen,
between the shifts of two magistrates,
the Xu family moved away and disappeared.
[Unknown]
It was such a coincidence.
Someone tried to cover something up.
[Xu's Tomb]
Sir Witch Doctor left a letter to me and left home.
Where has he gone?
Why did he hide an end-game in his room?
[Knight, Elephant, Pawn]
There're so many secrets.
I will figure everything out.
Do you mean she not only hurt her forehead when hitting the wall but also wounded the back of her head?
No. She didn't hit the wall.
She was hit by something blunt intensively.
You mean...?
Your Highness, there're fractures in her carpal bones, ulnas, and radii.
She was wounded before she died.
How was she wounded?
- To protect me.
- Protect you?
I was nearly born when she was hurt.
She had a swollen belly.
Someone suddenly pushed her from behind,
trying to make it an accident that she hit the wall herself.
To protect me in her body,
she held her arms against the wall immediately.
Because of the fierce hitting, she had fractures of different levels
in her carpal bones, ulnas, and radii.
[Multiple fractures]
Failing in killing her, the murderer hit the back of her head again,
and then she died of the fracture in her occipital.
Your Highness, my mother didn't kill herself.
She was killed by others!
Please redress the grievance for her.
Stand up.
Not to mention she's your mother, even if she's an irrelevant woman,
- I'll also find out the truth and redress the grievance for her.
- Thank you, Your Highness.
Okay. You're the coroner, taking care of the case.
Don't do this.
I'm sorry.
Your Highness, I know how to find my father.
How?
Do you remember I told you that
a human's appearance had something to do with his skull?
Yes.
With my mother's skull for reference, I can restore her appearance with pottery clay.
Then you can draw a portrait of her.
If someone can recognize her, he might also know my father.
Restore her appearance with clay?
Just like a statue.
It'll look more real with clay.
Sounds like a good idea.
But Chu Chu, she's your mother.
Have you made up your mind?
Your Highness, it's something about my mother's grievance.
As you said, even if she's an irrelevant woman,
we'll also find out the truth, not to mention she's my mother.
She had risked her life to protect me before she died.
As a coroner, I should do everything I can to speak for the dead.
Please let me do it.
All right. You can do it.
Let's do it your way.
Thank you, Your Highness.
Who is there?
[Director: Lou Jian]
[The Imperial Coroner]
[Episode 15]
[Jing Mansion]
Master, a letter from Young Master.
[Dear Father,]  [From Jing Yi]
Master, is there anything wrong with Young Master?
Commandery Prince An found a eunuch's corpse in the house
where Xiao Heng used to live.
A eunuch's corpse?
Why was a eunuch in Qianzhou?
Qin Luan went to Qianzhou, to pacify the rebellion of Chen Ying.
Later, eunuchs went there to exterminate the remnants.
I guess that was when the eunuch went there.
Commandery Prince An asserted that Xiao Heng killed the eunuch.
Prince Consort killed a eunuch?
It doesn't sound right.
Prince Consort was almost killed by rebels.
The eunuchs exterminated rebels.
Speaking of this, Prince Consort and the eunuchs
should be on the same side.
It's true that the eunuchs exterminated rebels.
But Xiao Heng never went on well with the eunuchs.
When he worked in the court, he often punished the eunuchs.
It's also possible that they took the chance to kill Xiao Heng.
You make sense, Master.
According to this, Xiao Heng is likely to be alive.
As reported, Princess Xiping just visited His Majesty.
Now, she may go to the Xue Mansion.
Keep a close eye on the Xue Mansion.
[Xue Mansion]
Come in, please, Your Grace.
Banxia, keep guard at the door.
Yes.
This way, please, Your Grace.
Mr. Xue, please save my son and me!
What are you doing, Your Grace?
If you want me to do anything, I'll do it, regardless of any danger.
You're the princess. Don't kneel to me.
Your Grace, be seated and tell me.
Don't cry, Your Grace. Or your eyes might get hurt.
Your Grace, you visited His Majesty?
If I guess correctly, His Majesty told you about the marriage
between General Xiao and Miss Leng Yue.
You knew that?
I heard about it.
I treat you as my family and I always tell you everything.
Why did you keep it from me?
I...
Your Grace, you watched Leng Yue grow up.
You also wanted Commandery Prince An to marry her.
Why don't you allow General Xiao to marry her?
Are you trying to placate me?
I'm not an ignorant woman.
I'm one of the imperial family, and I grew up in the palace.
Leng Yue is the only granddaughter of Leng Peishan, Military Commissioner of Qianzhongdao.
His Majesty is feeding my son to the wolves!
Now that you know the real problem, I'll get to the point.
General Leng is your uncle.
He's also the head of the Leng family.
It concerns his family's interests.
If General Xiao forcibly takes over the military power in the Southwest,
I'm afraid he'll be in danger.
If Jinli takes over the military power in the Southwest,
he and I will go the same old way like my mother did,
becoming chess pieces to restrain the Leng family in the Southwest.
Your Grace, may I ask how you replied to His Majesty?
I'm no longer a young girl.
I didn't lose my temper in front of His Majesty.
His Majesty promised me that I could divine their birthdays
before he gives the order about the marriage.
I can only stall him for a short time.
Sir, please do something for me.
I... I know.
You're Senior Jing's disciple and you don't want to disobey him.
If you worry about your future, please tell me directly.
It's human nature.
I won't blame you for it.
Your Grace, I watched General Xiao and Commandery Prince An grow up.
To be honest, I've been thinking about it so far.
If you trust me, I'll try to solve the problem for you.
What's the plan, Mr. Xue?
I'm going to the Southwest.
Your Highness?
What brings you here?
I'm looking for Jing Yi. Where's he?
I didn't see him when I woke up.
Maybe he's still sleeping.
Your Highness, I've got something to tell you.
May I have a word with you?
Your Highness, I know I may sound ungrateful,
but I must make something clear
or it'll hurt us both.
Just get to the point.
We grew up together.
I admire you for your morality and ability, so I always obey you.
But...
I only treat you as my good friend.
So do I.
That's fine, then.
Wait.
Be specific.
I hear that Aunt wants us to get married.
I don't know if you have agreed.
I want to make it clear to you.
But it's fine now.
From now on, let's still be good friends.
I'll still obey you.
Leng Yue, I don't know how you heard of that.
My mother never told me about it.
I respect you for being straightforward,
ebullient, and as brave as men.
But as you said, I only treat you as my good friend.
Also, we're cousins.
I never meant to love you.
I obey imperial rules and live my life.
You enjoy yourself in the martial world.
If you're forced to stay in Three Judicial Offices,
there'll always be a mess until we fight against each other
and both suffer great losses.
Yes, you're right.
Now that we made it clear, I have something to ask you.
- Go ahead.
- You never wanted to come to Qianzhou.
But you insisted on coming with me this time.
Why?
Aunt asked me to come with you.
No one can ever control you.
I can figure it out.
My mother must have asked you to keep an eye on Chu Chu
in case she might hurt me.
But you wouldn't be convinced to come or risk your life to save her.
So, why did you come?
I know I can hide no secret from you.
- I did come for Chu Chu.
- Chu Chu?
Yes. For her.
Because... she's... like me.
Who's talking out there?
Your Highness?
What are you talking about?
Chu Chu is working in the mortuary.
Yamen runners can't keep her company.
Go send her some pottery clay and stay with her,
in case she imagines things.
All right.
Go guard the door and keep everyone away.
Yes.
Your Highness, you look so serious.
Insiders know you come to talk with me.
Ignorant people will think you're coming to date a girl.
Are you looking for trouble simply because I haven't punished you for days?
I'm too exhausted to make trouble.
Who?
Didn't you just get up?
Why are your shoes muddy?
Who told you I just got up?
I woke up really early, went around the county,
and checked about local copper coins.
Then I came back to bed.
But just a while later, you came.
I do come to see you for some girl's stuff.
Girl? Which girl?
Tell me about it.
A girl from the Xu family.
The Xu family?
They don't look like a girl's stuff.
They're jewels and clothes of a woman.
Why don't they look like a girl's stuff?
I mean they belong to a married woman, instead of a young girl.
Also, they look old-fashioned.
Chu Chu.
Miss Leng?
His Highness said you were doing something important in this place
and asked me to bring you some clay.
You need this for an autopsy?
It's not for an autopsy.
It's for...
restoring my mother's face.
Your mother?
His Highness and I opened my mother's coffin.
I'll use the clay to restore her appearance.
When it's done, we may find someone who knows her
and confirm her identity.
No wonder His Highness worries when you stay here alone.
He worries?
No. No, I don't mean that.
I mean he worries you'll imagine things when you stay here alone.
Miss Leng, don't worry.
I promised His Highness that I would treat my mother
in the way I would treat other corpses.
I won't think about anything else, except restoring her appearance.
Speaking of that, when I learned medical skills, I noticed that
a person's skull had something to do with his appearance.
But whether the person is fat or thin also plays an important role.
Luckily, we found a set of my mother's clothes,
which was buried with her in the coffin.
Based on the clothes, I can figure out her shape.
When I finish this, I'll know
what my mother looks like.
Your Highness, where did you get them?
They belong to Chu Chu's mother.
Chu Chu's mother? Lady Xu?
She's been dead for many years.
How did you get..?
From her coffin?
Your Highness, you went too far!
It's all right when you checked who Chu Chu was,
but you shouldn't have opened her mother's coffin!
Chu Chu allowed me to do that.
She was there when the coffin was opened.
She opened her mother's coffin?
She has inspected her mother's skeleton.
Now, she's trying to restore her mother's appearance in the mortuary,
so as to provide more clues for her mother's identity.
Chu Chu has seen all kinds of corpses as a coroner,
but opening her mother's coffin and checking her mother's skeleton?
It's hard for anyone, Your Highness.
That's why we must check every single clue very carefully
and not waste her bravery.
You're familiar with girls' stuff.
Check them carefully and see what information you can find.
What do you want me to find?
If I tell you now, I'll influence your judgment.
Check them first.
I'll go see Chu Chu in the mortuary.
All right.
Speaking of it, I don't remember what my mother looks like.
When I was very little, my parents died, too.
Princess Xiping brought me up.
Princess Xiping?
Why did she bring you up?
Your parents died early, but you have a grandfather, don't you?
Didn't I tell you?
His Highness's mother, Princess Xiping, is my aunt.
When my parents died, my family was in a mess.
My aunt brought me to her house and looked after me.
But my grandfather?
He didn't come back to Chang'an until years after my parents died.
He was summoned to meet the new emperor.
If I had waited for him, I might have been dead.
I'm simply complaining. Don't take it seriously.
Don't tell His Highness or Xiao Jinli.
They always want to patch things up between my grandfather and me,
especially Xiao Jinli.
If he knew, he'd be nagging me again.
I see. Don't worry. I won't tell anyone about it.
Miss Leng, don't be too sad.
I think when you look into the mirror,
you'll know what your parents look like.
Look into the mirror?
Yeah.
People think we're born to be different.
It's not right. We look like our parents.
I'm serious. I studied it very carefully.
One doesn't have a face out of nowhere.
[Father, Mother] [Appearance inheritance]
He looks like his parents.
For example, if a couple doesn't have tall noses, their child
will hardly have a tall nose.
And the eyes... If the couple have a single eyelid, their child
won't have double eyelids as I do.
[Single eyelid, Double eyelids]
Sounds interesting.
I haven't noticed that before.
I don't know what your parents look like.
But you look so beautiful.
It's not only because of your father.
Thank you, Chu Chu.
You're welcome.
I'm telling the truth.
Do you know why I came to Qianzhou?
You told me about that.
Princess Xiping sent you.
Before I went back to Chang'an, I had heard about you.
At first, I thought you got close to His Highness for a purpose.
But after I met you in Chang'an, I knew I misunderstood you.
I met all kinds of people in the martial world.
The first time I saw you,
I knew you and I were the same kind of person.
I'm a coroner.
You're from a rich family.
We're totally different.
How can we be the same kind?
I don't mean family background,
but what we pursue.
What we pursue?
You went all the way to Chang'an, just like I ran away from Chang'an.
We pursue what we want.
You want a chance to be a coroner.
All I want is to be freed from the clan.
There aren't many chances for girls.
When I see you trying hard to be a coroner,
I kind of see the old me.
So, I promised my aunt to come to Qianzhou with you
so that I could help you realize your dream.
Now, His Highness has finally hired you.
Congratulations. You'll be an official coroner in Three Judicial Offices.
Thank you, Miss Leng.
What for?
I'm just an idler who is quite self-sentimental.
You should say thank you to His Highness.
Forget it.
Who do you think is the most handsome,
His Highness, Jing Yi, or Xiao Jinli?
They all look handsome.
But in different ways.
Be specific.
Vice Minister Jing has a pretty face.
General Xiao has a strong body.
His Highness...
You know what?
I'm sure his skull looks great.
I'm right about you.
You're indeed a good coroner.
His Highness looks handsome.
But I always think he shouldn't look like this.
Why?
Is General Xiao's biological brother of the same parents?
Yeah. They're twins.
Some twins look different.
It's not weird, isn't it?
It's not weird when twins look different.
But as I said,
I can infer the child's appearance from his parent's skulls.
It's not perfectly correct, but based on their appearances,
they don't look like brothers of the same parents.
Don't let Xiao Jinli hear you.
You see how hard he protects His Highness.
If he heard you, he'd punch you!
As far as I see, one of them may look like their father
while the other looks like their mother.
Or maybe His Highness decided a lot before he was born.
You know what? His Highness has been making his own decisions since he was little.
Maybe when he wanted to look like this, he then had the face.
He has good taste, then?
Your Highness!
Your Highness.
How's the clay statue going?
It's done.
It's my first time doing this.
I may have done a poor job.
But the crude face won't be wrong.
Well done.
Leave the rest to me.
You had a long day. Go back for some rest.
When I find any clue, I'll tell you personally.
Thank you, Your Highness.
Leng Yue, walk her back.
All right. Let's go.
Eunuch Sun. Eunuch Qin.
Eunuch Qin.
You, leave!
Yes.
Do you know why you can stay?
He's asking you. Say something!
He's dead?
Yeah. I think he took some poison.
Aconitine.
He's really from the Southwest.
How daring!
He even dared to make trouble here.
He thought I was totally ignorant?
It's not your place to stir up trouble.
Master, who do you mean?
Are you sure he's the man who spread the rumors about Duke Chang?
Absolutely sure!
We came unexpectedly and he killed himself hastily.
There must be some clues that haven't been destroyed yet.
Search this room carefully.
Yes.
Master.
What's this?
Look. A receipt of Antique Store.
[Jin Lin, Chi Fang with Antique Store, the 20th day of the tenth month]
Antique Store?
[Jin Lin, Chi Fang with Antique Store]
[Antique Store]
Manager,
Qin Luan has come.
Come in, please.
Eunuch Sun!
Be quick. Get us some tea.
[Elegant Literature]
Don't bother.
You're the manager?
I'm Chi Fang, manager of Antique Store.
Greetings, Eunuch Qin.
It's our great honor to have you come.
[Jin Lin, Chi Fang with Antique Store, the 20th day of the tenth month]
It's for another eunuch, I guess.
Now that you have the receipt, I'll go get it for you.
Please, wait a second, Eunuch Qin.
[Elegant Literature]
[The Book of Songs]
Eunuch Qin.
It's well repaired.
Your skill is good as imperial craftsmen.
You are flattering me, Eunuch Qin.
When he brought this here, did he say something?
He simply asked me to repair this.
He said nothing else.
Officials often say that
Antique Store is the granary for literary scholars.
When I see it with my own eyes, I know it deserves the reputation.
Look. Even you hold the Book of Songs.
I'm just an uneducated person mingling with the arts.
You flatter me, Eunuch Qin.
I don't deserve the honor.
Eunuch Qin, you seldom come.
This is a little gift for you.
Please accept it.
Here you are, Eunuch Qin.
Thank you, Manager Chi.
You're welcome.
See you, Eunuch Qin!
Miss Leng, has your wound healed?
Yes.
I nearly forgot about it.
You risked your life to help me.
I don't know how to pay you back.
Let me treat you to something to eat.
There's a shop of rice noodles ahead. It's the best in Guanling County.
Good idea. Let's go.
How's it going?
Not smoothly.
How about Chu Chu? Is she doing all right?
She did a very good job.
I asked Leng Yue to walk her back.
Why do you want me to play chess with you?
Play it with me.
Rejuvenate your mind before checking the evidence.
What... What's this?
It's an end-game.
End-game?
Your Highness, don't torture me.
You know how poorly I play chess.
Within one hour,
you can defeat me ten times even if we start a new game,
not to mention an end-game.
As long as you win, I'll return all your deductions.
- Really?
- If you lose,
you'll also lose your salary for the next three months.
Rice noodles for you.
- Thank you, sir.
- Wait a second.
Rice cake!
I want to eat that. What about you?
Rice cake?
All right. I'll go buy some.
No, no. I'll go.
- I want to see how he makes it.
- Delicious rice cake!
Come and have a look!
Figured cloth. Sir, get me some water.
Nice figured cloth.
Come and look at the pouches.
- Miss.
- Sir.
- Try some.
- All right.
It's homemade.
It smells delicious.
Sure, it's homemade.
Chu Chu!
Your Highness, playing chess with you is more tiring than viewing files.
My mind is in a whirl.
I'll even lose my salary for the next three months.
I can't hold on. I'll go get some rest.
Check the evidence carefully, or you'll lose more salary.
Brother.
- Your Highness.
- Don't bother saluting.
Leave us.
I have something to ask you.
What is it?
Who is better in Swift Moving, you or Jing Yi?
Speaking of martial arts, I can defeat him with a single hand.
But speaking of Swift Moving, I don't want to admit it,
but he does much better than me.
Considering his Swift Moving, when he deliberately sneaks
about ten meters away from you, can you notice him?
He has poor martial arts.
If I pay attention, I'll notice him.
But I may not if I'm not paying attention.
- Why do you suddenly ask?
- Nothing.
Your Highness!
Your Highness, bad news!
Chu Chu was kidnapped!
What? When? Where?
Just now. Less than a quarter of an hour.
At the fair near the Yamen.
When I was buying something,
that man knocked her out and took her away!
It was my fault. I was too careless.
Did you see him clearly?
A middle-aged man with medium height.
I think I met him before.
- He was alone?
- Yes.
Then, you let him run away?
I...
Jinyu, I'll go assemble the soldiers.
Leng Yue, go borrow some men from Zheng Youde.
Also, bring Deputy Magistrate Tan Gui.
He's a native. He's more familiar with the local conditions.
All right.
Be quick!
Your Highness, here it is.
After he caught Chu Chu, he ran down the lane.
- I was a bit late and they were gone.
- Over there!
What kind of people live nearby?
Your Highness, common people live nearby.
Most of them do small businesses.
If I remember correctly, no one has a criminal record.
Precisely.
Leng Yue, you said when you caught up, a carriage passed by
- and stopped you so that you failed in catching up.
- Yes.
- Where?
- Right here.
Here, Your Highness.
Tracks of the carriage?
The carriage was parked there.
Chu Chu sat there.
That man knew Leng Yue was responsive and had good martial arts.
He asked the carriage to stop her.
Chu Chu!
He met Leng Yue before.
- Chu Chu!
- And he knew what she could do.
It's Xu Rugui!
Jinyu!
Is this Miss Chu's hairpin?
Where did you find it?
- Under the basket.
- Under the basket?
Chu Chu can't have dropped it.
Xu Rugui asked his man to stop Leng Yue.
He knocked Chu Chu out and took her away.
In such a short time, he dropped the hairpin under the basket.
- He did it on purpose!
- Who did it?
Xu Rugui.
Brother, keep searching this place with your men.
Have two runners stay and help.
Let the rest of them go back to the Yamen.
All right.
Does it have something to do with Jing Yi?
Who... Who are you?
I think I met you before.
Where am I?
I'm warning you! I work for the Yamen.
Commandery Prince An, you know?
I'm a coroner working for him.
He'll come and find me!
I'm sure he'll come, Chu Chu.
You know my name?
You know my name, too.
But everything was in a mess that day.
You may not remember my face.
Or you may have only remembered another image of mine in Rugui House.
You... You are...?
I'm Xu Rugui.
Timing and subtitles brought to you by The Imperial Coroners @ Viki.com
♫  Nothing can stop me  ♫
♫  From missing you all the time  ♫
♫  The moonlight appears, cold in the late night,
as the world changes  ♫
♫  Only with you by my side can I embrace my yearning for you  ♫
♫  When I close my eyes I meet you once again  ♫
♫  I'll gently brush your hair by your ear  ♫
♫  Life is long, with love and regrets in this world  ♫
♫  With you by my side, no matter how far I go,
we'll never be apart  ♫
♫  With your smile, in this moment, let me
cherish this lifetime  ♫
♫  Only for you, I have to worry about the end of this life  ♫
♫  I’m still young, with my love not yet realized for you, but I'm
willing to be here for you till the end
♫  You can rely on me in this lifetime  ♫
♫  Hope to spend this beautiful lifetime together  ♫