Timing and subtitles brought to you by The Imperial Coroners @ Viki.com
Li Zhang illegally made coin molds and minted coins.
He used the mint as bait, trying to kill us.
Fortunately, Chu Chu's astuteness saved me.
Chu Chu, I will never give you up.
Please, don't up on me.
Go.
We got Xu Rugui! Withdraw! Withdraw!
[The Imperial Coroner]
[Episode 26]
[Guanling County Office]
It's not easy to investigate the illegal minting of coins,
but now you have the right to act at your discretion in Qianzhou.
It's much more convenient now.
My father got you the authority without any trace.
I almost didn't realize it.
But, Your Highness, my father put a lot of thought to protecting us.
This is not a good sign.
That's right. Even Senior Jing is so careful about this,
it can be seen that the picture doesn't look good in Chang'an.
I'm afraid it's going to be harder
than we estimated to go back to Chang'an and redress the case.
Now, Xu Rugui is on his way back to Chang'an with Mr. Xue.
If Senior Jing can make good use of him,
maybe he can suppress Qin Luan for a while.
Rest assured. The first person to know about this must be my father.
I've sent a message to him as you told me.
With him being in Chang'an, I think they can't make any waves.
Leng Yue, did you get any reply to the previous letter?
Your Highness, I'm going to leave first.
Not yet.
Then stay in the mansion today.
It should be about the right time.
Greetings to Your Highness!
Get up.
Your Highness, the Prefect's Mansion caught fire.
What?
Your Highness, after you and Prefect Li Zhang left the County Office for Phoenix Mountain yesterday,
I took some people to raid the Prefect's Mansion quietly as you ordered.
When we arrived at the Prefect's Mansion in the afternoon,
it had been burned into ruins.
When did the fire start? Did anyone get hurt?
According to the people nearby, around noon yesterday,
a group of soldiers suddenly surrounded the Prefect's Mansion
and took away everyone there.
They set the Prefect's Mansion on fire.
Fortunately, it was during the day. There was a lot of noise.
The people nearby had been evacuated before the fire got bigger.
No one got hurt. A few houses nearby were destroyed by the fire.
Soldiers? What soldiers?
I... I didn't really see them.
- I dare not speculate.
- Feel free to tell us.
Well...
You took General Xiao's four soldiers with you.
There were soldiers going into the Prefect's Mansion before the fire and the people nearby saw them.
Did they wear the same clothes as General Xiao's men?
Yes.
What did the four soldiers coming with you say?
They had a big reaction.
They said someone wanted to frame them.
Your Highness, I didn't dare to speculate
because I think this matter is very strange.
Strange how?
General Xiao brought a limited number of soldiers.
Except those who followed you to the mountain,
and those who followed me to the Prefect's Mansion,
there are no more than four or five people left.
According to the people at the scene,
there were at least twenty soldiers when they set the fire.
How could General Xiao gather so many people in such a short time?
General Xiao's soldiers are all from Military Commissioner's army.
But there are tens of thousands of soldiers in the Military Commissioner's army.
These soldiers in Qianzhou
are not necessarily General Xiao's subordinates.
You mean General Leng?
What?
Your Highness, General Xiao is back.
Magistrate Zheng.
Commandery Prince An.
Well... Prefect Li is unconscious now.
General Xiao won't allow me to get a doctor here or visit him.
Well... If anything happens to Prefect Li at my office,
what should I do?
Go to the side hall and ask Miss Leng to come here.
Miss Leng?
Yes, yes. I'll go get her.
How is he doing?
I mean, I moved the stones for the whole night.
I've been so busy that I haven't had time to drink any water.
I got dust everywhere. But you only worry about him. Why don't you worry about me?
Aren't you standing here and denouncing me loudly?
Should I need to worry about you?
Fine.
See? He has woken up.
He is fine.
Li Zhang.
Your Highness.
Your Highness is here. Your Highness is here.
Your Highness is here.
Your Highness! Your Highness!
Your Highness, mercy! Your Highness, mercy!
Is he delirious? Who is he greeting?
Your Highness, mercy!
Hurry and order someone you can trust to cordon off this courtyard.
Don't let anyone come near here without permission except for Leng Yue and Jing Yi!
- All right.
- Hurry.
Be careful.
Your Highness, mercy!
[Self-Discipline and Virtue]
You guys get everyone out of here and lock down the courtyard!
- Yes!
You. Go.
Go.
- Miss Leng.
- Hurry.
Miss Leng, please.
What's going on here?
Commandery Prince An has urgent affairs to deal with.
No one is allowed to approach without permission.
Magistrate Zheng, please go back.
Urgent affairs?
Do you need me to send more people here to guard the yard?
General Xiao, feel free to order me if you need anything.
- I will...
- Go far away.
Do you hear me?
Well... Yes, I hear you.
What's the fuss about?
Just for Li Zhang?
Can he fly away?
It's Commandery Prince An's order.
You and Leng Yue go inside.
Your Highness, mercy. Your Highness, mercy.
Your Highness, mercy!
Your Highness, is Li Zhang awake?
I'm here.
What do you want to say?
Your Highness! Your Highness!
Your Highness, mercy! Your Highness, mercy.
Your Highness, I blew it up.
They all know it.
They are still alive.
Your Highness, run away!
Your Highness, you can't run. You can't run.
I will kill Xiao Jinyu! Kill Xiao Jinyu...
I will kill Xiao Jinyu!
Kill Xiao Jinyu... Kill Xiao Jinyu...
Where do you want me to go?
Your Highness. Your Highness. You run...
Your Highness, you can't run.
You are the rightful Emperor of Tang.
The country is yours.
You can't run away. You can't run away!
Nonsense! What are you talking about?
What the hell is he talking about?
Duke Chang has arrived!
Long live Your Majesty!
What's going on here?
Tell me about it.
Looks like the mastermind behind Li Zhang is really Duke Chang.
Li Zhang went crazy. Are you two also crazy?
Li Zhang suffered a brain injury.
He was crushed by rocks and buried for too long.
He had difficulty breathing, and the injury worsened because of suffocation.
That's why he becomes delirious.
Can he be cured?
This kind of brain injury is the same as a spine injury. It's incurable.
He will only get worse.
If he wakes up later, he will only become more delirious.
Do you hear that, Jinyu? Li Zhang went crazy.
He is talking crazy.
No, just because he is crazy, what he said just now is the truth.
Come on.
Emperor Wuzong's son is dead.
Everyone in court knows it. Even a roughneck like me knows it.
When Emperor Wuzong was alive, he saw his uncle as a thorn in the eye.
Emperor Wuzong's son is a forbidden subject for the His Majesty.
How dare you take such a guess.
Don't you want your head to stay on your neck?
Hold on!  Let me sort this out.
The current emperor is the uncle of the late Emperor Wuzong.
Which means if Duke Chang, the son of Emperor Wuzong, is still alive,
it should be Duke Chang who'd ascend the throne.
The rightful emperor Li Zhang kept mentioning Duke Chang.
- Yes.
- What?
You are the most perceptive and cautious one when it comes to these matters.
Why are you also nodding along?
I was being just like you
when Commandery Prince An said that to me earlier.
But I have to believe it now.
Didn't you hear a saying
that nothing is more true than what a madman says?
Earlier?
I mean, Jinyu, when did you start thinking about Duke Chang?
Before I came to Qianzhou.
What?
It was just my speculation.
Now it looks like I'm right about it.
There is no solid evidence to prove Duke Chang is still alive,
but those who cut off the message between Chang'an and Qianzhou,
and instructed Li Zhang to mint copper coins
should be this group of people under the banner of Duke Chang.
They are up to something.
Up to something? What?
To recruit soldiers... and usurp the throne.
Do you know what you are talking about?
Jing Yi, you also think so?
I don't want to think in this way.
But it makes sense.
As the Prefect of Qianzhou, it's the most secretive way to let him
be in charge of recruiting soldiers.
Besides, he used illegally minted coins.
He doesn't need to touch the public money.
All he needs to do is to change the account book.
There is no time for the prologue.
I just want to know what we should do now.
Go back to Chang'an now?
We can't. The emperor just issued an imperial edict
and ordered Commandery Prince An to investigate the illegal minting of coins in Qianzhou.
I guess the eunuch who announced the imperial edict hasn't left Qianzhou yet.
We only have a cave that was blown up,
a Li Zhang who can't even explain his own identity,
and a suspect who has been dead for years in the emperor's mind.
If we go back to Chang'an now, we have no witness nor physical evidence.
It's not believable at all.
What should we do then?
How about writing a memorial to report these things to the emperor?
You can ask the emperor to issue an imperial edict to allow you to go back.
We can't, either.
The emperor might not believe it even when we tell him face-to-face.
It will be harder for him to believe it if we write it on paper.
If someone treacherous accuses us of making it up,
we will only receive the edict of punishment.
Nothing will work. Can you say something useful?
Take it easy.
Jing Yi is right.
We can't report it to the court rashly.
This group of people intercepted the messages between Chang'an and Qianzhou,
illegally minted a large number of coins,
and just killed the Minister of War, Feng Jie, who just finished
his inspection of the military affairs in the Southwest and rushed back to Chang'an.
I think Feng Jie got killed because he found something
during the military inspections.
It's very likely that the rebels are in the Southwest.
If that's the case, once they know that Li Zhang failed to kill us,
then it will be the rebels who want to kill us next.
Our safety is a small matter.
But if we act rashly and alert them,
making them take desperate action and go to war with the government,
plunging the people into the flames of war,
then it will really be a dilemma.
We have to find out where they are and wipe them out in one fell swoop
before they take any action.
I didn't bring many soldiers this time.
We can defend against some ordinary bandits, but not an army.
Why don't you go back to the base of the Military Commissioner with me?
No matter how wild this group of bandits are,
I don't believe they dare to break into the base of the Military Commissioner.
No, we can't.
Your Highness, I'm afraid the base of the Military Commissioner is also not safe now.
What?
I thought it was nonsense.
I wanted to tell you later.
This is the letter "that guy" sent to me just now.
Your Highness, take a look first.
To Commandery Prince An,
[Leng Peishan]
I heard that Commandery Prince An was ordered to investigate the case of illegally minting coins in Qianzhou.
I shouldn't have bothered you.
However, weird things have happened frequently in the army and people have gotten killed.
There might be evil spirits involved in this.
I'm afraid the soldiers will rise in revolt if we do nothing about it.
I wonder if you can come here in person and check it.
[Jing's Mansion]
Master.
Where is the news from?
Master, it's from Qianzhou.
It's about the Military Commissioner.
Strange things have happened frequently in the base of the Military Commissioner. No one knows what's going on.
About seven or eight people have gone mad.
Three people have committed suicide.
It's spreading panic in the army now.
[Princess Xiping Mansion]
Why did you lie to me?
How could you lie to me?
Your Grace.
What's the fuss about?
Your Grace, I just got the news that there are people looking for
the servants dismissed by us in the early years.
Who?
These people act in secret.
I just got wind of it and I think this matter is of great importance,
so I came to report it to you.
Your Grace.
Your Grace, don't worry. General Wu just left.
He shouldn't have gone far.
Do we need to send someone to get him back and ask him to find out who they are?
No. We can't let anyone know it,
not even the people from the Three Judicial Offices.
Otherwise, Jinli and Jinyu will be in great danger.
Go to the mansion and find some guards you can trust.
Ask them to investigate it secretly.
- Remember to keep quiet about it.
- Yes.
- Hurry.
Go to the base of the Military Commissioner of Qianzhongdao?
Don't worry. It's my father's last wish
to overturn the case of your father and the soldiers of
the Military Commissioner of Jiannan.
I won't forget about it.
It's just that it implicates too many people.
I still need to elaborate on the plan carefully.
Otherwise, even with the evidence left by my father,
it's hard for us to solve it for good.
What's more, if we don't find out what's happening in the base of the Military Commissioner,
I'm afraid we can hardly go back to Chang'an safely.
I understand. I'll listen to you.
But the Military Commissioner's base is heavily guarded.
I heard that even a bird can't get anywhere near it.
Who would dare to make trouble there?
General Leng wrote a letter to Leng Yue.
He said that there have been several soldiers going crazy for no reason.
Some soldiers even committed suicide.
Within a few days,
the rumors are spreading in the army and causing panic.
What rumors?
The rumors of... evil spirits.
Evil spirits?
The Military Commissioner, Leng Peishan, who is Leng Yue's grandfather,
hopes I can leave for the base now to expel the evil spirits.
There is no evil spirit in the world.
Just take the ghost house built by Sir Witch Doctor,
everyone was talking about it like it was real,
but it turned out to be the wind.
If there is an evil spirit in this world,
the coroners don't need to do any autopsy at all.
Your Highness, do you really believe there are dangerous evil spirits in the world?
Master didn't talk about spiritual beings.
The so-called evil spirits are just the embodiment of evil minds.
However, the army of the Military Commissioner is a strong guard in the Southwest.
If anything happens to them,
those who will suffer are the people living in the Southwest.
This happened strangely.
Whether a ghost or a human being did it,
we have to find out the truth first
before we return to Chang'an to redress the case.
General Xiao, the people near the Prefect's Mansion said that it was the soldiers of the Military Commissioner who
I dare not tell any lie.
I got it.
General Xiao, is it really General Leng who ordered those people to do it?
We all know what kind of person General Leng is.
How would he join hands with someone like Li Zhang?
I know my brother.
He will never wrong a good person.
Nothing is clear yet.
We can only know the truth
after we go back to the base and investigate it.
Go back and rest.
We will leave early tomorrow morning.
Yes.
You are thoughtful indeed.
What should we do about Prefect Li?
It's an established fact that Li Zhang illegally minted coins,
but the mastermind behind him hasn't been captured yet.
I don't know how many more people are involved.
So we can't convict and punish him for now.
He is delirious and talking crazy now.
It's inconvenient to detain him at the County Office.
I've asked Jinli to find some people to imprison him secretly.
We will deal with him after we find out the truth.
I guess he got what he deserved.
When will we leave?
Your Highness, don't worry. With my family staying here,
my dad will take good care of the body of Sir Witch Doctor.
To make sure your family won't be implicated,
I will ask my men to send your family to a safe place.
And I can rest assured to entrust my father's body to your family.
It's just that I'm afraid...
I can't keep my promise this time.
Promise? What promise?
I promised you I will keep you safe forever.
You regret it?
No. Of course not.
Then you mean...
Chu Chu...
I should have sent you to a safe place to hide for a while,
or sent you back to Chang'an first.
But this time, your father's case has not been redressed.
If anyone becomes aware of your identity,
I'm afraid you will be in great danger.
What happened in the army is very strange.
I'm afraid it will also be dangerous.
After some thought,
- I think I have to take you with me and put you at risk.
- What?
Your Highness, are you going to take me with you to the base?
This will be a dangerous trip.
If you don't...
♫ The moment ♫
♫ You smile ♫
♫ Let me cherish it for good ♫
♫ Because of you ♫
♫ I care about my life ♫
♫ I'm not old yet ♫
♫ I still love you ♫
♫ At last I settle down for you ♫
♫ I can rely on you all my life ♫
Your Highness, I thought you would regret being with me.
I'm not afraid of any danger.
Besides, we promised each other in the cave
that no matter what happens, we will face it together.
As a dignified commandery prince, you can't break your promise.
Chu Chu, what I said and did in the cave that day...
was not honorable.
I think I took advantage of the situation.
I should have asked you again in a serious way.
But I'm afraid if I ask you again,
you will reject me.
I always keep my words.
I said yes and I won't regret it.
Chu Chu...
I know I'm not a likable man.
For a woman, I am not good enough to be a husband.
I always think that you don't know many men now.
After your father's case is redressed,
you will become a true lady from a family of loyal subjects.
After you meet all those handsome young masters in Chang'an,
you will get tired of me.
How will you still cherish me at that time?
I don't want you to fall for other men.
So I hurried to show you my love
and wanted to make you do the same thing.
Now I've confessed my nasty thoughts to you.
If you regret it now...  I won't blame you
♫ Let me cherish it for good ♫
♫ Because of you ♫
♫ I care about my life ♫
I don't like any other young master. I only like you.
Your Highness, don't worry.
No matter how many times you ask me, the answer will always be yes.
♫ I can rely on you all my life ♫
I tied a red string to the Tree of Love and made a wish.
They said the tree can make my dream come true.
But I still can't believe these things.
I want to hear your answer again.
Will you marry me?
Will you take all my love for you for the rest of your life?
I will.
♫ Spend our lives through time ♫
♫ Every time we see the setting sun ♫
♫ Every time we look back, we're by each other's side ♫
Chu Chu.
Father, I'm coming.
What are you doing here?
Mellow wine.
That's the wine for a heroine to get drunk.
Here, take the roast chicken.
A sip of wine and a bite of meat. Then beat me up.
Beat you up? Why?
I don't know.
Don't knights like you have to fight
after drinking to feel comfortable?
That's what the storyteller in Guangtai House said.
Give me some wine.
Just this little bit?
With your little tolerance,
if you get drunk, I'll have to carry you down.
I'm not asking for trouble.
I'm glad that you didn't ask for trouble.
If you really don't want to go to the base,
just talk to Commandery Prince An. Or you can just leave.
Commandery Prince An won't make you go there.
Why are you drinking alone on the roof of the County Office?
I have to go this time.
Chu Chu.
Do you really like Chu Chu or are you just used to bossing her around?
I never wanted to boss her around.
She is the best coroner in the world.
She is bold but cautious.
I respect her just as I respect all talented and upright people.
She works for me as a coroner.
I'm not bossing her around. She is helping me.
I'm not talking about coroner.
I'm asking...
if you really like her.
She is the best girl in the world.
How can I not like her?
Do you think she is the best girl in the world?
Don't you think so?
She is my sister.
Of course, my sister is the best girl in the world.
But you just...
I saw it.
Are you going to take her with you?
Yes.
The Three Judicial Offices, Chongrenfang, North Street, Chang'an.
What did you say?
It's my residence in Chang'an.
You can come to visit Chu Chu anytime you want.
[Three Judicial Offices]
Take this token and come to my residence in Chang'an.
No one will stop you when they see it.
Remember what you just said.
No matter how high your rank is, no matter how far you are,
if you dare hurt Chu Chu,
I will never let you go.
You don't have to hide it from me.
I don't know much about politics,
but I also grew up with you and Commandery Prince An.
I know what you two meant when you winked at each other. I understand
that man's letter came at a perfect time, didn't it?
We just caught Li Zhang.
His soldiers set the Prefect's Mansion on fire.
Then his man sent such a letter.
Evil spirits.
I think he is the biggest evil.
What if it's just a coincidence?
Coincidence?
I don't think you know it.
Commandery Prince An has been suspecting him for some time.
He asked me to write a letter of no importance to throw a stone to clear the road.
As a result, something is wrong with him.
Your Highness, since you think Miss Leng's grandpa inviting us to his base is a trap,
why are you still going?
You have to play with fire to stay warm.
Chu Chu, remember, after we arrive at the base, except for my brother
and the people coming with us from Chang'an,
any other people's words can't be trusted.
I got it.
Your Highness, you are preparing for the worst again. Right?
Miss Leng must feel bad now.
I know that feeling.
The feeling that you can't stop worrying if your family is a bad person.
She will think it through.
Even if she can't think it through for now,
someone will help her think it through.
Leng Yue, he is still your grandpa.
You know what kind of person he is.
You know him too, don't you?
Considering how cowardly you are,
even you are volunteering to go to the base and fish for information with Commandery Prince An's guards.
What does that mean?
Obviously, you think he is up to something and you want to find it out.
Duke Chang and the son of Emperor Wuzong are just excuses and disguises.
I think he is probably the mastermind.
Hush. You can't say that.
Why not?
Even you care about my feelings.
What about him? When did he ever care about me?
He doesn't care about me now.
He was the same when my father and mother died.
He only sent a letter that the Military Commissioner of Jiannan rebelled.
He was stationed in the Southwest and couldn't return to Chang'an.
Then my parents died in the insurgency in Chang'an.
Now I know it.
It was not a rebellion, it was...!
You can't say that, either.
I used to think he was just ruthless,
but at least he was loyal to his country.
Now I know he isn't even loyal.
What kind of person is he? He is a bastard!
- Give it to me.
- Give it back to me! I bought it!
I also bought the roast chicken. It didn't cost me any lesser.
Let's change it.
Leng Yue, do you know why Commandery Prince An can solve every case?
Normally, when there are several totally different possibilities,
people will subconsciously choose the one they want to believe.
If they can't disprove the other possibilities,
they will start to feel irritable and depressed.
Just like the way you are.
You are even venting your feelings on the roast chicken.
But Commandery Prince An is different.
When he is in such a situation,
he will choose not to believe any of it
and then deduce the truth step by step through the evidence he collects.
And the truth might be completely different
from the previous possibilities.
Just like Li Zhang and Xu Rugui.
Even the storyteller in Guangtai House
can't make up such a strange story. Right?
But when Commandery Prince An shows you the evidence,
you have to believe that's the truth.
What do you want to say?
I just want to say we are all mortals.
We have feelings.
It's normal to feel agitated and depressed
because you can't prove your speculation for now.
But you also need to know the truth in the end
might be completely different from what you think now.
No matter what the final truth is, we will face it together with you.
As for me sneaking into the base, don't worry about it.
I'm an expert in putting on an act and asking around.
Besides, I can still run away if it doesn't work out. You know me.
If I want to escape, even the guards in the palace can't get me.
Right. I remember how timid you are.
You must run faster than a rabbit if anything goes wrong.
I'm not worried about you.
Are you still coming with us?
Of course.
But don't worry, I won't do anything stupid.
I just want to know the truth.
Fine.
Go back to your room after you finish the roast chicken.
I've prepared the bath water for you.
Go back to my room after I finish the roast chicken?
You took my wine.
According to the storyteller, I should beat you up first.
Don't run!
[Ready to pick up the goods]
Manager, I've tidied the things up.
Go to the pharmacy now and get this prescription filled.
(Prescription)
Remember, don't just go to one pharmacy.
Get it filled in several pharmacies.
Who is so bold to intercept and kill a minister
and rescue the criminal under my watch!
Your Majesty, calm your anger.
Calm my anger?
How can I calm my anger?
Xue Rucheng took the criminal Xu Rugui back to Chang'an.
But Xu Rugui was taken away in the suburbs of Chang'an.
As the Minister of War, he was nearly killed
under the protection of the Imperial Guard in broad daylight!
We even don't know who did it.
Well, Commandery Prince An is not in Chang'an now.
Is there no judge who can arrest criminals?
Your Majesty, these officials are incompetent.
You can denounce them and punish them as you want.
You don't have to save face for them and make yourself feel bad.
Your Majesty, getting angry can hurt your health.
You must take care of yourself.
Your Majesty, you have been busy with national affairs recently.
Have a cup of soothing tea first.
Master, when it comes to making the emperor happy,
you are the number one in the world.
No one can do it better than you do.
Listen. Only when I am happy, I'll have the mood to make him happy.
Well, Master, what are you happy about?
Tell me and let me share your happiness.
What else could it be?
Zhou Han finally did a good job.
Shouldn't I be happy about it?
Is there any news from Zhou Han?
Where did he take Xu Rugui to?
Xu Rugui was taken...
Zhou Han got Xu Rugui?
Wait, Master. Hold on.
- Zhou Han got Xu Rugui?
- Yeah.
Zhou Han only said
he planted his men among the soldiers of the Shence Army
who escorted Xu Rugui.
But he didn't mention that he got Xu Rugui out.
Timing and subtitles brought to you by The Imperial Coroners @ Viki.com
♫  Nothing can stop me  ♫
♫  From missing you all the time  ♫
♫  The moonlight appears, cold in the late night,
as the world changes  ♫
♫  Only with you by my side can I embrace my yearning for you  ♫
♫  When I close my eyes I meet you once again  ♫
♫  I'll gently brush your hair by your ear  ♫
♫  Life is long, with love and regrets in this world  ♫
♫  With you by my side, no matter how far I go,
we'll never be apart  ♫
♫  With your smile, in this moment, let me
cherish this lifetime  ♫
♫  Only for you, I have to worry about the end of this life  ♫
♫  I’m still young, with my love not yet realized for you, but I'm
willing to be here for you till the end
♫  You can rely on me in this lifetime  ♫
♫  Hope to spend this beautiful lifetime together  ♫