Timing and subtitles brought to you by The Imperial Coroners @ Viki.com
Chu Chu, I want to spend every day with you
and take care of you for the rest of my life.
Will you marry me?
I can do whatever he asks me to do.
But... But I can't marry him.
She obviously likes me.
But why won't she marry me?
[Guanling County Office]
I can't intervene in the affairs of the Three Judicial Offices.
You can decide for yourself.
But it's the emperor's order to bring Chu Chu back to Chang'an.
Either I take her back or I take back the truth of Commandery Prince An Consort's case.
I don't mean to offend you,
but neither Chu Chu nor the evidence about my father's case
can be taken away by you.
It's not that I don't trust you,
I just can't trust those guards around you from the Shence Army.
It concerns the Division of Eunuchs.
It's too important.
I have to be careful enough.
However, if you only want to report on your mission,
I can let you take Xu Rugui back.
Xu Rugui?
Xu Rugui is Chu Chu's uncle.
Chu Chu's biological mother turned to him for help,
but he killed her to keep himself safe.
Then he threw himself onto the lap of Qin Luan and became his minion.
He was ordered by Qin Luan to arrest Chu Chu in Qianzhou
in order to get one step ahead and find my father.
Now he has failed and Qin Luan abandoned him and wants to kill him.
Wu Jiang saved his family secretly in Chang'an.
If you bring him back to Chang'an
and promise him to give his family a way out,
Xu Rugui will tell the truth in front of the emperor.
Then the emperor will know that Chu Chu is in danger now.
I will draw up another memorial to explain the cause in detail
and implore him to allow me to finish the affairs in Qianzhou first.
Then, I'll bring Chu Chu back to Chang'an to apologize for our offense.
You can report on your mission this way.
Yes, I can.
But if anything goes wrong, you will be blamed and punished.
I'm willing to bear all the consequences.
It's just that Qin Luan won't give up easily.
If you are going to bring Xu Rugui back to Chang'an,
you must take strict precautions along the way.
Your Highness, there is an imperial edict.
Here is the imperial edict.
"The illegal minting of coins in Qianzhou
disturbed the people and broke the law,
damaged the people's livelihood and the national fortune.
Commandery Prince An, Xiao Jinyu, is known for his ability in court
to solve difficult and strange cases,
and is the right person to investigate and handle
the case of illegal minting of copper coins in Qianzhou.
From today on, Commandery Prince An is given
the power to act at his discretion.
All the officials in Qianzhou are at his disposal."
Respect this.
Minister Xiao Jinyu receives the edict and thanks Your Majesty.
Commandery Prince An, I need to rush back to Chang'an and report on my mission.
I should leave.
By the way, before I left Chang'an, Senior Jing asked me
to bring you a message.
Qianzhou is dangerous.
You must be careful.
Thank you very much.
I should leave.
Sir, now I'm ordered by the emperor to investigate the case of illegal minting of coins.
I can't return to Chang'an before I solve this case.
I hope you can agree with what I just said.
All right.
Since you have the power to act at your discretion,
you can keep Chu Chu here in the name of investigating the case
and this can be an explanation to the emperor.
Without delay, I'll set off immediately
and bring Xu Rugui back to Chang'an
lest the treacherous man gets the news.
Thank you, Sir.
[The Imperial Coroner]
[Episode 24]
- Chu Chu.
- Your Highness.
Is there anything you need me to do?
No.
I was...
abrupt last night.
It was busy just now and I didn't have time to talk to you.
I'm here to apologize to you.
Here are some rouge and powder.
It took me a long time to pick it.
I still feel that it's not good enough for you.
But it's the best I can find.
If you take it, it means you forgive me.
Your Highness, I'm not blaming you.
I can't take this.
I'm a coroner and I spend a lot of time with corpses.
I...
I might not smell good.
But distinguishing the smell is very important for an autopsy.
If I use powder, the result will be inaccurate.
If it bothers you, I will stay away from you.
That's not what I meant.
Then I will take this back.
I have one more thing for you.
I saw it on my way here.
You popped up in my mind when I saw it.
So I picked it for you.
Thank you, Your Highness.
Your Highness, is there anything else?
Nothing.
I forgot that a coroner doesn't use powder.
But why did she throw your flowers into the swill bucket?
Did you say exactly what I told you?
Yes, exactly.
It was my first time to say such wild words.
How could I remember it wrong?
That's weird.
That doesn't sound like something Chu Chu would do.
What flowers did you give her?
As you said, inconspicuous at first glance,
but exquisitely beautiful when you look carefully.
This is good.
What's the matter?
You came just at the right time.
You are close to Chu Chu. Help us analyze it.
Commandery Prince An sent flowers to Chu Chu.
Chu Chu said thanks and threw the flowers into the swill bucket.
Flowers? This one?
Yeah.
This is Lespedeza. It can be used as medicine.
But normally people use it to feed pigs.
No wonder she threw it into the swill bucket.
To feed pigs?
[Lespedeza | Used to feed pigs]
You told her she popped up in your mind when you saw it?
You two, get out.
You came up with that bad idea of sending flowers and rouge to her, right?
What do you mean by "that bad idea"?
Isn't this a necessary step to please a girl?
Who would've known that Chu Chu is such an otherworldly person?
Jinyu, is what Jing Yi said true?
A necessary step to please a girl.
You are so experienced.
What girls did you please before?
- It was all for show.
Is there no one you really like?
There is one.
Who?
Never mind. Perhaps she doesn't like me at all, and it's just my wishful thinking.
You can tell me.
I...
I can give you some advice
and make sure you will get her.
Really?
Then you need to teach me, step by step.
I mean, how could you listen to Jing Yi about such a kind of thing?
Do you have any good ideas?
What good idea can I have?
You are really being desperate.
Let me ask you. Has Miss Chu ever adored Jing Yi?
It means Jing Yi's method doesn't work on Miss Chu at all.
No wonder it didn't work out. Right?
You have a point.
But I don't know whom Chu Chu adored before.
Who do you want her to adore?
You know it.
That's it.
Now it's you who wants her love.
So you should do it in your own way...
and follow your heart.
You do have a point.
I didn't think it through.
You've suffered a lot from searching the mountains during the past few days.
When I used to go into the mountains to suppress bandits,
I would stay there about half a month.
This is a piece of cake for me.
Your Highness.
Come in.
Your Highness, the Prefect of Qianzhou, Li Zhang, presents himself.
Greetings to Commandery Prince An and Vice Minister Jing.
Did you come here so late for Chu Chu?
No, no. I was in a hurry before and I acted recklessly.
I still owe you an apology for my offense.
Then, why are you here?
Commandery Prince An, Vice Minister Jing and I talked about
the illegal minting of coins in Qianzhou on that day.
I know that this matter is of great importance.
It took me some effort and I found out some clues about the case.
Today, I received the imperial edict that all the officials in Qianzhou
should fully assist Commandery Prince An to investigate this case.
I'm here to report it to you.
During these days, I've checked the production
of all mines under my control.
I asked my people to take the fake coins
and consult the local experienced miners one by one.
After comparisons, I came to the conclusion
[Investigation of Illegal Minting of Coins in Qianzhou]
that the coins should be made from
copper and tin ore in the Guanling Mountain area.
I've written the detailed process of investigation
and the results in the case file.
Thank you for your efforts.
This is what I should do.
Prefect Li, I spend a lot of money,
but I don't know much about making money.
Please favor me with your instruction.
I dare not. Please favor me with your instruction.
In your opinion, why would these people mint coins illegally?
Why...?
They mint coins for profits.
Where do the profits come from?
I'm slow-witted. Please enlighten me.
Let me put it this way.
The coins don't come out of nowhere.
It requires a lot of manpower and material resources to mint coins.
Normally the coins they made for profits
are in poor quality and light.
The cost of minting a coin
is much lower than the face value of a coin.
Then their efforts are not wasted. Am I right?
You are right, Vice Minister Jing.
That's weird.
The current batch of fake coins minted in Qianzhou
looks just like the genuine coins
in terms of the fineness, the texture, and the weight.
It can be seen that they used some good materials and a lot of labor.
The cost can be imagined.
If it's just for this little profit, why don't they do something else
but such a dangerous thing?
Vice Minister Jing is scrupulous indeed.
I never thought about this.
Your Highness, what do you think?
Why bother with this now?
We can ask the supervisors after we find the mint.
You are right, Your Highness.
Your Highness, I think the mint is very likely
in the Phoenix Mountain in Guanling County.
Prefect Li, that's also what we think.
Do you also think so?
If you don't mind us usurping your authority,
we want to go to the mountain with you tomorrow.
Okay, I'm much relieved
if you two come with me.
Are we all going to the mountain tomorrow?
Tomorrow, you lead the troop
and follow me and Li Zhang into the mountain to find the mint.
Jing Yi, Leng Yue, and Zheng Youde
will take some runners to the tree hole
and round off the case of Xu Rugui.
What about Miss Chu?
If I don't let her come, she will come after she knows it.
I will be misunderstood
and I'm afraid I can't explain it for the rest of my life.
It's perilous in the mountains,
instead of letting her run around alone,
it will be safer to keep her close to me.
You are right. There is one more thing.
Did Mr. Xue mention the marriage of me and Leng Yue before he left?
He said it's a blessing in disguise.
It's good for you to marry Leng Yue.
What?
I mean, what is Mr. Xue thinking about?
Leng Yue is not that bad, right?
Why are you also making it worse? No.
Is it about whether she is good or bad?
It will get people killed.
What will get people killed is the power struggle behind this marriage, not Leng Yue.
Don't you think Leng Yue is a good girl?
You are my real brother indeed.
How can you ask me at this point?
I'm just asking you if Leng Yue is a good girl.
Yes, Leng Yue is a good girl.
But I'm just like you.
I always see her as a good friend.
I never thought of marrying her.
So I'm saying you and Leng Yue are both victims.
But you are still hurting each other.
Hold on!
Mr. Xue didn't say anything about a blessing in disguise, right?
Well done. You got the nerve to make fun of your big brother.
I'm not in the mood to make fun of you.
It's just that things are getting more complicated in Qianzhou.
I don't want you two to be at odds in the face of our enemies.
You are a general.
You should know better than I do
that trust can be a matter of life and death sometimes.
Yes, you are right.
I'm going to fight...
To have a good chat with her.
My Lord.
Everything is prepared as you ordered.
Get more people to follow them into the mountain tomorrow.
I want to see how lucky Xiao Jinyu is.
Xiao Jinli will also bring soldiers to protect him tomorrow.
Well...
What?
Don't worry, My Lord.
You are resourceful and you can capture your enemy easily.
Xiao Jinyu won't come back alive this time.
You can leave.
Are you sure about it?
Don't worry. I've made a thorough plan.
Xiao Jinyu will take the bait.
If it's done, the irrefutable proof that we mint coins
will be gone forever.
Then go ahead and do it.
I won't fail you.
You mustn't take it lightly.
Xiao Jinyu is on guard against you.
So what if he is on guard against me?
Xiao Jinyu is ordered to investigate the case.
He will take the bait if he sees one.
This place is rarely visited indeed.
We've been walking for a while and there are no people at all.
Of course. There is nothing here.
It has been rainy recently.
There are even fewer people going into the mountain.
General Xiao, what place are we looking for in the mountains?
Ask Commandery Prince An.
A place to mint coins.
Mint coins? Shouldn't the government mint coins?
Why would we come to Phoenix Mountain?
Some people are illegally minting coins in Qianzhou.
Prefect Li found out that the ore used for minting coins
is from the mountains in Guanling County.
He suspects that the mint is in Phoenix Mountain.
Here?
Magistrate Zheng.
I heard from Chu Chu that a lot of people have fallen in here.
If Commandery Prince An didn't say it in front of your face today,
I think you would only fill the hole when you had fallen in there yourself.
Yes, yes. No, No.
No, no.
I'm shameful.
I'm guilty.
Fill the hole carefully.
Don't damage the roots of the tree.
Yes.
It's a felony to illegally mint coins.
This group of people is so bold.
They must be well prepared.
The mint they chose must be a hidden and a convenient place.
Do you have any idea?
I'm not capable enough, but I took a guess.
Feel free to say it.
Minting coins not only requires manpower,
but also copper ore, tin ore, water, and firewood.
The ore can be transported from elsewhere,
but water and firewood must be sufficient here.
Otherwise, it would be inconvenient and greatly increase the cost.
The cost will outweigh the gain.
Therefore, the mint must be in a lush forest with abundant water,
and it's convenient to get in and out.
After all, a large number of coins need to be sent out of the mountain.
They won't take a road like this.
You've said a lot. Where is this place?
I need to ask Miss Chu about this.
Me?
There are many places here with plenty of trees,
sufficient water, and a convenient road.
I don't know, either.
Are you making a wish?
I'm not.
Childish.
I saw you and Xiao Jinli drinking and laughing on the roof
of the county office last night.
What were you talking about?
None of your business.
Did you agree to marry him?
Actually, if I think about it, Xiao Jinli is pretty good.
If I marry him, I'll be Commandery Prince An's sister-in-law.
Then no one would dare to talk nonsense to me.
You really think so?
You can't think this way. Xiao Jinli...
there is nothing good about Xiao Jinli.
He is stubborn and bad-tempered.
He wears the same clothes all day long.
He also has stinky socks on him.
You can't marry him.
You won't be happy if you marry him.
Then, who should I marry that will make me happy?
Me... Me.
You must be sick.
What's wrong with me? Consider me.
No.
Chu Chu.
Is there any place in the mountain
with running water that does not flow into the villages,
dense bamboo forests, and a road leading to
the busiest place down the mountain?
Running water that does not flow into the villages,
dense bamboo forests, and a road leading to the busiest place?
Minting coins requires a lot of sustained water.
So it must be running water.
If the sewage generated by minting coins
flows into the water source where people live,
it would be easily noticed.
So the running water must flow to a place where no one lives,
like in this valley, to stay hidden for a long time.
Minting coins needs to burn wood.
Although bamboo is not the best fuel,
it's easy to cut down and it grows fast.
It's convenient and not easy to be noticed.
As for the road leading to the busiest place,
because this place is sparsely populated,
no matter the coins are sent out in a small amount with more times
or in a large amount with fewer times,
it's still very easy to be noticed.
But if they blend in the crowd in disguise,
it would be much safer for them.
It makes sense.
When you put it like this, I think there is such a place.
But that place is not a mint.
It's a kiln.
A kiln?
A place to produce porcelain.
That place is exactly the same as you described.
A kiln? Yeah.
It must be that kiln.
It's not an official kiln, right?
No. I can swear with my head.
There is no registered official kiln in Phoenix Mountain.
I know where that kiln is.
I'll take you there.
Thank you, Miss Chu.
Your Highness, please.
It's here.
Go. Hurry up!
Commandery Prince An. It looks like no one has been here for a long time.
How did it become like this?
I remember there was smoke coming up
when I went into the mountain in November last year.
There are no ruts on the ground and no footprints.
The yellow leaves of last winter are still here.
This place should have been abandoned for several months.
Even though this kiln is empty now,
I think there must be some clues here.
I remember you mentioned in a case file you sent back to me
that every move of a person will leave a trace.
Those who destroy the remains
will also leave traces of the destruction.
There are always clues.
Jinyu.
Your Highness, please.
Watch your steps after you go inside.
Everything here is evidence.
Don't touch them.
Yes, I got it.
It seems to be just a kiln.
Are the tools for minting coins and making porcelains the same?
It requires a furnace to melt the metal.
A kiln can't be used as a furnace.
In such a small place, people can't move at all
if they put a furnace here.
Besides, you can see what's here at a glance.
If they place the equipment for minting coins here,
it's easy to be spotted by the villagers when they come here.
Your Highness! It's empty here!
There is something wrong with this wall.
There are traces on the ground.
We should be able to move this wall.
It has opened.
Commandery Prince An is perceptive indeed.
There is something wrong with this kiln.
Jinli, please take some people and bring some torches here.
Let's go inside and take a look.
Okay.
Your Highness, are you okay?
I heard that it's a illness.
You will get sick when you go into a place without windows.
Are you...?
Don't worry. No matter what's inside,
I'll be by your side.
What's wrong, Jinyu?
Commandery Prince An. Miss Chu.
Did you find anything?
Your Highness, why do you look so ill?
It doesn't matter.
I'm just tired. I'll be fine after some rest.
Take a break if you are tired. We have plenty of time.
It's okay. Let's go.
Be careful, Your Highness.
Your Highness!
Your Highness.
Your Highness, look.
Give it to me.
Your Highness, this is the place where they minted coins.
There is a mint in the kiln.
Prefect Li.
Do you remember that Jing Yi asked a puzzling question yesterday?
Forgive me for being slow-witted.
You are saying...
He asked you why this group of bandits risked their lives
to mint coins for such little profit.
Yes, I remembered it.
You also said we would know it after we find the mint
and ask the supervisor.
Your Highness, these bandits are all gone.
I'm afraid we won't be able to catch anyone.
Then there will be no way of finding out.
Not necessarily.
The profit they made is not that little as Jing Yi estimated.
Jing Yi misestimated the profit because he calculated it
according to the cost in a normal situation.
But if it's a local official who is in charge of the minting of coins,
it would be a totally different situation.
Every county office has labor expenses.
If the official slightly changes the account book,
the labor cost of minting coins can be paid by the county office.
By the same logic, the copper and tin used to mint coins
can also be paid by the county office by changing the account book.
This way, the biggest costs
were paid by the county office with the public money.
The rest doesn't cost much.
It's such a profitable business.
This is...
Well, is there anything wrong with my analysis?
No, no.
I understand it all of a sudden and I'm enlightened
after hearing what you just said.
I just can't think of any official in Qianzhou who can be this bold.
This place is under the jurisdiction of Guanling County.
Could it be Magistrate Zheng Youde?
You forgot a little thing.
Guanling County is just a poor county.
They don't even have any money to hire more people.
Even if Zheng Youde wanted to do it, what excuses can he use
for such a large expenditure?
I'm slow-witted. I was in a hurry and I didn't think it through.
Please forgive me.
It's not that you didn't think it through.
Guanling County is a hidden place indeed.
But its only disadvantage is the inconvenience to get in and out
caused by its concealment.
In order to send the fake coins out of Guanling County as soon as possible,
five years ago, you allocated some money to build a bridge in Guanling County.
It was to provide convenience for the criminals,
but now everyone is praising it as a good deed.
That's ironic.
Well... Your Highness, please don't wrong me.
I built the bridge for the good of the people here.
There is no other intention.
Your Highness, take a look.
The wounds on Prefect Li's hands
fit these tools perfectly in terms of shape and size.
It's you who made the coin molds!
Timing and subtitles brought to you by The Imperial Coroners @ Viki.com
♫  Nothing can stop me  ♫
♫  From missing you all the time  ♫
♫  The moonlight appears, cold in the late night,
as the world changes  ♫
♫  Only with you by my side can I embrace my yearning for you  ♫
♫  When I close my eyes I meet you once again  ♫
♫  I'll gently brush your hair by your ear  ♫
♫  Life is long, with love and regrets in this world  ♫
♫  With you by my side, no matter how far I go,
we'll never be apart  ♫
♫  With your smile, in this moment, let me
cherish this lifetime  ♫
♫  Only for you, I have to worry about the end of this life  ♫
♫  I’m still young,  ♫
♫  With my love not yet realized for you, but I'm  ♫
♫  Willing to be here for you till the end  ♫
♫  You can rely on me in this lifetime  ♫
♫  Hope to spend this beautiful lifetime together  ♫