Timing and subtitles brought to you by The Imperial Coroners @ Viki.com
Lord Jing said that I still had a chance
unless His Highness expelled me.
He asked me to learn how to please His Highness.
I've made up my mind what to do.
But His Highness keeps asking about Uncle Witch Doctor.
Considering he's so smart,
if I keep working for him,'
I'm afraid I can no longer keep the secret.
[Two Merits Hall]
Take back your handkerchief.
How many identical handkerchiefs do you have?
Where are you going?
I'm going to the Palace.
[The Imperial Coroner]
[Episode 8]
No way. I can no longer stay here.
Where's my pass?
Qin Luan, that old fool!
How reckless he's getting!
He even dared to bully you like that!  I'm going to avenge you.
Ridiculous!
I... I'm being ridiculous under an order.
[To Leng Yue]
Knowing I would arrive today,
Auntie asked someone to wait for me at the city gate with the letter.
[Princess Xiping]
She insisted that I should go to the tea gathering in the Palace.
I didn't mean to go. But now, I do.
Stop.
Your Highness! Your Highness!
Let her in.
- Your Highness.
- What happened?
My pass is missing.
Your pass is missing?
- When did you find it missing?
- Just now.
When I was packing my bag, I found it missing.
Why did suddenly pack your bag?
I...
I want to go home.
I didn't pass the selection exam.
And I've lost my tools.
I can do nothing here if I stay.
I want to go home, make new tools,
and practice harder before I come back again.
You failed the exam?
Your Highness, you're quite partial.
You even think highly of a useless man like Jing Yi.
She looks sincere. She must be a useful talent.
She won't be worst than Jing Yi.
Wait for me out there.
Everything will be fine, okay?
I'm going out for some business.
Go back to your room and look for your pass carefully.
If you still can't find it, when Wu Jiang comes back,
tell him how you found it missing and he will help you.
Silly girl. Don't try to find the Handsome Judge.
You can't find him in this world.
If you want to say something,
but no one listens to you,
look at the pendant and talk to it.
Pretend I am there listening to you.
I'll keep it carefully.
I believe
that you'll be the best coroner.
Also, you must remember.
- Do not—
- I remember. I remember.
I won't tell anyone about you.
I'll practice my skills carefully
and become the best coroner.
I will find the Handsome Judge.
Uncle Witch Doctor, I can no longer stay here.
But I can't leave without the pass.
Also, I don't want to leave.
Since I was born,
he's been the first man who allows me to perform an autopsy
and trusts me.
I want to work for him.
But he keeps asking about the pendant.
He even managed to portray you.
Uncle Witch Doctor, what do I do?
Should I keep doing what Lord Jing asked me to do?
I have something he's interested in.
Then why did he want General Wu to help me find my pass,
instead of asking me to stay?
Miss Chu.
General Wu.
Lian Qiao said you wanted to see me?
Yes. My pass is missing.
I can't find it at all.
His Highness asked me to tell you and said you would help me.
All right. I'll help with that.
But Miss Chu, shall we go to the Ten-Commandment Hall?
Ten-Commandment Hall?
Yes. His Highness wants you to do him a favor.
Do him a favor?
Is he going to let me stay?
[Fragrance Chamber]
Xiao Jinyu hasn't arrived yet?
Your Majesty, someone told me that Commandery Prince An had arrived.
Greetings, Your Highness.
General Zhou, are you waiting for someone?
There's some emergency in Shen Army
and I need to tell Eunuch Qin about it.
You mean a soldier in Shen Army was infected with pestilence
and died last night?
Such a small problem even disturbed you?
I'm ashamed of that.
How can pestilence be a small problem?
Shen Army is part of Imperial Armies.
There's pestilence in Shen Army.
If anything goes wrong and it spreads into the Palace,
can you take responsibility for it?
You're right, Your Highness.
I know this is very serious.
Last night, when it happened, I had the soldier taken out of town,
burned and buried deep, exactly according to military rules.
It's very efficient of you.
No wonder Eunuch Qin thinks highly of you.
I'm simply doing my duty.
Your Highness.
Your Highness, you said you were busy with work.
But now you're free enough to ask about a sick soldier.
You've done your work so quickly.
I really admire that.
But Your Highness,
Shen Army isn't under your charge.
Take care, Your Highness.
Have you handled the problem?
Don't worry. The soldier was burned.
He wasn't burned to ash yet,
but no good skin remained.
Greetings, Your Highness.
I'm late. Please punish me.
Your Majesty, the tea's ready.
Please have a taste.
It's good.
Your Majesty, I've got something to say.
Your Majesty, Minister Feng loved tea before he died.
He was suddenly killed.
I've worked with him for years.
I can't help thinking of him. But look at Commandery Prince An.
He kept disturbing Minister Feng's home with a female coroner.
Last night, he even burned the mourning hall for Minister Feng
and nearly burned his body.
How can he take charge of Three Judicial Chief Ministries like that?
Please perceive it, Your Majesty.
Your Majesty, I was there last night.
Commandery Prince An went there to apologize, under your command.
There was simply a coincidence.
There can't be such a coincidence.
Everybody in Feng Manor witnessed that.
But His Highness nearly died in the fire, too.
Tell him to come over.
Please, Your Highness.
Your Majesty.
What happened last night?
Last night, someone set it on fire.
I'm still checking on the case.
But if the female coroner I took to the Feng Manor for an apology
hadn't risked her life to protect Feng Jie's corpse,
many truths would have been ruined.
Minister Han devotes himself to work and he watches out for danger
as a judge should do at any time.
Also, he doesn't follow me like sheep.
It's the luck of our nation.
It's also our luck when you give sympathetic consideration.
I've got something to say, too.
Someone was infected with pestilence?
How did you know, Miss Chu?
These are used for protection when contacting pestilence victims.
When I was little, there was pestilence in my hometown.
The magistrate sent men to teach us.
Oh, I remember.
When Manager Xu ran away yesterday, he was taken out in a carriage
where there was a dead man who died of pestilence.
You're right.
It was the burned corpse that was taken out of town in the carriage.
In Chang'an, no news has come about pestilence.
So, His Highness wants you to figure out
if this man died of pestilence.
But there're many other coroners in Chang'an.
Why does His Highness want me?
His Highness said if you failed to figure out how this man died,
no other coroners in Chang'an would manage to do that.
He really said that?
He trusts my skills so much?
He also said that, even if the corpse was burned,
it didn't mean there is no danger.
If you have any concerns, you can refuse to inspect it.
No. I have no concern at all. I'll inspect it.
Qin Luan.
Here.
Commandery Prince An told me that
a soldier in Shen Army was infected with pestilence, right?
For your information, Your Majesty, that's true.
I was just told, too.
Don't worry, Your Majesty.
The infected corpse was taken out of town immediately,
burned and buried deep.
It's such an important thing.
You simply burned the corpse?
Shen Army guards the Palace.
If you fail to figure out the real problem
and let the pestilence spread to the Palace, different ministries,
or even different parts of the capital,
can you take responsibility for it?
Don't get angry, Your Majesty.
I'll ask them to—
Don't bother.
I just asked the Imperial Insignia Guard
to cooperate with the Imperial Medical Service
and seal off the battalion of Shen Army.
Those who took the corpse out of town last night should all be isolated.
More decisions will be made accordingly in ten days.
I neglected my duty. Please punish me, Your Majesty.
All right.
Go to the battalion and keep an eye on epidemic prevention.
This way, Miss Chu.
Where are we?
His Highness said,
if you must take some tools for the autopsy,
you can choose some from these.
These are all made of steel.
By the way, General Wu, I want to ask.
Can I complete an autopsy this time?
His Highness said,
coroners in Chang'an are not allowed to complete an autopsy without Permit of Autopsy,
or coroners will be sentenced.
This is the Permit of Autopsy with an official seal.
His Highness said that you can do whatever you want.
Moreover, His Highness asked you to fill in the autopsy sheet by yourself.
After you finish it,
I'll send the autopsy sheet to His Highness immediately.
Okay. General Wu, rest assured.
Take your time then.
I'm sorry to offend you at the Thought Chamber today.
Please forgive me.
This case is weird.
Please protect yourself carefully when investigating.
Be safe.
[Permit of Autopsy]
Xiao Jinyu.
Yes.
You did well in protecting Feng Jie's corpse,
but that's your responsibility.
You disturbed Feng Manor with a coroner. It's your fault.
Look, I heard you're good at making tea.
You can show it here.
If you're really good at it, I won't punish you.
Yes.
Please allow me to make some preparations.
Please have a look.
I heard Commandery Prince An is good at painting.
Unexpectedly, he can make paintings with tea,
showing the scenery of the four seasons in these small cups.
How amazing!
Thanks to your Majesty, I can widen my horizon today.
Some talented persons in the palace can make paintings with tea, too.
But compared to yours, it's nothing at all.
Xiao Jinyu, what's in the box?
What's it for?
To be frank, Your Majesty, it's not designed to make tea,
but it's helpful to stir the tea and water, and produce froth.
So I use it for the moment.
What's it designed for?
- Collect evidence.
- Collect evidence?
When investigating lawsuits,
I had to analyze dirty water to get clues sometimes.
- Your Highness.
- If I allow it to be precipitated by itself,
it will cost a long time.
I may lose the opportunity to catch the suspects.
I found that if I rotate and vibrate the dirty water
before the precipitation, I will need a much shorter time.
- Therefore—
- Enough! Stop it!
I lost my appetite now.
Ridiculous.
Jinbao, throw it away.
His Majesty lost his appetite.
Wait!
Leng Yue?
My greetings, Your Majesty.
It's been a long time.
You've grown up.
Princess Xiping told me you'd come here today,
I've arranged a seat for you.
Stand up.
Thank you.
Your Majesty, I heard you lost your appetite just now,
I want to give it back for you.
You can make tea, too?
A piece of cake.
And I don't need these things.
I just want a piece of tea block, a kettle of boiling water,
a big bowl, and a sword.
If you're happy with it, can I ask for something?
Okay.
Thank you.
General Wu.
General Wu, don't worry.
This person didn't die of plague.
Didn't he die of plague?
- Your Highness.
- What's the result?
Miss Chu has ascertained the death cause of the corpse.
I forgive you.
Since you believe I'm a good coroner, I won't leave.
The dead, male, about 30 years old.
[Transposition of viscera]
Died two days ago.
Whole body burned.
Spine curled up.
Split tibia in the left leg.
[Split tibia]
The third rib on the right side is broken,
[Viscera injured]
stabs in the lungs.
[Died of losing blood]
Mouth, nose and auditory meatus have residual blood.
rib was broken by an external force
[Nose, soot and charcoal ash, blood]
and stabbed in the lungs.
He died of blood lost, not plague.
She's really a good coroner.
Your Highness, on my way here,
I saw Imperial Medical Service and Imperial Insignia Guard
encircle the camp of Shen Army with a lot of people.
Should I send Miss Chu's investigation results to Imperial Medical Service?
Don't bother.
It's not bad for them to clear Shen Army.
And I need them to do this to help me lock them up for some days.
By the way, Your Highness, there's another thing.
Miss Chu asked about the pass.
What should I say?
Give it to her.
Give it to her?
Tell her it was found at the inn where she was staying before.
Your Highness, what if she leaves Three Judicial Chief Ministries?
[…I won't leave.]
She won't.
Good! Excellent!
You deserve your identity from a General Family.
Thank you.
What about my reward?
Reward! Tell me.
What do you want?
Your Majesty, I want Sun Mingde to lead a horse
and show me around Daming Palace.
Okay. I agree.
Thank you.
Sir. I don't feel well.
I have a rest here. I'll go back now.
Thank you for your help in the matters
involving Feng Manor last night.
Thank you very much.
- This…
- Here are only you and me. Tell me the truth.
Did you complete the autopsy last night when you went to Feng Manor?
To be honest, sir, I did take a coroner there.
These are the tools left behind by the coroner.
You… You have the right to investigate all cases.
But Feng Jie's case, His Majesty had an order before.
How dare you do this!
Thank you, sir.
I know I'm wrong.
I have another thing to tell you.
I'll leave the capital soon for Qianzhou in the southwest.
Qianzhou? What will you do?
Is it General Xiao…
My eldest brother is fine.
I want to find my father's whereabouts.
Did His Majesty agree?
His Majesty will.
You want to find your father in southwest?
Yes.
It's been years.
My mother never mentioned it to me.
I didn't know that what was buried
in my father's tomb was just a set of
clothes, until the day before yesterday.
The rebels tried to kill my father in the southwest at that time.
His whereabouts are a mystery.
It's affirmed my father was dead only after Qin Luan and his people
took back my father's things.
I believe it's still suspicious.
Why?
When I was investigating a murder case in the capital last night,
I found out that someone has been searching for news about my father.
It seems they've always been looking for my father for years.
Some people are looking for Xiao Heng?
- Who are they?
- I haven't figured it out.
Anyway, they are secretive.
I don't think they are of goodwill.
I want to find out my father before they do
and figure out the details.
Managing criminal cases it's my business,
as well as my duty as a son.
You have to go to a far place to look for a missing person.
Any degree of certainty?
Even if there're only very few clues about my father,
I'd like to put all my effort into trying.
It's hard for you to be so loyal and filial.
In this case, I'd help you.
You are allowed to check it in the southwest.
Thank you, Your Majesty.
I have another thing to report.
Eunuch Sun, thank you for helping me to stay.
Hey.
You are welcome.
Sun Mingde.
Yes.
Your Majesty!
Go get the brocade cloak offered by Shengzhou
and give it to Commandery Prince An.
Yes, Your Majesty.
It's cold in the morning and evening in the mountainous southwest.
Pay more attention to your health.
Thank you, Your Majesty.
You may raise.
What else? Just go on.
Your Majesty, I've made it clear that Feng Jie, Minister of War,
Liu Yue, Director of the Ministry of Revenue, whose accidental death was reported last month,
Representative Lu Chuansheng of Capital Liaison Office in Qianzhou,
were all killed by killers supported by Rugui Tavern.
What?
The cases are very complicated.
I've reported this all in the memorial.
[Memorial]
Please take a look.
Why did the killers kill the three?
- Not just three of them.
- Who else?
At the end of last year, I found officials died of an accident
during the year were nearly 30%
more than that of the years before.
I didn't think it was normal.
Last night, I checked the files again
when I found out the cause of Feng Jie's death, I figured out
those killers created many of the accidental death cases.
Who appointed them?
Why did they kill the courtiers?
Not only courtiers.
I checked all accidental death cases
in the capital for recent ten years.
I found not only officials,
but also the servants and singers
have been killed by them.
These people don't have any relation.
That's not all.
Rugui Tavern also has an underground backroom.
A lot of surveillance records are there.
Almost the whole Chang'an has been involved in it.
What does that mean?
Rugui Tavern is doing business, an inn in front
but killing behind.
Also information dealing.
Xu Rugui is just a businessman.
He has no roots in Chang'an.
But he can do such business in the capital for over ten years
without being found.
There must be someone backing him.
What I'm more worried about is the payer for killing
Liu Yue, Lu Chuansheng and Feng Jie.
Go on!
Please take a look, Your Majesty.
It's produced in Qianzhou. What's wrong?
Your Majesty, this is official.
This is counterfeit.
Counterfeit?
The day before yesterday, I got several counterfeit cooper coins
from a Qianzhou business team by accident in the West Market.
So I asked people to pay attention.
[Kaiyuan Coin]
We found nearly 20% of the currency circulated
[2-Zhu in weight, red, mixed with copper and tin]
in the market is counterfeit.
[2.4-Zhu in weight, in copper]
When I did the exam for coroners,
[Fake Real]
I met a coroner from Qianzhou.
80% of her money was counterfeit.
You are right.
It's well duplicated.
But the fineness is a bit different.
The counterfeit can be mixed in.
How can that be?
There must be someone who is making counterfeit copper coins.
Liu Yue was the Director of the Ministry of Revenue.
One of his duties is making coins.
Yes.
I guess this is the reason for Liu Yue's death.
Lu Chuansheng, Capital Liaison Representative of Qianzhou,
was responsible for the liaison of affairs between Qianzhou and Capital.
If there is illicit coin casting in Qianzhou,
he should be the one to report it.
As well as Feng Jie.
He went to the southwest to inspect military affairs
and was assassinated on the night he returned to the Capital.
I have read his inspection minutes,
but I didn't find anything abnormal.
But whether he really didn't find anything abnormal,
we'll never know.
Your Majesty, army, money, and news…
All these three anomalies are from the Southwest.
I speculate that the buyer's intentions are malicious
and may endanger the stability of the Southwest.
How dare them!
Your Majesty, when I searched Rugui Tavern last night,
Xu Rugui had escaped
and destroyed a large number of surveillance records.
In the remaining records, the one about my father was left.
It seems that someone wants me to investigate this matter.
Since all the clues point to the Southwest,
I plan to play along to find my father's whereabouts
and secretly investigate the anomalies of the Southwest
to draw the buyer and seller out.
In order not to alert the enemy,
Your Majesty, please withhold the information of this case from the public.
After I find out the truth and capture the buyer and seller,
you can close the case.
Okay.
I grant you the prerogative to investigate this case.
to investigate this case.
Thank you, Your Majesty.
Oh, right.
About Yan Ming's case, after the murderer committed suicide, there is no follow-up.
Is it also related to the Southwest?
I'm still investigating it.
I'll entrust you with the safety
of the people in the Southwest.
This trip is very dangerous.
Do you need me to send more guards to protect you?
Your Majesty, my trip to the Southwest this time
is in the name of finding my father's whereabouts.
If there are many people accompanying me,
I am afraid that I will cause suspicion and get into trouble instead.
Your Majesty, please allow one person to go to the Southwest with me.
- Who is that?
- Vice Minister of the Court of Judicial Review, Jing Yi.
Let me ask you.
Why did Commandery Prince An
want to look for his father?
It's because of that coroner.
I've investigated her.
She is not involved in any parties in Chang'an.
In the future, you should be more careful with her.
You must also go to the Southwest with Commandery Prince An.
Why should I go there?
I have things to do in Chang'an.
To do what?
Are you still thinking about Leng Yue?
Let me tell you.
If Commandery Prince An asks His Majesty for you,
then you have to go.
Father, do you think this girl has something to do with Prince Consort?
Why do you say so?
In addition to the jade pendant of Prince Consort and Princess Xiping,
she also has several volumes of legends.
According to His Highness, the cases in the legends
are adapted from the previous cases handled by the Prince Consort.
Apart from His Highness and Prince Consort,
you're the one who's most familiar with these.
Legends?
Yes. There is a Handsome Judge in it.
Handsome Judge?
Brother Jing, please speak your mind.
Prince Consort, you've handled several big cases in a month.
I heard someone call you Judge behind your back.
They calling me Judge means that I'm just doing the right job.
Only when someone calls me Impartial Judge
it mean I'm doing a great job.
Impartial Judge? No way.
Why is that?
Take a look at yourself.
You're not an Impartial Judge,
but a Handsome Judge.
Otherwise, Princess Xiping may not be happy.
Brother Jing, you're making fun of me.
So you gave him that nick name.
I was just joking.
When I said this, there was no one else but the two of us.
If anyone knew about this,
it would be Prince Consort himself.
Could it be…
Could it be that Prince Consort is in Qianzhou
and still alive?
Timing and subtitles brought to you by The Imperial Coroners @ Viki.com
♫  Nothing can stop me  ♫
♫  From missing you all the time  ♫
♫  The moonlight appears, cold in the late night,
as the world changes  ♫
♫  Only with you by my side can I embrace my yearning for you  ♫
♫  When I close my eyes I meet you once again  ♫
♫  I'll gently brush your hair by your ear  ♫
♫  Life is long, with love and regrets in this world  ♫
♫  With you by my side, no matter how far I go,
we'll never be apart  ♫
♫  With your smile, in this moment, let me
cherish this lifetime  ♫
♫  Only for you, I have to worry about the end of this life  ♫
♫  I’m still young, with my love not yet realized for you, but I'm
willing to be here for you till the end  ♫
♫  You can rely on me in this lifetime  ♫
♫  Hope to spend this beautiful lifetime together  ♫