I'm Chu Chu.
I came to Chang'an to become a coroner
who can work for the Handsome Judge, Chief of Six Gates.
Kind Lord Jing helped me to take part in the Coroner Qualification Test.
[Court of Judicial Review]
But I mistook Commandery Prince An
[Two Merits Hall]
as the testing body who takes care of all criminal cases.
[Three Judicial Chief Ministries]
His Highness is smart and kind.
I think he's the Handsome Judge that I'm looking for.
But... he looks very curious about my pendant.
Greetings, Your Highness and Vice Minister Jing.
You may rise.
Thank you, Your Highness.
Miss, you must be the coroner Commandery Prince An picked
in today's selection test.
Congratulations.
No. No. The result hasn't come out yet. I just...
General Zhou, did His Majesty send you here for any mission?
Here's the thing.
When I was patrolling in the Palace,
[Three Judicial Chief Ministries]
I picked up a bunch of keys.
I guess some official lost them when he left the Palace.
I'm then asking in all departments.
General Zhou, where did you find the keys?
In the corridor outside Xuanzheng Hall.
Don't bother, then.
Even if you visit all departments in Chang'an,
no one will claim them.
What do you mean, Vice Minister Jing?
In the way you're looking for the owner,
soon all officials will know that someone lost a bunch of keys.
It's no problem if they're normal keys.
If they're keys to archives, storerooms, or prison,
the owner will be in big trouble.
If I lost the keys, I would never admit that.
You're right.
Thank you for your instruction.
I'll take my leave then.
[Three Judicial Chief Ministries]
Qin Luan's Imperial Armies go where they heard of anything,
just like dogs.
Don't they fear being battered?
Your Highness, may I
have my pendant back?
Since it matters so much to you, keep it carefully.
Don't leave it to others again.
I understand.
Heng, are you still alive?
[Princess Xiping, Emperor Wenzong's daughter]
Do you know I'm still waiting for you?
[The Imperial Coroner]
[Episode 2]
Come and have a look!
He's perspicacious.
He punishes evil-doers.
He really looks like the Handsome Judge.
Are you still inspecting me?
By the way, it's the ointment to remove blood clots.
My grandfather made it.
It's very effective. Apply it.
Thank you. Don't bother.
I know you think coroners bring bad luck.
But this is new.
I haven't used it before. It's not dirty.
What? Regret so soon?
No, no.
You don't think what I touched is filthy?
You also touched me, didn't you?
Angelica and peony for improving blood circulation.
Ligusticum and cattail for removing blood clots.
Boswellia for pain relief and peach kernel for dissolving lumps.
They work for my symptoms.
You can even recognize it?
I know a little.
Is there anything you don't know?
Who gave you the pendant you left in the inn?
Why did he ask about my pendant?
I can't tell anyone.
You can't tell me
or you don't want to tell me?
Come and have a look!
Baked cake.
Hot baked cake!
Baked cake!
Stop.
Jing Yi, go buy a piece of baked cake.
Don't bother. I... I'm not hungry. Don't buy it.
Hot baked cake.
I'm hungry.
Xiao Jinyu is heading for Yan's Manor?
Yes.
Besides Jing Yi,
he also took a female coroner who took part in the exam.
Female coroner?
A girl even wants to be a coroner?
I asked about her.
When she first came to the capital, she met Jing Yi privately.
She also took part in the exam, for Jing Yi's sake.
A female coroner?
Make an issue of female... Sounds like what the Jing Family do.
Not only Jing Yi works for Xiao Jinyu, but also a female coroner.
Jing Zhi thinks so highly of Xiao Jinyu.
Jing Yi is smart, but he's a playboy who enjoys wealth and honor.
In case of corpses, he can't help feeling terrified.
It makes sense when Jing Zhi plants a female coroner
to spy on Xiao Jinyu.
I failed to figure out who she is.
But I find something suspicious.
What is it?
When I saw Xiao Jinyu today, he was holding a stone pendant.
As soon as he saw me, he hid it right away.
When he stared at the pendant,
I felt that he cared a lot about it.
The female coroner said it was her pendant.
Stone pendant?
What does it look like?
It's flat, with carved patterns.
Looks like one of two halves.
- It has...
- Blue Tassel?
Eunuch Qin, you know that?
Did you see it clearly?
I'm sure I did.
Looks like the blue tassel isn't from any ordinary family.
I looked at it a few more times and I was quite impressed.
Why does a female coroner have the love token
of Princess Xiping and Xiao Heng?
Don't worry. I'll take her back.
Go. Go ahead.
Is Xiao Heng...?
I must send someone to get some intel from Princess Xiping.
According to the first witness,
when he arrived here, he found the dead man.
Did the witness move anything in this place?
He claimed he didn't.
Come on, Your Highness. What do you mean "claim"?
I didn't!
Lord Jing, you found the dead man?
Yes.
Lord Jing, how did you find him?
I heard the scream.
That night, Yan Ming held a banquet in the foreyard,
to show off his valuable calligraphy.
Unexpectedly, he didn't come back after a long while.
Later, there was a scream coming from the study.
Then came the scream of a dancing girl. I rushed here immediately.
As soon as the dancing girl pushed the door open,
she saw what happened in the study
and slumped on the ground out of fear.
Before she recovered from the shock, Jing Yi arrived.
So, he was the first to get into the study and checked on Yan Ming.
Didn't the dancing girl or Lord Jing see the murderer?
Not to mention the murderer, there wasn't even a suspect.
Look here, there's a big spot of blood.
There must have been blood on the murderer.
I asked to seal the manor for a thorough search immediately.
No one was missing. No extra men were here, either.
But we found no one who had blood on him.
Don't you think it's strange?
The bloodstain looks smooth.
I think Yan Ming took the box out and put it here.
When he was dead, the calligraphy wasn't in the box.
So did he... did he take it out and show it to the murderer?
Where's the calligraphy now?
Now that Yan Ming showed it to the murderer and it's missing now,
it means the murderer wanted the calligraphy, killed Yan Ming
and ran away with it?
I don't think the murderer wanted the calligraphy.
How do you know he hid it in this place?
When something is hidden among similar things,
people can't easily see it.
Now that the murderer didn't want the calligraphy,
the stain on it didn't matter. Why did he hide it?
If he hadn't hidden it,
would you think he was a thief who killed Yan Ming
so as to get the calligraphy?
I heard that the calligraphy was missing after Yan Ming was killed.
Did Commandery Prince An find any clue?
He hasn't told me about it.
Yan Ming was killed because of the calligraphy.
It's not appropriate to say this,
but what a pity when the calligraphy is missing!
In my humble opinion, Yan Ming may not be killed
because of the calligraphy.
Then why was he killed?
If the murderer only wanted to steal the calligraphy,
he didn't have to kill Yan Ming.
It makes sense.
You checked the crime scene.
What else did you see from the corpse?
You can tell me now, can't you?
- I want a try.
- How?
- Could you pretend to be the murderer?
- Just show me how you think the murderer killed Yan Ming.
I'll show you how I think Yan Ming died.
All right.
What's in your hand?
The weapon. It's a meter long and as thick as wheat straw. Anything wrong?
Someone's dead!
Help!
What are you doing?
I'm pretending to be Yan Ming.
I'm showing you the calligraphy, but you hold a weapon.
Of course, I would yell for help!
You're right.
I wasn't thinking in the murderer's position.
Let's try again.
Look at this.
This isn't right.
It doesn't make sense.
There's really a hole.
That's how he protected himself from Yan Ming's blood.
In this way, people without the bloodstain are also suspectable.
You said something's not right. What's that?
I mean there's no trace of bumping on Yan Ming's back.
He shouldn't have fallen down like this.
But if you take a look at the bloodstain, he did.
Then the murderer held him before he bumped into the desk,
like you just did.
The murderer killed him.
Would he even worry if he would be wounded?
Then why did you hold me?
You're the murderer.
Miss Chu, if you wanted to be serious,
you didn't scream like Yan Ming did.
I don't know what you heard.
But Yan Ming didn't scream before he died.
Why?
Judged from the blood on the ground,
the upper part of his heart was stabbed.
It's the connection part between the heart and the blood vessels.
When it was stabbed immediately, Yan Ming would be out of breath
because of the huge blood loss.
He wouldn't be able to scream at all.
Jing Yi, are you sure you heard Yan Ming's scream?
The murderer screamed?
If so, the murderer would stop Yan Ming from bumping into the desk.
Why?
In case he made a noise and others would notice.
Would you like to try again with me?
Yes.
To fool others, the murderer faked the crime scene.
Someone's dead!
What are you doing?
You're the murderer and Yan Ming, aren't you?
There should be a dancing girl. I would pretend to be her.
It was what happened that night.
Now that you pretend to be the dancing girl,
don't you realize something wrong with her?
What's wrong with her?
It took her a while to find Yan Ming after she came.
There was a short interval between the two screams.
When the murderer screamed,
the dancing girl must have been in the yard.
No matter how fast the murderer left, she must have seen him.
But why did she stay and do so much, instead of leaving immediately?
That's right.
[Jiangshan Hall]
Your Majesty, I wonder
if I should say something about Yan Ming's case.
Go ahead.
Yan Ming is a vice six-rank official,
but he's at least a minister.
His case has been suspended for half a month.
After you gave a time limit,
Commandery Prince An used Yan Ming's corpse for the Coroner Test,
instead of solving the case quickly.
He's absolutely disrespecting you.
He's so careless and arrogant!
No wonder other officials impeach him.
I shouldn't have spoilt him.
If he doesn't find out the murderer before sunset,
I'll dismiss him from the office!
Did you search the dancing girl's body immediately?
I did.
But that wasn't very necessary.
She wore such a thin dancing dress.
How could she hide a one-meter-long weapon?
So, she left the weapon here.
It's the weapon.
He can even find this?
I think the dancing girl learned from some ventriloquists in the Dancing Service.
It's hard to imitate a man's voice,
but it wasn't very hard to scream only.
She didn't hold the weapon or had the blood on her.
She could have left directly.
Why did she scream twice?
According to her confession,
she wanted to steal something in the yard on her way to the latrine.
As checked, she greeted other dancing girls who came with her
before she left.
She also met a maid and asked the way.
But she couldn't be vindicated with such simple evidence.
She couldn't assure her safety unless she made herself the witness.
A girl tricked me?
Wait. What did she steal?
Go catch her in the Dancing Service and ask her.
She must have run away after she stole the thing.
You'd better issue a warrant.
What if she's still there?
Why did Lord Jing leave through the window?
That's his bad habit.
You're awesome, Your Highness.
You're even smarter than the Handsome Judge.
Your Highness, may I still work for you?
You must answer all my questions, then.
All right.
Tell me about your pendant.
Pendant?
Are you... Are you really not the Handsome Judge?
I'm not.
What does he have to do with the pendant?
I can't tell you unless you're the Handsome Judge.
Yan Ming's case isn't closed yet.
I need you to give evidence in court.
You can't leave Chang'an before that.
And you must come whenever you're needed.
Your Highness.
Miss Chu, is this yours?
I don't even know where I lost it.
Where did you find it?
You silly girl, you don't even know your package was stolen.
Stolen? Who stole it?
Just now.
The waiter who asked for the bill.
But he doesn't look like a thief.
Didn't you realize your package smelled like that waiter?
What smell?
The smell of honey locusts and atractylodes that coroners have.
He's a waiter in an inn.
He doesn't use that.
You keep holding the package in your arms.
It must be very important to you.
When you checked in, you wouldn't give it to the waiter.
So, it's very likely that he searched your package secretly.
You really know everything.
Wait.
This isn't my purse.
No. I mean this is my purse.
But the coins are not.
They're yours, too.
It's your pay.
Keep them carefully.
So many coins for such a short time?
Isn't it great to work for you...?
What?
Your Highness, please give these coins back to Lord Jing.
All right.
Send some men to follow her.
Check where she goes
and who she meets.
Yes.
Also, exchange her own coins.
Amazing whip, Your Grace!
What are you scared of?
You don't deserve to be killed by my whip.
I don't. I don't!
What are you coming for?
For your information, Your Grace,
these are grapes from the Western Regions.
My master asked me to bring them...
Get out!
Princess, my master truly cares for you.
Go, go, go.
Go back and tell Qin Luan.
Don't think I don't know he always complains to His Majesty.
How dared he slander Commandery Prince An!
What does he think he is?
Get out with your grapes!
Yes. Yes, I will.
Get out!
Let's go. Go.
Be quick!
Leave us. What happened?
Didn't I ask you to get some intel from Princess Xiping?
Look what a mess you're in!
I got nothing, Master.
Princess Xiping has such a big temper.
Before I finished, she lashed at me!
Master, it doesn't matter when I'm aggrieved.
But Master, I work for you.
When she lashed my hips, she was exactly slapping your face!
What did you say?
Don't get angry, Master. I don't mean that.
You're useless.
Master, you asked me to ask about the female coroner.
Do you suspect she has something to do with Prince Consort Xiao Heng?
What kind of special connection do they have?
Does she have something to do with Xiao Heng
or does someone else want Xiao Jinyu to think so?
Anyway, someone must have seen
Xiao Heng and known where he is.
As long as we know who the female coroner is,
all problems will be solved.
Master, you care about the pendant.
Does it have a special meaning?
Princess, it takes trouble to blend.
[Princess Xiping Manor]
Have some rest.
When did I ever do such a thing?
If my husband comes back someday,
he'll laugh at me when he sees me.
Princess.
You all want me to believe that
he's dead.
But in his grave, there's nothing but a set of clothes.
I won't believe he's dead
until I see his body.
Your Highness, I also wish him to come back.
But it's been so many years.
If he were still alive, why didn't he come to see you,
considering your deep love?
Stop. I don't want to listen.
Don't let my children
know about the cenotaph.
(T/N: cenopath - empty tomb)
Yes ma'am.
Especially Jinyu.
If he knows, he'll look for his father, regardless of anything.
We mustn't tell my children about it.
He's so handsome and so kind.
He solves cases,
and wants to hire a female coroner.
- The Handsome Judge is perspicacious and kind.
- Perspicacious and kind.
He has an abhorrence of sin and a handsome appearance
so that people like him at first sight.
Isn't he the Handsome Judge?
Why doesn't he admit that?
[Notice]
How is that possible?
Sir. Sir?
What happened?
Something surprising.
Three Judicial Chief Ministries solved a criminal case
where a man was struck by lightning.
Look, here's a notice,
telling us how to protect ourselves from lightning.
Oh my God!
People can even die like that?
Yes. I saw that today.
You saw the lightning?
No.
I mean I helped to solve the case today.
I checked the dead man who was struck by lightning.
You're a coroner?
What bad luck!
Sir, are you all right?
Why didn't you watch your steps?
Miss, are you trying to hit me to death?
I'm sorry. Are you all right?
Let me check on you.
Don't touch me.
Sir, I think you're hurt.
Let me take you to see a doctor.
It's kind of you.
Don't bother, Miss.
I have medicine at home.
I live near here.
Let me get you back home, then.
All right. Thank you.
Come on. Stand up.
Be careful.
Your Highness.
Greetings, Your Highness.
She's the dancing girl?
Yes.
She ran quickly.
I've never been so tired before when chasing girls.
Take her away.
You're right again.
She was still practicing dancing in the Dancing Service.
I lose whenever we make a bet.
How boring!
Others give good things to beautiful girls.
But everything His Majesty awards me goes to you.
But you're wrong about one thing.
What is it?
You said she had stolen something from Yan Ming.
I searched her residence in the Dancing Service,
but didn't find anything.
What exactly did she steal from Yan Ming?
Besides, I personally searched her body that night.
Even her shoes were taken off.
What could she have stolen?
[Year of Jia, Yi, Bing, Ding, Wu, Ji, Geng, Xin...]
[Year of Renchen]
That's what she stole.
What?
A book volume.
Interrogate her and find it.
She really stole something?
All right, then. I won't decline a job to deal with a beautiful girl.
After interrogating her, ask the three grave robbers in prison.
According to them, they know very well
about all nearby grave robbers.
Grave robbers?
Why do you want to ask about them?
Isn't it Miss Chu's pendant?
I asked Wu Jiang to borrow it from my mother.
It's Princess Xiping's pendant? Then...
I haven't seen my father's pendant before.
But Chu Chu's pendant has the same pattern and the same tassel.
You think someone robbed Prince Consort's grave, got the pendant out,
and gave it to a female coroner so that you would be attracted
and more likely to hire her?
I asked the three grave robbers.
They said that no one had robbed my father's grave.
So, she didn't get this pendant from his grave.
Do you think she looks like a spy?
She came from the Southwest.
Prince Consort was also killed by rebels in the Southwest.
He might have lost it somewhere
and someone picked it up before giving it to her.
If this is the truth, why doesn't she admit?
Miss, it's right ahead.
Be careful.
What do you want?
Miss, go with me and I won't kill you.
I... I don't have money.
- I'm... I'm ugly, too. I even eat a lot.
- Shut up!
I work for Commandery Prince An!
Stop nagging and give me the pendant!
Pendant?
Give the pendant to me!
Give it to me!
Go!
Miss Chu, shall we go back to Three Judicial Chief Ministries?
All right.
This way, please.
Master, you're back?
Madam said you wouldn't have dinner if you didn't come back.
Has Jing Yi come back?
He can't come back very soon.
The Coroner Exam has already concluded.
Where has he gone?
According to his servant, he has gone to the Dancing Service
to catch the murderer who killed Yan Ming.
He found out the murderer?
Yes, he did.
Your Highness.
- Your Highness.
What happened? Stop crying.
Explain to me before you cry again.
Or...
Or keep crying for a minute.
Wu Jiang, what happened?
A gang of villains tried to kidnap Miss Chu.
Who are they?
I'm sorry, but I failed to catch anyone alive.
I only bring back a corpse.
Please punish me, Your Highness.
Don't... Don't punish him.
I didn't know they were bad men.
It was all my fault.
And they didn't kill those kidnappers.
A villain did.
All right. I won't punish them.
Are you hurt?
Then what are you crying for?
I feel like I had a nightmare.
I didn't wake up until I saw you.
Then I couldn't help crying.
What do you mean?
Your Highness, you asked General Wu to save me today, didn't you?
You helped me again.
You helped me several times today.
I…
Shall I... Let me kowtow to you.
There's no such rule with me.
Don't bother to be so courteous.
You don't be courteous, either.
Stop calling me Miss Chu.
Call me Chu Chu.
All right. Chu Chu.
You took back the corpse?
Yes.
- Go get us a coroner.
- Yes.
Don't bother. I'm a coroner.
Your Highness, you saved me.
I don't know how to pay you back.
All I can do is to perform an autopsy.
I can do it on anyone.
Let me do it for you.
I want an autopsy on the kidnapper.
Are you still willing to?
Yes.
His heart was stabbed by something sharp.
The cut is neat.
He died with one stab.
Thick calluses between his right thumb and the index finger.
He's sound in limbs.
Your Highness,
in her purse, there're 23 copper coins with Qian Printing.
I checked in the Minister of Revenue.
Nineteen of the coins are illegal coins.
They're the same as what the merchants from Qianzhou used you saw in the West Market.
You didn't say much, did you?
Don't worry. I know what I should say.
But I think there's something suspicious with Miss Chu.
She gave this to me today.
It's poisonous?
No.
If she poisoned it, she would be someone
I unintentionally offended during a case
and she simply came to take revenge.
That would be simple.
But this isn't poisonous
and she flatters me all the time.
She's more eager to be admitted than ordinary coroners.
If someone is behind her,
the pendant she holds must be the bait.
But she prefers to give up the chance of getting a job,
rather than tell me how she got the pendant.
With all due respect, Your Highness, Jing Yi found that girl.
Get to the point and then leave!
Your Highness, there's no restriction for tomorrow's selection exam,
is there?
I met a genius coroner today!
But she's a bit special
and she can't be admitted to Three Judicial Chief Ministries unless you help her.
I promise you, she'll impress you!
Then you come to annoy me first?
I'm serious, Your Highness.
No way.
You know what? If you miss out on her, you'll regret all your life!
I mean even if someone helps her, it can't be me.
Otherwise, when people know about it, there'll be trouble.
I'll help her, then.
I'll be the invigilator tomorrow.
Jing Yi grew up with me.
I know him very well.
He won't do this to me.
He doesn't need to do so, either.
Wu Jiang, have you heard about the Handsome Judge she just mentioned?
I haven't.
Now that you want to know about her pendant
and obviously, Miss Chu hasn't met the Handsome Judge before,
why don't you pretend to be him?
What if she wants a code
or to check about some birthmark or nevus?
You're right.
Even if I can pretend to be someone,
I need to know what this man looks like.
Yes. Yes. You're right, Your Highness.
We can't figure out if there's such a man in the martial world.
Send a letter to Leng Yue.
We should ask her what she knows most.
Yes.
By the way, who kidnapped her?
They're martial art masters.
But they deliberately concealed their martial arts.
I can't tell who they are.
As far as I see,
they came for Miss Chu on purpose.
Also, they don't want to kill her.
They don't want to kill her?
Yes. I heard them say...
Go with me and I won't kill you.
Timing and subtitles brought to you by The Imperial Coroners @ Viki.com
♫  Nothing can stop me  ♫
♫  From missing you all the time  ♫
♫  The moonlight appears, cold in the late night,
as the world changes  ♫
♫  Only with you by my side can I embrace my yearning for you  ♫
♫  When I close my eyes I meet you once again  ♫
♫  I'll gently brush your hair by your ear  ♫
♫  Life is long, with love and regrets in this world  ♫
♫  With you by my side, no matter how far I go,
we'll never be apart  ♫
♫  With your smile, in this moment, let me
cherish this lifetime  ♫
♫  Only for you, I have to worry about the end of this life  ♫
♫  I’m still young, with my love not yet realized for you, but I'm
willing to be here for you till the end  ♫
♫  You can rely on me in this lifetime  ♫
♫  Hope to spend this beautiful lifetime together  ♫