Timing and subtitles brought to you by The Imperial Coroners @ Viki.com
[The Imperial Coroner]
[Episode 1]
In the middle and late Tang Dynasty,
eunuchs set Emperor Xuanzong on the throne.
To please them,
Emperor Xuanzong let them take charge of Imperial Armies
to keep the Imperial Palace safe.
Meanwhile, he established Three Judicial Offices,
making Commandery Prince An, Xiao Jinyu, managing all criminal cases.
Three Judicial Chief Ministries values coroners.
The Coroner Qualification Exam is held in the capital every year,
without any restriction.
Talented people will be recruited.
During the exam season,
[Jinguang Gate]
coroners from different towns come to the capital.
Here you are.
See you. See you.
Come again!
Have a look at the hairpins.
Miss, have a look.
What's this?
It's food.
[Chu Chu]
I'm here in Chang'an, at last.
I will pass the exam for coroner.
Handsome Judge, wait for me.
Stop.
Show me your pass.
[Pass]
[Approved]
You can go.
Come and have a look.
Make way, please.
Come and have a look! Come and have a look!
[Jing Yi, Vice Minister of the Court of Judicial Review]
Elder, what happened to you?
The old man was hit.
Are you all right?
I'm terribly sorry.
Shall I take you to see a physician?
I don't want to waste your time.
It doesn't matter.
I'm old already.
The bruise looks strange.
But now that I'm hurt,
I can't work in the fields for months.
Why is it red, but not swollen?
I don't have money to see a physician.
If you don't mind,
could you give me a bit of money for medical expenses?
- All right.
- I should do that.
He certainly should.
The old man was hit so badly.
Wait!
Thank you.
Thank you. Here you go.
- Elder, here you go.
- Thank you.
Thank you.
You lied! The bruise is fake!
What's she talking about?
Lied?
You faked the bruise to deceive people.
It feels a bit hot, but it's not swollen at all.
Everyone, take a look, the bruise has one color.
The edge is clear, too.
Obviously, it's made of burned beech.
Also, he isn't an elder.
The white of his eyes is white.
Shouldn't the white of the eyes
be white? Or can it be black?
It can't be black. But it should be yellow.
When people get old, the white of the eye turns yellow.
The older they are, the more opaque it turns.
[No opaqueness. Over 35 years old.]
This is what we mean by the saying "old and faded".
But, look at him.
The white of his eyes hasn't gone opaque at all.
People can fake their appearance and even voice.
But they can't fake the white of the eye!
- Look at his eyes.
- Go to hell!
Fraud, don't run!
The Court of Judicial Review!
Fraud!
Take him back.
All right. Break it up here.
Don't block the traffic!
Go, go, go.
What a fraud!
He even gave the fraud some money.
Chu Chu?
Yes. You're an official from the Court of Judicial Review?
I'm Jing Yi, Vice Minister of the Court of Judicial Review.
Greetings, Lord Jing.
Stand up, please.
This isn't what ordinary people use.
Tell me. Why did you come to Chang'an?
I'm not a businesswoman. I got a lift with traveling merchants.
I'm a coroner. These are my working tools.
Go away! Go away!
Commandery Prince An?
Who dared to kicked me off!
[Wu Jiang, Chief Guardsman]
Wu Jiang, are you blind?
[Sun Mingde, Palace Eunuch]
Let me show you who's blind?
Say, you!
Greetings, Your Highness!
I'm so sorry.
I didn't know you were here, Your Highness.
According to the Great Tang laws, who rides a horse in downtown will be flogged 50 times.
Wu Jiang. Here.
Your Highness, I came out to inspect the accounts of the Shen Army
under the command of Eunuch Qin!
He's waiting for me to return...!
Why are you so troublesome?
- Lord Wu, Lord Wu, this is used for the toilet. The toilet!
- That's what I want.
He does strict enforcement with no fear for nobilities.
Legal and illegal people all obey him.
You said you came to Chang'an to be a coroner.
Do you mean to take the Coroner Qualification Exam?
Yes.
After I pass the exam, I'll be an official coroner.
Is there really no restriction for the Coroner Qualification Exam
and anyone can take part in it?
Yes.
Go to the exam with this,
[Court of Judicial Review]
and no one will stop you.
Really?
Thank you, Lord Jing.
[Court of Judicial Review]
[Three Judicial Chief Ministries]
[Two Merits Hall]
Excuse me,
didn't we have the exam yesterday?
Why is there an exam again today?
You came through the unofficial path, yet you don't know this?
It was the Qualification Exam yesterday.
Now it's the selection exam that Commandery Prince An holds.
Anyone who passes it can be admitted to the Three Judicial Chief Ministries
and work for Xiao Jinyu.
Small Goldfish?
(T/N: Literal translation for Xiao Jinyu)
The name sounds so odd.
What Small Goldfish? You don't even know Commandery Prince An?
Everyone in Three Judicial Chief Ministries fears him.
Small Goldfish?
[Two Merits Hall]
Commandery Prince An?
What Small Goldfish?
Don't talk nonsense.
When you hear your name, come in with me.
Chu Chu from Qianzhou.
That would be me!
I'm Chu Chu.
Hold it steadily. Watch your steps!
Be quick!
- Senior Jing, why don't we see your son today?
- Be smart.
Commandery Prince An summoned him.
[Jing Zhi, Grand Tutor]
His Majesty asked them to solve Assistant Wu's case within a time limit.
[Wang Jun, Minister of Revenue]
As estimated, it's the deadline.
But His Highness still works on the exam.
[Han Ji, Minister of Justice]
He's so calm.
How arrogant he is!
Watch your language, Lord Han.
His Highness is your superior.
You must not disrespect him.
What superior?
Since Great Tang Dynasty was founded,
the Ministry of Justice, the Court of Judicial Review and the Censorate
do their duties separately and solve criminal cases together.
I wonder what His Majesty thinks of it.
He established Three Judicial Chief Ministries for Commandery Prince An,
overseeing these three ministries.
Officials like us must take orders from such a young man.
He's too young and ignorant!
[Xiao Jinyu, Commandery Prince An]
I'm Chu Chu.
What's your family name?
Chu.
Chu Chu is my name.
It means a lovely girl.
It's simple and easy to be remembered.
Candidate Chu Chu,
there're two parts to the autopsy exam.
Give correct inspections and you'll pass it.
You'll have a high score for offering extra clues.
The final paper subjects to my record.
Do you understand?
Yes.
Then get started, please.
Wait. What are these?
These are autopsy tools I made.
[Yin-yang Pestle]
This is Yin-yang Pestle.
It's made of hardwood.
It has a cone shape, with one thick end and one thin end.
Two ends are wrapped with cotton.
The thin end is for checking the nose
while the thick end is for the throat.
Yin-yang Pestle?
He was burned and also soaked in water.
On his arms and neck are lightly bronzing dendritic patterns.
The finger bones of his right hand have pale osseous pearls.
The yellow grease on the dead body isn't all solidified grease.
It's...
The smell of sesame oil.
Man, over 35 years old.
Around 1.7 meters tall.
His corpse is burned and curled up.
He died nearly half a month ago.
What's the cause of his death?
The results are in his mouth and nose.
I knew it!
There's soot in his mouth and nose.
So, he was burned to death.
What a useful tool!
- What's the nature of this case?
- Nature?
Did he suicide or was he killed?
Neither.
He died of an accident.
Accident?
His skull shows signs of a fractured.
He was burned badly.
After cleaning his neck, I saw some dendritic patterns.
He was struck by lightning.
Also, he was soaked in water after he was burned.
So, he was struck by lightning before it rained.
It was midsummer half a month ago,
when there are the most thunderstorms.
How could he be burned like this if he was simply struck by lightning?
I think this is how he died.
He was, possibly, walking in the rain with a lantern in his hand.
By the way, he was carrying some sesame oil, too.
When the lightning hit the tree,
he was putting his right hand against the tree.
What are you doing?
Stand up and talk normally!
I'm imitating how he died.
Interesting.
Unluckily, he was struck by lightning and passed out immediately.
He got the tinder and flammable sesame oil.
The tinder burned the oil
and burned him to death when he was in a coma.
He was badly burned, but I could feel that
he had fractures in his ribs, arms, and shanks
more than once or twice.
He was wounded in such vulnerable parts when he risked his life in fights.
If he weren't so badly burned, we could have seen his scars.
No matter what a bad temper he had,
he wouldn't fight people desperately almost every day,
unless that was his job!
What else do you know?
That's all.
My Lord, may I check the next body?
Check her background carefully.
[Exam sheet, Chu Chu, female]
Senior Jing, you have no idea.
The two corpses Commandery Prince An used
for the exam are from unsolved cases in the capital.
One of the corpses is Assistant Yan Ming in the Palace Library.
Yan Ming?
Man, over 40 years old.
His corpse has bruises all over.
Some flesh of his mouth, nose, chest, and ribs became putrid.
He died half a month ago, I guess.
His heart was stabbed through by a sharp object.
It was the only wound and also the fatal wound.
The sharp object has a spike,
is as thin as wheat straw,
and as long as one meter.
What exactly is the object as thin as wheat straw,
as long as one meter, and with a spike?
I don't know.
You even managed to guess the shape.
Should you be able to guess what the object is?
I didn't guess.
I figured it out.
I was taught
that a coroner's duty is to honestly record what he sees,
smells, hears, and touches.
He knows when he sees, smells, hears, and touches.
Otherwise, he doesn't know.
Deducing or judging isn't a coroner's duty.
We can't talk without evidence.
How does she know that?
What?
What I mean is that I told you what I figured out.
I can only tell you what I know.
Without enough evidence, I can't talk nonsense.
I... I also know one thing.
I know he was murdered
and he knew the murderer.
Nonsense!
What?
You want to wake him up and ask him?
I don't mean that.
I mean he knows the murderer
and the murderer knows him, too.
All right.
Go to the Wing Hall for injury inspection.
Thank you, My Lord.
She even knows rules for coroners,
deodorizing the smell by vinegar steaming.
Your Highness.
- She's the female coroner Vice Minister Jing asked you to take care of?
- Yes.
Please understand, Your Highness.
If it weren't for his sake,
we wouldn't have let a girl do the autopsy.
You're not qualified to get in.
[Jiangshan Hall]
Please wait here.
Your Majesty, Academician Xue is here.
[Emperor Xuanzong]
Greetings, Your Majesty.
[Xue Rucheng, Academician]
Many officials have been complaining about Commandery Prince An.
You're his teacher. Aren't you going to defend him?
Your Majesty, you think highly of him
and let him take charge of Three Judicial Chief Ministries.
You have your own decision.
[Qin Luan, Acting Chief Eunuch]
I don't need to defend him.
I let him take charge of Three Judicial Chief Ministries,
on the account that he's as upright as his father Xiao Heng.
But being an official and solving cases are different things.
Qin Luan.
Yes.
I remember when Xiao Heng checked the rebel case in the Southwest,
you went there to help him, right?
Yes. You have a good memory, Your Majesty.
At the command of His Majesty,
Military Commissioner Chen Ying of Jiannan and Prince Consort Xiao Heng rebelled.
They'll be executed right here!
Prince Consort!
Chen Ying!
Prince Consort, go!
You'll have to vindicate our soldiers!
Unfortunately, I was too weak to live up to Emperor Wenzong's trust.
I failed to bring him back alive.
I'm guilty, Your Majesty!
I forgot the manner. Please punish me, Your Majesty.
I noticed you were limping.
Were you flogged?
Who flogged you?
For your information, Your Majesty, when I was going out of town under your command,
I disturbed Commandery Prince An.
His Highness then punished me and had me flogged!
You may both rise.
Academician Xue, didn't you teach Xiao Jinyu
to be loyal and considerate?
I neglected my duty to instruct him.
Please punish me, Your Majesty.
As for Sun Mingde...
The Palace Internal Affairs decides how he should be punished.
Today, Xiao Jinyu didn't tell me before he flogged my eunuch.
Will he dare to kill people without telling me?
Don't be angry, Your Majesty.
His Highness was simply so young that he lost his temper.
Now that he has a temper,
you should instruct him properly.
He even uses the corpse of an official for the coroner exam.
If he can't solve the case, other officials will impeach him!
By then, I'll punish you, too!
Yes.
Your Highness, Jing Yi is so useless.
He's checking Yan Ming's case for half a month, but he has figured out nothing.
As soon as you take over the case, you've found new clues.
This case is difficult for him.
Your Highness, you think highly of the female coroner?
No.
Jing Yi wants me to notice her.
Vice Minister Jing, the next candidate is waiting out there.
How's the examination of bodies going? Has he come?
No.
He's in the latrine, because of diarrhea.
Diarrhea might be a big problem.
Have someone check on him.
Ask the next candidate to wait for a moment.
Yes.
Stay here and wait.
Don't run about, make a noise or look around.
When the examination body comes, you can start.
Yes.
- Your Highness.
Is that a girl taking the exam?
Yes, Your Highness. She has been in for a while.
He's got a bruise on his forehead.
He must be the examination of body for me.
You're the examination body, right?
What took you so long? I've been waiting for a while.
My Lord, he has come.
May I start now?
How dare you!
You can.
Vice Minister Jing.
Lord Jing.
The candidate and the examination body have come.
Examination body?
All right, then.
Now that you're both here,
let's get started.
Man, around 1.8 meters tall.
There's a bruise on his forehead.
Can you squat a bit?
Squat a bit, or I can't see clearly.
Just do it.
Now that you agree to be the examination body, you should cooperate.
It was hit by something hard.
No medicine has been applied yet.
He was possibly hurt last night.
Besides blood stasis, there're slight scratches.
I think he was hit
by a flat and roughly polished weapon, made of hardwood.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
There's a bruise as wide as a palm on the back of your left hand.
It was pressed by something heavy.
I guess
someone stepped on your hand.
A man.
You injured the end of your palms
by putting them against a smooth hard thing.
You nearly got the wounds at the same time.
Go away.
All right. Take off your clothes.
Go on.
No.
You were right.
You guessed right, too.
I've got a bruise on my tailbone.
But you don't need to check that.
You can stop now.
No way!
This isn't over yet.
I can't even fill half of the sheet.
If I stop now, I won't get a good score.
You're the examination body.
You can't decide if I continue or not.
If you don't want to take off your clothes, let me help you.
What does she want to do?
What does he want to do?
- What does she want to do?
When did I say I was the examination body?
You said that outside the room.
I did?
No. No.
You said that!
I only said you could start the test.
Jing Yi.
Yes, Your Highness. What do you want?
Sorry for the offense. Please forgive me, Your Highness.
Your... Your Highness?
You... you're the Commandery Prince An, Small Goldfish?
Shut up! Don't talk nonsense!
Salute to His Highness and say sorry!
Are you superior to a prefect?
What do you think you're doing?
I never met such an important official before.
But I met a prefect.
When the Prefect of Qianzhou visited our town,
our magistrate taught us
that when we met the Prefect, we should knee and kowtow.
I kowtowed once to him.
Now that you're superior, I kowtowed a few more times.
Is that enough?
Master, it was so wise of you!
His Majesty appreciates Xiao Jinyu for his justness.
How were you sure that he would defend me today?
Han Ji is the Minister of Justice,
but he has to take orders from Xiao Jinyu.
He can't be feeling good.
When he knows Xiao Jinyu used Yan Ming's corpse for the test,
he would certainly impeach him.
Those who Xiao Jinyu has offended are happy to help, too.
Xiao Jinyu was punished to repent.
Today, it was also possible
even if I wanted him to be flogged 50 times too.
Xiao Jinyu is known to be smart.
As far as I see, you're much smarter.
Not to mention Xiao Jinyu, even if his father were still alive...
I'm sorry.
Don't get angry, Master.
His Majesty mentioned it today.
Xiao Heng ran away! After him!
Be quick!
If Xiao Heng were still alive, we would be dead!
Yes.
Think more and talk less.
Or you can't survive!
Yes.
Greetings, Eunuch Qin.
General Zhou, may I have a word with you?
[Zhou Han, Commandant of Shen Army]
Find an excuse and check what happened in Three Judicial Chief Ministries.
Yes.
Your Highness, the previous exams are over.
Check carefully
if there's any wrong information on the sheet.
[Exam sheet, Chu Chu, female]
I filled it myself. Nothing is wrong.
You came from Pingle Town, Guanling County, Qianzhou?
You're from an official family and a literary family.
And all your families are loyal?
Yes.
Nonsense!
You're obviously from a coroner family.
Your grandfather is still alive.
Your father doesn't have any brother, but you have one.
Your brother even has a dog.
How do you even know that?
You wear big clothes and they're nearly new.
They are altered, but not tailored.
It means you borrowed them.
On your wristbands and hems, there're old and new dog scratches.
Considering your age, they can't be your father's.
They're very likely to be your brother's.
He can even see that?
There's the smell of honey locust and atractylodes on your clothes.
Now, the fact that you wash clothes with them,
it means the clothes belong to someone who is a coroner, too.
He's awesome!
Coroner is usually a family job.
As far as I see in your autopsy,
you're quite proficient in some unpopular skills.
Such skills have a conflict with the Great Tang Laws.
They weren't invented in recent years.
You know such skills.
It means your ancestors were coroners before the reign of Emperor Taizong.
You're right about everything!
You look handsome,
sound perspicacious and take care of criminal cases.
You... you're Handsome Judge?
Handsome Judge?
The chief of Six Gates!
Chief of Six Gates?
He's untraceable.
It's always hard to trace him down.
Nine Constables all take his orders.
He's the Chief of Six Gates, taking care of all criminal cases,
known as Handsome Judge.
A constable with great martial arts
follows him, named ﻿Soul-chasing Sword.
I've never heard of him.
I'm not Handsome Judge, either.
You've been mistaken.
But... You're as awesome as him.
Stop talking nonsense.
Now that I'm right about everything, you admit that
you filled in fake information on the exam sheet
and lied about your family background?
But I told the truth.
My families are coroners for generations and work in Yamen.
Aren't we consider an official family?
My family can also read.
We have a lot of books.
Aren't we a literary family?
Also, we're good people who have done nothing bad.
Aren't we loyal?
Kind of.
I heard what you said during the autopsy.
I want you to explain more about something.
When you checked the dead man who was stabbed by a sharp object,
you said he knew the murderer and the murderer knew him, too.
Do you mean they're acquainted?
Yes, you're right.
How did you know that?
I...
I'm afraid I can't explain clearly.
Can I gesture?
Yes.
Judged from his wound,
when he was killed, he was facing the murderer.
Just like... this.
What are you doing?
I'm trying to show you.
Wu Jiang.
He was offensive.
I apologize on his behalf.
It doesn't matter.
I... I was offensive, too.
Even if this was how he died,
why did it mean he knew the murderer?
If he didn't know the murderer,
he would have reacted just like he did.
As long as he had struggled,
he wouldn't have had such a smooth wound.
The brush is simply 20cm long.
But the weapon was a meter long.
He had much more time to respond.
However strong the murderer was,
he could have time to seize the weapon
when he was stabbed.
But within such a long time, he didn't struggle at all.
It means he never expected that man to kill him.
He didn't want to believe that even when he was dying.
You know clearly what a dead man thinks.
Of course.
Dead men are different from living people.
You can learn from their corpse
about their thought and what they did before death.
It's much easier to understand them than living people.
What else can you see from his corpse?
One more thing.
But I haven't seen where he was killed.
I can't talk without evidence.
I can show you the place.
Do you want to handle this for me?
Yes. Of course!
[Two Merits Hall]
- Your Highness.
- You really don't know Six Gates?
It's a wonderful place. There're even female constables.
I thought Six Gates was the only place where women could work.
You're sure she wasn't lying?
Why do I think she keeps talking nonsense?
I work for His Highness by judging if someone's lying.
Even if you don't trust me, you should trust my ancestral skill.
I hear you got her back from the street.
Yes.
What do you mean got her back?
I did that for the sake of her fate with His Highness.
See? His Highness noticed her.
I'm serious.
[Three Judicial Chief Ministries]
- Greetings, Your Highness.
- Who are you?
You may rise.
I'm a waiter at Fusheng Inn.
The girl...
It's already bad luck when a female coroner like her lives in our inn.
She even ran away without paying the bill!
She left a stone pendant,
saying she would take the exam here
- Why does she have the pendant?
- and would buy the pendant back afterward.
Who exactly is she?
I think she simply wants to repudiate the bill!
No, no.
I didn't mean that!
When I woke up this morning, I found my purse missing.
I was in a hurry for the exam.
Then I left the pendant as a pledge
and left a note on the table.
I even put my thumbprint on it.
As soon as I make money, I'll go pay the bill
and buy back my pendant.
Buy back such a useless stone.
Who are you trying to fool?
It's not a useless stone!
- You're obviously trying to repudiate the bill!
- I'm not!
How much does she owe you?
Please understand, Your Highness.
Taking accommodation, lamp-oil, and candle into consideration,
the bill is 37 copper coins.
I'm telling the truth!
Jing Yi.
Thank you. Thank you.
Your Highness, there's another bill.
- She's a coroner...
- How dare you to push it!
- Sir...
- What sir? Vice Minister!
Vice Minister, think about it.
If it were you,
would you like to sleep on a bed a coroner once slept on
or use the tableware she used?
I would.
Wu Jiang, go back with him and tell the manager of the inn that
I'll rent the room Miss Chu lived in for a long term.
No one shall change anything in that room.
- I'll go live there whenever I'm free.
- Yes.
I'll see what an inn it is
that even a waiter can bully a customer in my place.
Don't get angry, Your Highness!
I don't mean that.
I won't ask for the money. I won't!
- I'm leaving, Your Highness.
- Come back. Her pendant!
And the note she wrote.
Go!
Spare me, Official!
I won't do that again, Official!
Thank you, Your Highness.
I paid.
Thank you, too, Lord Jing.
When I make money, I'll pay you back.
Don't bother.
Timing and subtitles brought to you by The Imperial Coroners @ Viki.com
♫  Nothing can stop me  ♫
♫  From missing you all the time  ♫
♫  The moonlight appears, cold in the late night,
as the world changes  ♫
♫  Only with you by my side can I embrace my yearning for you  ♫
♫  When I close my eyes I meet you once again  ♫
♫  I'll gently brush your hair by your ear  ♫
♫  Life is long, with love and regrets in this world  ♫
♫  With you by my side, no matter how far I go,
we'll never be apart  ♫
♫  With your smile, in this moment, let me
cherish this lifetime  ♫
♫  Only for you, I have to worry about the end of this life  ♫
♫  I’m still young, with my love not yet realized for you, but I'm
willing to be here for you till the end  ♫
♫  You can rely on me in this lifetime  ♫
♫  Hope to spend this beautiful lifetime together  ♫