Leng Yue got hurt for saving me.
General Xiao arrived at that time.
His Highness found fake copper cash in the pay of General Xiao.
His Highness said Prefect Li Zhang might play a role.
Lord Jing and His Highness made a bet and went to the county government.
I took His Highness and General Xiao home.
My brother met us.
He scolded me for that.
He's really ill-tempered.
I can't do anything about that.
Sir, would you please do me a favor?
We'd love to. What's it?
It's late now.
Will you allow us to stay here for one night?
Are you serious?
Stay here?
Sir, we are a family of coroners.
Even the villagers dislike getting in contact with us
because they think it's unlucky.
Will you really stay here?
As a coroner, you are helping the dead and the government.
How could it be unlucky?
Every government office has its mortuary.
Chu Chu saw that there're also such rooms in my home in Chang'an.
If you have to say so,
I'm about the same as you are.
You have such a room, too?
Yes, they really have one.
I even performed an autopsy there.
Autopsy results are the basis for investigation.
One false step will make a great difference.
As a judge, we have to be cautious.
Go tidy up a room and prepare some dishes and wine.
You don't know where the wine is.
I store them. I know where it is.
I will go take it.
Come with me.
Zhang Yun. Chen Feng.
- Yes.
Go visit Jing Yi and tell him I'm staying here tonight.
Ask him to do whatever he should do. He doesn't need to wait for me.
- Yes.
Timing and subtitles brought to you by The Imperial Coroners @ Viki.com
[The Imperial Coroner]
[Episode 11]
Brother, what's the matter?
Tell me who those people are.
You heard that.
One is a judge from the imperial court.
The other is his elder brother, a general.
His men once suppressed bandits around here.
Every word is true.
You went to Chang'an alone.
How could you know people like that?
I met them on the exam.
You went their house on the exam?
I've been helping him investigate when I was in Chang'an.
So he let me stay so that he could ask for information.
You even lived in his house?
Jing Yi should hold Li Zhang for half a day.
We will meet him in the government office after we have supper.
Why do you want to stay here now?
Isn't it odd?
Chu Chu isn't treated as she's a biological daughter.
They are all good to her, aren't they?
Yes, they are good to her.
But it's weird.
Weird?
As her father, Chu Ping shows his love.
But it's in a polite way.
Polite?
I once left the capital for a case.
Mother was worrying all night.
When I went for her for some tea,
she said in anger she wouldn't allow me to drink.
Chu Chu has left home for so long without any news.
Now she's back all of a sudden.
But Chu Ping didn't blame her at all.
Maybe it's because Chu Ping isn't as bad-tempered as Mother.
No.
And Chu He, he didn't act like an elder brother.
Chu He is a bit weird.
If you were sent back by others after being away home for a long time,
I'd first see if you are all right.
As long as you are fine and the visitors aren't malicious,
I'd say thanks of course.
But Chu He didn't.
It seems the kinder we are, the more he cares about who we are
and the more malicious he is.
You are right.
As a girl with an unimpeachable reputation,
how could you just live in a strange man's house at random?
You don't know what intentions he had.
He had good intentions.
You know what?
I lost my purse then and was wronged by others.
He caught the thief and got my purse back.
When I was hijacked in the street, he arranged his men to save me.
What's more, he has never looked down upon me.
He said I'm the best coroner he has ever met.
I failed the last test for coroner, but he is willing to give me another chance.
He said he'd take me back to Chang'an if he agreed to take me on.
Even if he decides not to hire me, he will investigate my background
so as to rank me as a coroner.
He even wants to investigate your background?
Brother, it's an item in the ranking test.
You took it in your first test, right?
Yes, that's true.
I know others said I was born out of wedlock.
But you've asked me to ignore the words since I was a little girl.
You told me that's nonsense.
He's the smartest and fairest person I've ever seen.
He won't trust the nonsense readily.
He will figure it out himself.
Lass, do you have to be the coroner?
Our family are all coroners for generations.
I'm one of us. Of course, I will be a coroner.
This...
If the Handsome Judge doesn't exist,
the coroner around him should be the one making people jealous.
I thought he sent me home because he didn't want me.
But he is staying for one night.
It means I still have a chance.
That's my last chance. I will surely take the opportunity.
You want to leave home so much to work with him?
Of course not.
After I make some achievements, I will take you all to Chang'an.
Brother, Chang'an is big, very beautiful.
It has everything.
You will like it.
I don't like it.
You talked to me about our father.
So you doubt it's related to the Chu family?
The Chu family and Father were close.
There must be clues about Father here.
The Chu family hide Chu Chu's background on purpose
and Chu Chu hides the history of the pendant deliberately.
We can only find out the truth here.
Are you sure the witch doctor is our father?
That's the only possibility.
The Chu family are honest people.
How about asking them straightly?
It's not the time.
Okay. It's up to you.
Will you ask some guardsmen here?
Or I call some soldiers?
Otherwise, you will live with me tonight.
Excuse me.
It's the backlands here.
Our family lives here alone without any relative visiting.
We don't have many rooms.
Today we can get only one room for you.
It's fine. That's enough.
My brother and I haven't been together for long.
Right?
Thank you for understanding.
Thank you.
I have to leave now.
Let's go.
[Antique Shop]
[The Book of Songs]
Master, goods from the southwest arrive.
Here is the list. Please check.
[To Manager Chi]
You may leave now.
[Three stars are on the sky. Which day is today?]
[One hundred and sixty eight]
[On the islet, there is a beauty.]
[Fish]
[One hundred and sixty eight]
[Is]
[Unhooked]
[Fish is unhooked.]
[Fish is unhooked and enters Qianzhou.]
My Lord, the mushrooms are freshly picked.
Please have a try.
It's a specialty in the mountains here.
Father, here's the liquor.
You silly boy. Why are you standing here?
Serve the liquor to the guests.
Chu made all dishes herself.
She said it's for thanking you.
If you don't like any of the dishes, just punish her.
Your Highness, please.
So this is a tea party in Qianzhou?
Your Highness, both tea and liquor are for a party.
I especially took two chefs from the government office.
They are no better than chefs in Chang'an.
But they are good at making Qianzhou dishes.
Please enjoy, Your Highness.
Please enjoy, Miss Leng.
Yes. Please enjoy.
Please enjoy.
Prefect Li, you are well prepared.
It's my pleasure.
Your Highness.
Your Highness. Miss Leng. Please.
Is it…
Thank you for the reward, Your Highness.
Why are you pretending?
- This...
- What?
Your Highness, sorry I don't understand.
Please make it clear.
Prefect Li, Magistrate Zheng, can't you see the copper coins are illegal?
This...
[Qian]
It's my fault.
As the prefect of Qianzhou, I don't know such a monstrous crime
was committed in my rule.
I cannot get away with it.
Please punish, Your Highness.
Yes, I can't avoid punishment, either.
Prefect Li, Magistrate Zheng.
Please get up.
Prefect Li, you can't blame yourself.
The copper coins are good enough to pass for genuine.
It's hard for ordinary people to figure it out.
I found it all of a sudden in the market on my way to the county government office.
Anyway, it's a serious matter.
Please investigate thoroughly.
I will do it.
Copper cash casting needs tremendous manpower and materials.
As the Prefect of Qianzhou, you know the situation the best.
It's the right thing to let you investigate the case.
So just go ahead.
- I…
- That's enough. Let's stop talking about business.
Let's just enjoy the party.
Hey, don't just keep eating.
Do you have any news?
I will tell you if there is.
But I don't get any news.
Normally, if Xu Rugui doesn't have any news,
there should be the pony express about Xiao Jinyu's death.
But there is no news.
What should we do
if my master asks for it?
It's not an easy thing for you.
Xu Rugui didn't do it well.
It made you suffer hardship.
Yes, how awful!
He's been fond of food and drink when nothing bad happens.
But we have to handle it when something happens.
Will Xu Rugui take the chance to escape because he thought Eunuch Qin
isn't as powerful as before?
No, he won't.
Where can he escape to?
His home is here.
He has his wife and concubines as well as his children here.
He won't be as inhumane as Xiao Heng was.
Stop!
It's the anniversary of Prince Consort's death tomorrow.
Aren't you afraid he enters your dream?
You…
Stop talking nonsense.
It's really unlucky.
Your Highness.
I'm not drunk.
Your Highness. The road is wet.
Mind your step! Your Highness.
Your Highness. I'm slow-witted.
I should be punished with one cup.
No, no, no. It should be three cups.
Three cups.
Magistrate Zheng. Rest early.
Let's gather next time.
Yes. Yes.
Yes.
What's wrong? Are you all right?
I'm okay.
I was drinking rashly.
You are too thin to bear it.
Take this. You will be fine soon.
You didn't allow me to drink and even drank for me.
Why did you flaunt your superiority?
I didn't.
You can't drink for the injuries.
I've told you I'm fine.
You need to meet His Highness, right?
Oh, yes.
I will go soon.
I will keep watching here.
If anyone asks for anything, I will say you are buying food for me.
Are you taking me as a fool?
I can see that Zheng Youde is truly drunk but Li Zhang is pretending.
Fine.
Wait for me with the night snack.
Just go ahead.
Your Highness, why are you standing here?
I haven't drunk for long. It makes me a bit dizzy.
I'm out here to sober up a bit.
Great! I just made some soup for it.
Just take it before it cools down.
Thank you.
It's my pleasure. I prepared it when I made dishes.
You are suffering from indigestion.
You will feel uncomfortable without soup for sobering up after drinking.
How do you know my suffering?
I've seen it on the way back.
You didn't like cold food nor stodge.
You didn't drink cold water no matter how thirsty you were.
You've kept your hand in the chest when you were taking a nap.
Most people with stomach illness have this habit.
Thank you for paying attention to me.
But please keep it as a secret.
And don't let my brother and Jing Yi know that.
They don't know it?
It's no big deal.
If they know it, they will accommodate themselves to me.
It's troublesome.
Finish this.
Then I will keep it a secret for you.
Thank you.
It's me who should say so.
My family is very hospitable.
But as coroners, people often avoid us on walking in the street,
let alone coming to visit.
You are willing to eating and living here.
All of us are very happy.
- Really?
- Sure.
About what happened today, my family can talk to others for years.
What I wanted to ask is, are you really happy for my visiting?
I…
At first, I didn't want you to come.
You said you would send me home if you decided to refuse me.
I was afraid you would leave me home and refuse me after sending me back.
Meanwhile, I don't have a good reputation here.
I feared that you might change your mind after you knew that even if you planned to hire me.
Reputation?
Chu He and I weren't born by the same mother.
His mother was my father's wife.
She died of dystocia after giving birth to Chu He.
I never know who my mother was.
People here always said I was an illegitimate child.
Anyway, I don't mind it now.
You said I only need to act well and wait for your decision.
You haven't told me your decision, so I can't think randomly.
I choose to work with you, so I should trust you.
Here. Open it.
Your Highness, what is this?
Your tools were ruined when you worked for me.
I should compensate you.
I got the materials from the best swordsmith in Chang'an.
They are tough and corrosion-resistant.
But I didn't have too much time with tough conditions on the way
to make it more precise.
You made them yourself?
On our way here from Chang'an?
It's impossible.
I've been with you all the time.
You were reading or reviewing the files.
I didn't see you doing this.
I made them during the night.
Night?
You didn't sleep?
I used to sleep little since I was a child.
As long as you like it, my efforts were not in vain.
Of course, I like it, but…
It's too valuable.
It's valuable only if you can get along with it.
Lord Jing.
Lord Jing, have you eaten yet?
My father went out for liquor and he'll be back soon.
Will you have a drink?
No, thanks.
May I speak to His Highness in private?
Okay. I will be in there.
Chu Chu. Do you have food that I can take away? Please pack some for me.
Okay.
Did you get the ins and outs about Li Zhang and Zheng Youde?
Zheng Youde didn't act abnormally.
But his words are different from Chu He's.
It's true he doesn't bully people.
Anyway, he isn't a good officer, but an honest officer at most.
Honest like a bungler.
Even the Deputy Magistrate under him has more brains than him.
We can see through the cases he dealt with these years
that he's slow-witted but conscientious.
How about Li Zhang?
He must know something about the copper cash casting.
I just gave the case to him without any hesitation as per your words.
Then he pretended to be drunk early because he's afraid I'd ask more.
Yes, I lost the bet.
But I wonder if the information about
the Chu family are worth five gold coins.
Say it.
I asked Zheng Youde for information about the Chu family.
Before Zheng Youde came to Guanling County for the post,
Chu Chu has lived in the Chu family.
So he doesn't know who Chu Chu's biological mother is.
Anyway, according to Zheng Youde,
every one of the Chu family is a freak.
What do you mean?
The family didn't contact people at ordinary times.
But they offered sacrifice to the death
without ties of consanguinity with them.
They live frugally.
But they are generous to the dead.
Your Highness, don't you think it's weird?
Weird?
Do you mean the tomb of Chu Chu's mother may be there?
How is it? Is it worth five coins?
Lord Jing.
- Thank you.
- Be careful.
- The officer…
I'm leaving.
Mind your step.
Brother. Brother, you are drunk. Get in.
I am not drunk. I'm very awake.
What's going on?
I didn't expect he can't drink.
He was fine just now.
I didn't get drunk.
You said you're an official from Chang'an.
I don't believe it.
Prove it.
Brother, stop jabbering Grandpa is sleeping.
You'd go sleep too. It's none of your business.
Do you dare?
What should I do to prove it?
There is a haunted house.
The one the witch doctor lived in.
If you can catch the ghost, I will trust you.
The witch doctor lived in a haunted house?
Brother, stop talking nonsense.
Go back to your room.
Chu Chu.
Is it true?
It's true.
The house has become haunted... for years.
Everyone in Pingle knows it.
If you don't dare, don't come for Chu Chu again.
Okay. I will go with you tomorrow morning.
Now. Not tomorrow morning.
The ghost appears at night, not in the morning.
Are you scared?
You hear it?
The ghost is crying.
It's from the house.
So what?
Do you dare to go?
Since it is so, please lead us the way.
Your Highness
Do you really dare to go?
I've never seen a ghost before.
So I can take the chance to increase my knowledge.
Brother Chu, please.
General Xiao, please stop His Highness.
I haven't seen a ghost, either.
I will go with Jinyu.
Let's go.
Wait for me.
You really went to buy the snacks?
Of course.
How do you feel? Are you sober now?
Yes.
Why are you so gentle today?
I'm a bit…
Get up. Remember you are Commandery Prince An now.
His Highness can't sit like that.
So you are treating me as I'm His Highness?
His Highness ordered that I'd cooperate with you.
Tell me the truth.
Did you lose your heart to His Highness?
You are not awake, right?
What nonsense are you talking about?
When Princess Xiping asked you to come to Qianzhou,
didn't she tell you she wants you to marry His Highness?
You agreed to come to Qianzhou.
Does it mean you agree with the marriage?
What are you talking about?
My auntie never mentioned that to me.
What's more, His Highness and you are my best bros.
Who will marry her bro?
You are a girl.
I won't take you as my bro.
Okay. Sister and brother. Sister and brother?
No.
Sisters. Will it be all right?
You are still drunk, aren't you?
I will accept the snack. Thank you.
Go back to sleep quickly.
Sisters?
I don't want to be.
[Jing Manor]
[Qian]
Why are you sitting here alone?
Darling, aren't you sleeping?
Do you meet any difficulties or did you buy something secretly?
Darling, it's no big deal.
Don't bother.
Then forget it.
I also don't want to concern about your things.
I'm here originally to tell you how to solve the marriage
of Commandery Prince An and Leng Yue.
Anyway, since you don't want to bother, I'm leaving now.
Hey, no, please don't.
Darling. Please calm your anger.
I'm begging you.
Please sit down, my darling.
Darling, you like the jade bracelet with lotus on
from the Han palace sold in Antique Store, right?
I will buy it for you tomorrow.
It's been a while.
It must have been sold out.
As long as you like it, it'll be yours.
I will get it for you no matter how.
That's about right.
Then please tell me the details.
You know what?
Nice. Okey.
Brother. Brother!
Forget it. Let's go back.
No. We have to catch the ghost today.
Don't be scared. I will protect you.
Is it that place?
That's it.
Do you dare to enter?
Brother, please mess the pile up.
Okay. I will take something for it.
Why do you do that?
Don't you want me to catch the ghost?
Do you mean the ghost is hiding here?
No.
It should be that the so-called ghost is trapped in.
Chu Chu. You said the house was like that when the witch doctor lived here?
It happened when I was a child.
One day, the house suddenly made the noise.
Sir Witch Doctor wasn't scared at all.
I was scared at first but not later after I got used to it.
There is no so-called ghost.
It's just because it's windy at night in the mountainous area.
The wall affects the wind direction.
So it caused the cry.
Make way, please.
Brother.
Brother!
Be careful.
The ghost cry is gone.
What's going on?
Father could see it all.
He must have done it on purpose.
On purpose?
Brother, there is an interlayer.
Why is there something here?
Why is it hidden here?
Did Sir Witch Doctor put it here?
Come on. Take it out.
Luckily, it's not Sir Witch Doctor.
White gypsum. Charcoal. Flax.
Sichuan Pepper. Sawdust.
They are all for anticorrosion.
The body should be preserved here by someone deliberately.
Deliberately?
Did Sir Witch Doctor do it?
What for?
It's iron stick for furnace lining.
It'll be rainy later.
Let's take the corpse in.
All right. Chu He. Please help us.
Don't move. Let Chu Chu do it.
I'm the coroner of Guanling County.
Let me do it.
You just drunk and are not awake now.
You even can't control yourself in front of your senior.
How can I trust you that you can perform duties as a coroner?
Brother, I can do it.
Chu Chu. Do it.
[Domestic Service]
A tag of Palace Domestic Service.
Palace Domestic Service?
[Domestic Service]
Why is the belonging of the palace here?
The dead…
What's wrong?
He's neither a man nor a woman.
Neither a man nor a woman?
- Eunuch!
Why was there a eunuch here?
The corpse was carefully kept.
It looks plump, making it as it hasn't been dead for long.
Actually, he died years ago.
This kind of corpse is called a wet body in our sector.
My grandpa said that before.
This is the first time I see it.
Can you check out the cause?
There are several sharp injuries.
The wounds are narrow.
The fatal injury is ripping into its left chest obliquely
upward from the 5th rib, and out of its upper left back
after through the heart.
The weapon is almost a sharp, cylindric,
hard thing with a tine, like a…
Like this.
Yes, it's like that.
Oh, no!
Timing and subtitles brought to you by The Imperial Coroners @ Viki.com
♫  Nothing can stop me  ♫
♫  From missing you all the time  ♫
♫  The moonlight appears, cold in the late night,
as the world changes  ♫
♫  Only with you by my side can I embrace my yearning for you  ♫
♫  When I close my eyes I meet you once again  ♫
♫  I'll gently brush your hair by your ear  ♫
♫  Life is long, with love and regrets in this world  ♫
♫  With you by my side, no matter how far I go,
we'll never be apart  ♫
♫  With your smile, in this moment, let me
cherish this lifetime  ♫
♫  Only for you, I have to worry about the end of this life  ♫
♫  I’m still young, with my love not yet realized for you, but I'm
willing to be here for you till the end
♫  You can rely on me in this lifetime  ♫
♫  Hope to spend this beautiful lifetime together  ♫