Timing and subtitles brought to you by The Imperial Coroners @ Viki.com
The Prince sent people to save me and found my baggage for me.
I've never seen such a good official like him.
It would be great if I can work with him.
The Prince must be the Handsome Judge.
Otherwise, how would he know so much about the Handsome Judge?
Miss, I think you better confess.
You have tasted the food in the jail.
Don't you want a quick death?
A life for a life.
I have nothing to say.
I can't report to Commandery Prince An just with your life.
Let's talk about this.
I heard from Commandery Prince An that you killed Yan Ming to steal something.
You are a weak woman.
It's not easy for you to use great effort to steal something.
I'm not asking you to return it.
Just tell me what kind of stuff it is.
I'll give Commandery Prince An a similar one to finish my task.
It's a win-win solution.
Vice Minister Jing has a glib tongue indeed.
Since Prince An doesn't know what I stole, you can put him off
with anything you want.
Why bother?
You really stole something from Yan Ming?
I didn't believe Commandery Prince An when he told me about it.
Yan Ming is a nerd.
There are a few valuable paintings and calligraphy works in his manor.
But they are not worth enough to get him killed.
And you had no chance to take the thing out of
Yan Manor on the night when it happened.
I thought Commandery Prince An made a mistake.
Now it seems that I really have to give him something to finish my task.
To be frank,
I really want to put him off with something.
But who is Commandery Prince An?
He is Deity Erlang.
(T/N: Erlang Shen is a Chinese god with a third truth-seeing eye in the middle of his forehead)
Somehow he got one more truth-seeing eye than others.
It's not as easy as you think to put him off.
Let's take a look at you.
You used great effort to cover the blood and hide the weapon.
But he still found you out.
I know you hid the thing you stole in Yan Manor.
I need to send the interrogation record to Commandery Prince An tonight.
You are a smart woman.
Think about it.
If I hand in the record and Commandery Prince An closes the case,
the thing you hid in Yan Manor will be safe.
Then you can give it to anyone you want.
Just tell me what kind of stuff it is.
Can I trust what you say?
You really hid the thing in Yan's mansion?
You...!
[The Imperial Coroner]
[Episode 3]
Your Highness, there are all kinds of people in Chang'an.
This girl is so credulous.
It's dangerous for her to stay in Chang'an.
Should I warn her a little bit?
After all, safety awareness is necessary.
Her parents can say that.
Her relatives and friends can say that.
Ordinary people can also say that.
But officials like us can never say that.
If the official asks people to be on a defensive day and night
and be cautious all the time,
why would the court keep us?
Please calm down. I was wrong.
Your Highness, Miss Chu has finished the autopsy.
- How do you know that?
- What?
The words you just said.
The officials can't say that and why would the court keep you...
That's what the Handsome Judge said.
How do you know that?
Has the Handsome Judge you've been talking about also said that?
Yes, that's what he said.
You have never seen that Handsome Judge,
how do you know what he said?
I heard a lot about him.
He said those words when he was admonishing the corrupt officials.
Where did you hear about his deeds?
I just know it.
You haven't told me how you know these words.
I also heard it from someone else.
How is the autopsy?
I've finished it.
But there is something strange.
Your Higness, can you come with me and check it?
Okay.
The dead were male. He was older than 30 years old.
The cause of death is being shot by a short arrow in the heart.
His legs or feet were fine.
He pretended to have a limp.
I should have found it out at the time.
But I panicked.
It's not your fault.
He wanted to hurt you,
he would attack you no matter if you found it out or not.
Although he pretended to have a limp,
he did have many scars on his body.
The oldest one is five or six years old.
The newest one is about one month old.
They are all sharp injuries.
He should be someone who used swords and spears a lot.
There is a thick callus on his right hand's purlicue.
Based on the position and the shape of the callus,
he should use knives a lot.
But... there is one strange thing.
This man used his right hand a lot,
but he was left-handed.
What do you mean by that?
The callus on his right hand means he
[Swordsman]
often held a knife with his right hand.
When he hijacked me, he also held the knife with his right hand.
But the callus caused by writing is on his left hand,
[Scholar]
which means he wrote with his left hand and held a knife with his right hand.
A left-handed scholar
[Swordsman Scholar]
and right-handed swordsman. This person was too weird.
What's the difference between me and the man in charge?
A beard.
Isn't it just a beard?
Zhou Han greets Eunuch Qin.
Have you finished it?
It was one step away.
Xiao Jinyu's Chief Guardsman, Wu Jiang
suddenly showed up with his men and took that female coroner away.
Did you men fight with Xiao Jinyu's people?
Yes.
But we've been very careful to conceal our moves.
The captive was silenced in time.
What about the body?
Zhou!
Can't you clean up your own mess now?
Please rest assured.
That person never met anyone from the Judicial Service.
Xiao Jinyu won't know him.
What a fool.
Please calm down, I'm slow witted.
You are not slow witted.
You are retarded.
Let me ask you.
Did your men see the pendant again?
Yes.
But they didn't get it.
Find some clever men and keep a close eye
on Xiao Jinyu and Princess Xiping.
Let me know immediately if anything happens.
Especially when it's about the pendant.
What's more, go back and shave the hair around your mouth.
I'll kill everyone in your family
if I see one more hair again.
I know.
Get out!
Master, would Zhou Han, this idiot, implicate us?
Keep an eye on the outside.
Yes sir.
It wouldn't be strange if he was originally in the army.
In the army?
A martial art master would hold the weapon with his hand
that he is comfortable with.
But it's different in the army.
The soldier must hold the weapon with the right hand, without exception.
Therefore, the left-handed will become ambidextrous after they join the army.
I just arrived in Chang'an.
I haven't offended anyone who served as a soldier.
You didn't offend him.
It's he who has an eye on you.
On me?
I have no money.
- I see.
- What?
When he hijacked me,
he told me that he wouldn't kill me if I go with him.
I think he fell in love with me.
He wanted to take me back and make me his wife.
It's getting late.
Miss Chu. You...
Chu Chu, have you found a place to stay in Chang'an?
Not yet.
I'm worried that the inn owner doesn't want to take in a coroner.
I wanted to find a deserted temple.
But there seems to be no deserted temple here.
The stores will be closed half an hour later.
I've taken too much of your time today.
You can stay in the Three Judicial Chief Ministries if you want.
It is also convenient for me to discuss these unfinished cases with you at any time.
Live in the Three Judicial Chief Ministries?
I also live in the Three Judicial Chief Ministries.
Well, do you have other plans for the night?
No. I'm willing to.
I can work for you if you don't mind.
I can do anything.
I won't stay there and eat your food for free.
[Three Judicial Chief Ministries]
Miss Chu, please have some tea.
You are...
I'm a maidservant here, Lian Qiao.
You can order me if you need anything.
No.
- Have you been working here for many years?
- Yes.
You must know a lot about the Prince, right?
What do you want to know?
Is the Prince married?
The Prince isn't married.
No way.
How is he not married at this age?
In our Pingle Town, a man at his age should become a father long ago.
The Prince is still young.
How is Miss Chu doing?
Miss Chu has settled down.
Our guards live in Liutao Office.
They will report immediately if anything happens.
Did she ask you anything about the manor?
Never.
But Miss Chu asked me about a place.
- What place?
- Do you know where the Six Gates is?
The Six Gates is the Three Judicial Chief Ministries.
Here?
Not really.
The Six Gates is what the people working in the office call it.
It's a nickname. It's a joke.
No.
I'm not talking about this Six Gates, but the Six Gates
with constables and the Handsome Judge.
Let her do whatever she wants in the manor
and give her what she wants.
I'd like to see what she's up to.
Does he have someone he likes?
Why are you so interested in the Prince's love life?
I just don't get it.
What kind of woman can match such a handsome man like the Prince?
It would be best if she is
a lady with double-fold eyelids and a high nose.
With the appearance of the Prince,
their child will be really good-looking.
I dare not discuss the Prince's personal life.
But what you just said, that's how the girls in Chang'an
talk about Vice Minister Jing.
It's rare that a girl would praise the Prince the way you do.
The girls in Chang'an do have a strange taste.
How handsome the Prince is.
By the way, I also want to know
if there is any work I can do for the Prince.
Anything will do.
Work?
Miss Chu asked me to bring you a hot boiled egg.
I'm not hungry.
She asked me to peel the egg
and roll it on the wound on your forehead.
It can promote blood circulation and disperse blood stasis.
Go ahead.
Your Highness.
You've been suspecting Miss Chu's background,
but why did you still ask her to do autopsies again and again?
Although she is suspicious,
she is a talented coroner
indeed.
She is more gifted than other coroners.
It's not something you can have through learning.
I've heard that those who play zithers or draw need to be gifted.
A coroner's work is to find out how a person dies.
Does it make any difference being gifted or not?
For ordinary coroners, a corpse is just a corpse.
But, for her, these corpses seem to be alive.
Alive?
She can feel what they feel and think what they think.
I have never seen such a peculiar coroner like her.
It would be the best
if my suspicion of her is just misunderstanding.
If not, I would like to give her a chance
to get back on the right track.
I believe that.
Jing Yi was going down the wrong path at that time,
but you still pulled him back to the right track.
What?
What do you mean?
Are you asking me to roll away?
Well, I've worked my butt off.
It's under curfew now and I can't go home.
I just got here, and you did that to me. Just go.
There are snacks from Princess Xiping's Manor.
It's the top grade.
What about the confession?
It's kind of troublesome now.
The scroll you talked about is really hidden in the Yan manor.
I have found it.
But when I took the scroll back to the Court of Judicial Review
and wanted to question that dancing girl, she died of poison.
I have found someone to check her body. It's aconitine.
(T/N: Aconitine poisoning is related to the rapid onset of life-threatening heart rhythm changes.)
Aconitine?
She is a dancing girl.
How did she get this highly poisonous herb?
She might get it while dancing at some place.
This is the scroll.
This is a book about anecdotes of the Wuzong Dynasty.
Yan Ming wrote a bunch of messy comments next to it.
[Duke Chang The Imperial Family]
He seemed to be interested in
[Mystery]
the Emperor Wuzong's young son, Duke Chang.
I mean, Yan Ming was a scholar.
He didn't study poems and songs,
but study dead people like coroners.
Yan Ming... might be looking for someone.
Looking for someone?
Who was Yan Ming looking for?
A dead person.
A person that no one can find.
What are you talking about?  I think Yan Ming had nothing better to do.
Anyway, the murderer who killed Yan Ming is already dead.
We can offer an explanation to the Emperor now.
Watch your attitude when you go to court tomorrow.
My father and Mr. Xue told you many times
to make more friends and less enemies.
I have no intention of making enemies.
That's good.
But those who are against truth and justice are my enemies.
Wash your hands that just touched the poison.
I asked the kitchen to save some food for you.
You rest here tonight.
Tomorrow morning, go to the Shen Army and ask about
if there is a junior officer in his thirties missing
who has been in the army for about five years.
Shen Army?
Did those eunuchs cause any trouble again?
When we left Yan Manor today, there were soldiers in disguise
who tried to hijack Miss Chu.
They failed
and used this to kill the captive.
This arrowhead is not something that an ordinary blacksmith can make.
This is made by the Crossbow Agency of the Weapon Bureau
exclusively for the army in the capital.
I asked someone to get it from the Crossbow Agency.
Are you suspecting that someone from the Shen Army tried to hijack Chu Chu?
If you verify it
and there is such a person missing in the Shen Army,
then it's not a suspicion anymore.
Qian Printing made copper coins illicitly.
The dancing girl.
The aconitine.
[Qia]
They are all related to the Southwest.
Why does Prince An care so much about
the witch doctor's pendant?
Yan Ming was killed for looking into the son of the late emperor.
The dancer who killed him took poison when she was found out.
Prince An said he is not the Handsome Judge.
But why does he know so much about the Handsome Judge?
The case of Yan Ming is not that simple.
Help!
Something bad happened!
Madam. Madam, are you okay?
What happened?
Master... Master...
Master died.
Madam.
It's okay, Madam. It wasn't me
Really wasn't me!
- It's not me.
- Madam, don't be afraid.
Go get Madam!
[Pull out the net and guard the back]
[The Book of Songs]
Master.
Master, wake up!
Anybody, get in here.
- Your Highness.
- What happened?
Have all the chickens of Chang'an flown here to file a complaint?
The chickens didn't fly here. Miss Chu bought them.
Miss Chu bought them.
Why would she buy chickens?
- Your Highness.
- Go ahead.
There is the obituary from Minister Feng's Manor.
Obituary?
[Feng Manor Liu]
Feng Jie passed away last night.
Didn't Minister Feng go to the Southwest to inspect military affairs?
How did he die?
Tell the housekeeper that I'll go to the Palace first.
I'll go to Feng's Manor to express condolences after I come back.
Yes.
[Three Judicial Chief Ministries]
You are back, Your Highness.
Your Highness.
You may rise.
- You are...
- Raise chickens.
I made a coop last night.
I asked Lian Qiao to buy these chickens this morning.
I bought them with the wages you gave me.
The chicken in Chang'an is too expensive.
If it's in our Pingle Town,
I can at least buy dozens of chickens with this money.
Didn't Wu Jiang tell you
that you don't need to worry about the food here?
General Wu did.
But I can't live here for free.
Lian Qiao said that there are people
who wash clothes and cook for you.
You don't need me to do it. I asked them.
You didn't raise chickens or grow food here.
There happens to be a vacant plot of land here.
So I made use of it for you.
After these chickens grow up, they can lay eggs when it gets warmer.
Chickens lay eggs, and there will be more chickens.
Considering the price of the commodity in Chang'an,
I can make a lot of money for you.
- Thank you for all the trouble.
- Not at all.
After the winter is over, I will clean up the ground in the backyard
and grow vegetables and grains.
Are you going to grow vegetables here?
It's a waste to only raise chickens in such a big area.
But I don't know what should be grown here.
If it's in our Pingle Town, the rice in the backyard
is enough to feed the big family for a year.
Lian Qiao. Go to prepare a set of maid's dress.
Yes sir.
Miss Chu, let's talk about these stuffs later.
I don't know if you can do one favor for me.
Autopsies?
Yes.
Of course I can.
But it's not for the offices.
It's my personal affairs.
Don't worry.
Whether it's for you or the offices, I will do the autopsy well.
I won't put you off.
This time you can't do it in public, and you can't use any tools.
You also need to dress up as my maid and come with me.
Is it okay?
Dress up as a maid and do the autopsy?
But I've never done that before.
If you think I can do it, I'll go with you.
You can do it.
Feed these grains to the chickens.
Thank you.
This dress is too troublesome.
Putting it on is even harder than making a basket.
You will get used to it.
Your Highness. Don't be afraid.
They don't bite people.
How would I be afraid of them?
I just don't want to stain my garments.
Your Highness, it's the first time for me wearing this kind of clothes.
How should I work dressed like this?
Stay here for a while, I'll teach you later.
- The towel.
- Isn't the towel right in front of you?
You are a maid. If I take it by myself, why would I need you?
Use your both hands.
Keep your head down.
It's too much, lift up a little bit.
Your Highness, my third neck bone is about to break.
Stand up.
Keep your spine straight.
Place the towel on the palms of your hands.
Lower your elbows.
Raise your wrist bones to the collarbones.
Keep your sixth and seventh neck bones straight.
Bend the fifth to the first neck bones.
Withdraw your jawbone a little bit.
Have I allowed you to move?
Have you remembered this posture?
Yes. I've remembered the position of each bone.
Put it back.
Answer yes.
Yes.
Keep your hands folded.
Put your right leg back.
Then squat down.
Okay, get up.
How dare you!
You...
Why do you have no scars?
Weren't you hurt before?
- What?
- A sword wound.
About two inches long, so deep that the bone was visible.
After healing, there is a scar as thin as an ink line.
No.
Is he really not the Handsome Judge?
What did you say?
Nothing.
But you are really white.
The creamy skin in the book should be like this.
Enough, come with me.
[Feng Manor]
[Funeral]
Banxia greets Your Highness.
You are exempted.
Is Aunt Banxia here to mourn for your mother?
Yes.
- You are...
- I'm also here to mourn Minister Feng.
I'll leave then.
Your Highness. Did I just give it away?
Yes.
- What to do then?
- It doesn't matter.
It's okay that you gave it away here.
Just follow my instructions after we get in there.
- Senior Jing.
- Okay.
Scholar Xue and Vice Minister Jing have arrived!
Senior Jing.
Sir.
After we get to Feng Manor, I will go to the mourning hall.
After I finish the funeral service, I will give the incense to you.
Then you take a look at Feng Jie's body
when you insert the incense into the burner.
I can only take one look?
If you can tell the cause of his death by taking one look, then yes.
What if I can't?
Miss. Let me do it.
Hurry up.
Servants! Servants!
Clear it up.
Come on, get up.
Come on. My lords.
Please move to the side hall to rest.
These are... scratches?
Miss! Madam, look at her!
What are you doing?
These incense ashes were splashed on Minister Feng.
He can't wear this shroud.
What are you doing?
When ashes fall on the shroud, it's the dead soul protesting against injustice.
It's unlucky. You should change the shroud now.
You should change the shroud now.
What injustice? What nonsense are you talking about?
Don't slander our Master. Well...
Don't talk nonsense. Apologize to Madam Feng now.
I'm not talking nonsense.
Don't you talk back!
Your Highness, she is not talking nonsense.
I have also heard about it before.
Madam, I think you better change Minister Feng's shroud.
We don't believe it.
But if someone who believes it sees it and spreads it out,
won't it hurt Minister Feng's reputation?
Well...
[Antique Store]
Sir. We got new products from the Southwest.
[Book of Songs]
Give it to me.
By the way, Senior Jing rushed us a few times.
Pack his goods according to the list as soon as possible and send them to him.
[Book of Songs]
Yes.
[illuminate Auspicious]
Master passed away suddenly.
Everything is prepared in a rush.
Please forgive us if we didn't serve you well.
When did Minister Feng return to the capital?
What kind of disease caused his sudden death?
Just before the gate closed yesterday, Master entered the capital
and went to the welcome banquet held by his colleagues.
It was a laborious trip and he had a few more drinks
which brought about the terrible disease.
When you get old, you can't neglect your health.
Scholar Xue is right.
That's how our Madam said to Master.
But Master was busy with official duties
and he turned a deaf ear to her words.
I remember that Minister Feng had no sons but three daughters.
Why didn't I see any of them?
Their husbands are talking offices outside the capital.
The three ladies are out there with their husbands.
Master passed away suddenly.
I'm afraid they won't come back until the day when Master is buried.
What about the Second Lady?
Master went to the Southwest for inspections and had been away for long,
he died suddenly just as he came back.
The Second Madam is too sad and she falls sick.
She can't greet guests now.
What's gone is gone. You should comfort her.
Yes.
I'll leave.
Princess. I met Prince An before I left Feng Manor.
Jinyu went to Feng Manor to express condolences?
Yes.
Did he go there alone?
He also brought a girl.
I've asked someone and she is a coroner.
Jinyu brought a coroner to Feng Manor to express condolences?
Go to the Three Judicial Chief Ministries and tell Jinyu
that there is something really important.
- If he doesn't come to me, I'll go to see him.
- Yes.
[Feng Manor]
[Funeral]
Good day, Commandery Prince An, Scholar Xue.
What was that about in the mourning hall?
I have some doubts. I want to know the truth.
Is there anything wrong?
I haven't found it out.
You are getting crazier.
What if the Emperor knows it?
Good day, sir.
Good day, Senior Jing, Vice Minister Jing.
If you have time, come to my mansion and have a simple meal.
Father, forget it. If Commandery Prince An comes to our manor,
Mother will introduce girls to him again.
Just give me a break.
What does it have to do with you
- that your mother introduces girls to Commandery Prince An?
- What does it have to do with me?
The city gate is on fire, disaster is brought to the fish in the moat.
Well... Senior Jing. there have been many trivial matters in the Three Judicial Chief Ministries.
I won't bother you today.
I'll visit Aunt in person some other day.
But I have some official affairs to discuss with Jing Yi.
Can you let Jing Yi go back with me?
Okay.
Be serious about your work with Commandery Prince An.
Otherwise, I'll go back and tell your mother about it.
Senior Jing, don't worry.
I'll leave.
What a tattletale.
At lease you parents are healthy.
[Feng Manor]
Your Highness, I was really scared.
I thought I was going to give myself away.
You really went there to do an autopsy?
Don't you know that?
Then why did you help me out?
Commandery Prince An doesn't attend any wedding or funeral.
He brought a coroner to the funeral this time.
Isn't it obvious?
When the fox preaches, take care of your geese.
(T/N: Proverb that says to be aware about hidden agenda)
Fox?
It's just an inappropriate analogy.
Chu Chu, did you find anything from that quick glance?
There is...
Hold on. It's time for lunch.
Chu Chu, are you hungry?
I'm a little hungry.
I fed the chickens but forgot to feed myself this morning.
Your Highness, considering how hard we tried to help you.
Shouldn't you treat us to a good meal?
No, I'm fine. I am healthy.
It's okay to be hungry for a while.
No way.
Your brain can't work well when you are hungry
and it's easy to forget stuffs. And it's easy to make mistakes when you think.
You are a coroner. Shouldn't you know better than I do?
Okay, let's talk while eating.
What do you want to eat?
[Rugui Tavern]
Vice Minister Jing, please come in.
This is...
This is Commandery Prince An from the Three Judicial Chief Ministries.
I'm Xu Rugui, the owner of Rugui Tavern.
- Greetings to Commandery Prince An.
- You may rise.
Thank you, Your Highness.
[Rugui Tavern]
The same old dishes.
Braised pigeon with soy sauce, seared salamander,
and roast lamb ribs.
Remember, it must be baby lamb.
Don't roast it for too long.
Get us more dipping sauce. I like you nomads' dipping sauce the most.
Rest assured. I got it.
Commandery Prince An, it's your first time to be here,
may I introduce you our specialties?
No need.
I want a flower chicken, a sour fish soup and a houttuynia salad.
Why did Prince An order Qianzhou dishes?
Your Highness, you do know what to eat.
Houttuynia is rare in Chang'an.
Only Rugui Tavern has it.
These three dishes ordered by Commandery Prince An
are all authentic Qianzhou cuisine.
There happens to be a cook from Qianzhou.
I won't say that the cooking is superb,
but this cook can make the authentic Qianzhou taste.
Commandery Prince An, Vice Minister Jing. Please wait for a while.
The dishes will be ready soon.
Wait!
Get this girl a cup of tea.
Forgive me for being clumsy and neglecting this girl.
It's okay.
Sit down.
This man looks strange.
I'll leave.
Are you a regular here?
Not really.
The food is delicious here. But it's too expensive for me.
I won't eat here if no one gives me a treat.
Have you known Feng Jie's death?
[Jiangshan Hall]
Your Majesty. I received an obituary from Feng Manor early in the morning.
I went to Feng Manor to offer my condolences.
Minister Feng passed away just after he came back.
The Feng Manor wasn't prepared at all.
It was hectic when I went there.
I feel really sorry for them.
The Feng Manor wasn't prepared, wasn't I caught off guard?
Now Feng Jie is gone, someone needs to take over the Ministry of War.
You are right, Your Majesty.
It's easy to talk.
Who can take it over?
Since I took the throne,
I've been racking my brains for my country day and night.
Everyone in court is trying to consolidate the power of Great Tang
and restore the prosperity.
How important it is to find a talent.
Do you think it's that easy to appoint a third-rank minister?
Feng Jie is only in his early fifties.
He is even healthier than those military officers.
How did he die in such a sudden?
I heard from Feng's housekeeper that it was a laborious trip to the southwest
and he had a few more drinks at the welcome banquet,
which aroused the terrible disease, leading to his sudden death.
What? He died of drinking?
- Prince An, Vice Minister Jing.
- Please enjoy yourselves.
Miss, please enjoy yourselves.
Feel free to tell me if you need anything else.
I'll leave.
Well? These dishes don't suit your appetite?
No. I just feel that this owner looks...
It's nothing.
It has been a hard day for you.
Go ahead and eat.
Your Highness. Do you also like Qianzhou food?
I never tasted it before.
My older brother is a general stationed in the Southwest.
He mentioned these Qianzhou dishes before.
Qianzhou is a thousand miles away from Chang'an.
You have left home at least for one month.
You haven't had your hometown food for some time, right?
You ordered these dishes for me?
I treat you two to a meal, of course, I should order dishes for you two.
But, Your Highness,
I haven't found the cause of his death.
It doesn't matter.
Fill your stomach first.
Come on, give me the bowl.
Thank you, Your Highness.
It should be true that she was born in Qianzhou.
Chu Chu, are these Qianzhou dishes authentic?
Yeah, they are really authentic.
I'm glad you enjoy them.
Take your time. Don't feel restrained.
Thank you, Your highness.
Did you find anything in the mourning hall of the Feng Manor?
There are several obvious injuries on Feng Jie's chest.
But those are not to hurt him. But to save him.
Save him? How to save him?
Can I show it to you in person?
You pretend to be Feng Jie. I'll be the one to save him.
Okay.
- What are you doing?
- I'm showing it to you.
Minister Feng should be dead now.
You need to relax and lie down with your eyes closed.
You can't move no matter what I do to you.
That should be how Minister Feng got those scratches.
Timing and subtitles brought to you by The Imperial Coroners @ Viki.com
Nothing can stop me
From missing you all the time
The moonlight appears, cold in the late night,
as the world changes
Only with you by my side can I embrace my yearning for you
When I close my eyes I meet you once again
I'll gently brush your hair by your ear
Life is long, with love and regrets in this world
With you by my side, no matter how far I go,
we'll never be apart
With your smile, in this moment, let me
cherish this lifetime
Only for you, I have to worry about the end of this life
Im still young, with my love not yet realized for you, but I'm
willing to be here for you till the end
You can rely on me in this lifetime
Hope to spend this beautiful lifetime together