Timing and subtitles brought to you by The Imperial Coroners @ Viki.com
Why are there so many strange things in Chang'an?
Prince An really looks like the Handsome Judge.
But there is no scar on him.
Minister Feng also died in a strange way.
Even the owner of the restaurant is unspeakably strange.
The owner asked me to bring you some beauties...
and some fruits.
Put it there.
Chu Chu, watch your demeanor.
If you want to take advantage of His Highness,
you won't just be fined.
I... I didn't want to take advantage of him. I was saving him.
Save him? You almost scared him to death.
There are people who are still alive when their hearts stop beating.
It can make the heart beat again in this way.
Many physicians know it.
But it's just that it doesn't work every time.
So, few physicians dare to use it.
They are afraid of being accused of killing the patients.
[The Imperial Coroner]
[Episode 4]
[Jiangshan Hall]
If all the officials of Great Tang become Wine Immortals like Li Bai,
what should the court do? What should the country do?
What should the people do?
To count on me alone?
Your Majesty, please calm your anger.
Go to draft an edict now.
The seventh-rank officials or above in the capital
are not allowed to gather and drink on non-holiday occasions.
Those who break the rule will be dismissed and severely punished.
Yes, Your Majesty.
Your Majesty, what about the canonization of Feng Jie...
Let's talk about it later.
By the way, go back and tell your precious student.
He caught the murderer before the deadline
and Yan Ming's case can be closed.
But he should handle his social relations properly.
He has to do it even he fakes it.
Ask him to go to Feng Manor and offer his condolences.
Tell him this is an imperial edict.
Your Majesty,  Prince An has offered his condolences to Feng Manor.
He did?
I dare not deceive Your Majesty.
When the morning court ended,
Senior Jing and I went to Feng Manor
and we ran into Prince An.
Go ahead. Hurry up.
You are saying there was a physician who saved him like that?
Based on the bruise and the scratches,
it should be a female physician.
A female physician...
I got it.
The family of Feng Jie's second wife runs a medical clinic.
I found it weird when I was in Feng Manor.
Housekeeper Feng seemed suspicious when he mentioned the Second Lady.
He must be hiding something.
Your Highness, have you noticed what Madam Feng said?
Chu Chu said that when ashes fall on the deceased,
it means the dead soul is protesting an injustice.
Then Madam Feng immediately said "don't slander our Master".
Slander?
Chu Chu meant an injustice was done. Why would she call it slander?
What do you think?
I wasn't thinking of anything.
But when I saw you two...
Doing that... I had a thought.
I think Feng Jie indulged himself too much and died under a skirt.
It must be like this last night.
Feng Jie drank too much at the welcome banquet.
The Second Lady accompanied him home.
When they were doing it, Feng Jie suddenly fell ill.
Second Lady has little medical skills and tried to save him, but she failed.
The Feng Manor worried that his cause of death would bring them shame.
So they said Feng Jie died of a sudden illness.
The Feng family wants to cover the disgrace up.
That's why when Chu Chu said that the deceased was wronged,
Madam Feng blurted out the word, "slander".
Chu Chu, what do you think of Jing Yi's analysis?
I don't know.
That's not enough to explain how he died.
But I can tell that Minister Feng was healthy and strong.
He didn't drink too much before he died.
At least he didn't die of drinking.
As for whether he died under a skirt just like Lord Jing said,
I need a thorough autopsy before I can know it.
What autopsy do you need?
Feng Jie died at his home, not in a brothel.
It's not wrong to say that he died of a sudden illness, right?
Why take it so seriously?
No one will look good if we reveal the true cause of his death.
And you will be blamed for it.
Your Highness, when I looked at Minister Feng,
I felt that he had a lot to say to me.
- He had a lot to say to you?
- Yes.
Everyone has something to say before they die.
It's just that some people have time to say it,
and some people don't.
Those who don't will leave these words on their bodies.
Some words are said through the scars.
Some are said through the posture.
Some are said through their relationships with other people.
The coroner's job is to interpret these words
to those who are alive.
Who told you that?
Did the Handsome Judge said that?
Yes, he said that.
Have you also heard of it?
It's also written in Father's personal letter.
How did she know it?
- I once read it in a book.
- Which book?
Is it the Legend of the Nine Constables in Six Gates?
- What legend?
- The Legend of the Nine Constables in Six Gates.
It was in this book that I read about Six Gates and the Handsome Judge.
Did you also read that book?
Is there any copy of this legend?
Yes, it's in my bag.
If you want to read it, I'll give it to you once I return to the Three Judicial Chief Ministries.
Okay.
Chu Chu, are you willing to check Minister Feng's body again?
- I can examine it?
- You can.
Again?
Really? That's great.
Thank you, Your Highness.
I should thank you.
Let's eat.
A few days ago, you said
that the Emperor set a time limit for Prince An to solve a case.
Today is the deadline.
Has the case been solved?
Kind of.
Don't be ambiguous.
What do you mean kind of?
The murderer was arrested.
But she committed suicide in the prison of the Court of Judicial Review.
- The prison of the Court of Judicial Review?
- Yes.
Then our son...
Did you lie to me?
He didn't come back for a meal today.
Did the Emperor ask him to stay and want to punish him?
Madam, when did I lie to you?
Jing Yi is fine.
Didn't Prince An take the blame
for whatever mistakes they made in the Three Judicial Chief Ministries?
When did you hear that
he pushed out his subordinates and let them take the blame?
Is Commandery Prince An okay?
He is fine.
Han Ji and his fellows spoke ill of him.
What then?
Those who don't work speak ill of those who work.
I think Han Ji and his fellows are just useless ducks.
They only quack all day.
Did you speak up for Prince An?
Yes, I did.
Madam, don't worry. It's over now.
By the way,
I heard that Prince An went to Feng Manor yesterday to express condolences.
Did he bring a maid with him?
It's not a maid, but a coroner.
- A coroner?
- Yes.
Did Prince An really let a girl pass the test?
I don't know if she passed.
But he is definitely interested in her.
Your Highness, you are finally back.
[Two Merits Hall]
Did Mother send someone here again?
What? How did you know that?
Wu Jiang, you have been serving Prince An for so long.
Don't you know that he has a third eye?
Your Highness, Aunt Banxia said
the Princess asked you to see her as soon as you come back.
Otherwise, she will come to see you.
Did Leng Yue reply?
Not yet.
Leng Yue? What happened to Leng Yue?
- Send someone to rush her.
- Yes.
Leng Yue is back?
Your Highness. Your Highness.
Your Highness, tell me about it.
Your Highness!
Your Highness. Tell me about it. Tell me.
You've had the meal and the tea.
Your tongue is glibber now.
Don't you have something to report to me?
Yes.
You were right.
There is such a person in the Shen Army.
Last night he suddenly asked for leave to go home.
There is no trace of him.
This is the military record. His physical features are in it.
Your Highness,
last night, you asked me to investigate it this morning.
You also took the morning court off for me.
You are taking the blame
for the dancer's suicide, aren't you?
It was my fault for being careless. It's what I should do.
But I interrogated her.
I asked you to do it.
You are even tougher than my father.
I would take being beaten one hundred times by him over what you've done.
How should I pay you back? By marrying you?
You'd better serve me.
Looks like it is Qin Luan who wants to catch Chu Chu.
But why does he want to catch Chu Chu?
Nothing good will happen if being targeted by these eunuchs.
What about being targeted by you?
What do you want to say?
I'm saying...
you are not just curious about Feng Jie's death, right?
Are you interrogating me?
Not at all. I won't ask you anymore.
Pretend that you are interrogating me, think about it,
is there no clue?
Clue...
Over the past one month, Feng Jie is the third official
who died mysteriously in the capital.
The third official who died in less than a month...
But they died in public.
In public, people still can get killed.
Just as fatal diseases don't always have obvious symptoms at first.
The most vicious killers might be hiding
behind the seemingly ordinary deaths.
If we don't find it out soon, the consequences can be disastrous.
Your Highness, his family members said nothing.
Why do you keep looking into it?
You should use the time to get more sleep.
Look at your red eyes.
By the way, I've interrogated the three tomb robbers.
They confessed everything.
I made a list and sent my men to arrest the people on the list.
Three or five days later, the grave robbers in the capital
can have a party in prison.
Your Highness, Qin Luan came.
What is he doing here?
He said he came to announce the Emperor's verbal edict.
He insists on coming in. He should be at the gate now.
It won't be a good thing.
Jing Yi, are the three grave robbers still in the prison?
Yes. Go to the Court of the Judicial Review's prison for me.
Give them a chance to atone for their crime.
Atone for their crime?
Do you want to dig out the two buried capital officials and do an autopsy again?
Be careful and leave from behind.
Don't let Qin Luan see you.
Rest assured.
You...!
[Two Merits Hall]
You nasty minions. Damn!
Commandery Prince An has arrived!
Eunuch Qin.
Your Highness.
Take a look.
I'm here to announce the Emperor's oral message.
Take a look. They won't even let me in.
Your Three Judicial Chief Ministries is well guarded indeed.
Not really.
It's just a place to store the case files.
Unauthorized people are not allowed in.
Am I also unauthorized?
Fine, fine.
Commandery Prince An, today you brought a coroner to Feng Manor and desecrated
the body of the Minister of War, Feng Jie, in the name of mourning.
The Feng family has told the Emperor about what you did.
Here is the imperial verbal edict.
Commandery Prince An, Xiao Jinyu, is ordered
to apologize to the Feng family in person.
If he disturbs the burial of Minister Feng again,
he will be severely punished.
Commandery Prince An, I hope you know what you are doing.
Let's go.
It's rare for Qin Luan to do something good.
Now we have a reason to visit Feng Manor again.
Master.
I've delivered it.
You are...
The Emperor gave an order
to send these things to Feng Manor.
Master.
Okay, go.
- Let's go.
I've checked the female coroner from the Southwest.
This female coroner is from Pingle Town, Guanling County, Qianzhou.
However, her mother has passed away for years
when this female coroner was born.
What did you say?
When she was born, her mother had been dead for years?
Did she pop out from her mother's grave?
That's what is weird.
This female coroner's father is called Chu Ping.
It's ascertained that he only married one woman.
His wife died when she gave birth to his eldest son, Chu He.
In the tenth year of Taihe, he somehow had a daughter,
which is this female coroner.
Xiao Heng died in the Southwest and no one has seen his body.
Less than a year later, a coroner's family in Southwest
somehow had a daughter.
Now, this daughter came to Chang'an with Xiao Heng's relics.
How can there be such a coincidence in the world?
In this case,
could she be a bastard daughter of Xiao Heng?
Are you asking me?
Master, calm your anger. I'll go to find it out.
Get away! Yes.
Your Highness, Miss Chu presents herself.
Let her in. Yes.
Your Highness, you are back.
This is the Legend of the Nine Constables in Six Gates.
It's all here.
Thank you.
[When someone dies, the coroner goes to the land...]
Did you write it?
No, I heard of these stories from other people.
I didn't write these stories.
I mean the handwriting.
Yes.
How do you recognize my handwriting?
I read your exam application form.
So I can recognize your handwriting.
You remember it just with one glance?
That's amazing!
Your Highness,
when can I check Minister Feng's again?
Your Highness.
Come in.
Your Highness, Jing Yi is back.
Let's forget about Feng Jie now.
I have two bodies that I need you to check.
No problem.
Do I need to dress up as a maid this time?
No need. You'll do it here.
Get down.
- Your Highness.
Your Highness, it has been done according to your instructions.
No one will find out these two tombs are already empty.
You know what, the craftsmanship of these three bumpkins
is pretty amazing.
No, it's outrageous.
Outrageous!
Where are the bodies?
In the autopsy room with the coffins.
Okay.
Send them to the interrogation room first and give them some food.
Find some people to keep an eye on them.
After Chu Chu finishes, ask them to take the coffins back to where they were.
Yes.
Move.
Is there an autopsy room and an interrogation room?
- What's wrong?
- Is there a place to store the evidence of the pending case
and a place to do all kinds of analysis and research?
How do you know that?
I heard of it. That's the house of the Handsome Judge.
He built a yard at his house.
There is an autopsy room, an interrogation room,
a place to store the evidence of the pending cases,
and a place to do analysis and research.
It's just like...
It's just like this place.
Are you the Handsome Judge?
You must be the Handsome Judge!
How old were you when you first heard about these things?
Six.
When you were six, I was also a child.
Even though I'm talented,
there is no way I could build a yard for myself.
Right.
But...
Your house...
This house was built in the last two years.
It's just a coincidence.
How can there be so many coincidences?
Guards.
Yes.
Take Miss Chu to the autopsy room.
Yes. Miss Chu, please.
Is this the legend of the constables?
This is not a legend at all.
Wu Jiang.
- Your Highness.
- Ask Lian Qiao to send some clothes to her
and find a chance to take her pass.
But she needs the pass to leave Chang'an.
Got it, Your Highness.
There is a strike injury in the left eye socket.
There is a bruise on the right side in the back of the head, and it's swollen.
Well... Your Highness, I still don't get it.
What does this mean?
These stories are all adapted from the cases my father worked on.
Your father's cases...
Are you sure?
I know the files of every case he worked on by heart.
Jing Yi.
If I remember it correctly,
apart from me and my father, there is only one person
who is familiar with these cases.
My father?
You are suspecting that Chu Chu works for my father?
I swear with my father's salary of this year.
I met Chu Chu at the gate of Chang'an.
I've told you everything.
You can verify it if you don't believe me.
There were a lot of people on the street. And the caravan.
- All of them can testify.
- Take it easy.
I'm just sorting out all the possibilities.
This is really impossible.
Your Highness, my father is skilled in
planting his people in all kinds of places.
How would he send someone with a suspicious identity?
Secondly, you've been avoiding women.
My mother knows it better than anyone else.
Even if my father wants to plant a coroner by your side,
he wouldn't find a girl.
Thirdly, this girl is pretty silly.
She is not like someone who can work for the Jing family.
Your Highness.
Have you finished it?
Your Highness, can I ask you a question first?
Go ahead.
Do these two deceased have any relationship with Minister Feng?
Why do you ask that?
When I looked at Minister Feng today,
I found an injury on his right brow bone.
It's a strike injury.
Generally speaking, this kind of injury isn't enough to kill anyone.
And medicine had been used on that injury before he died.
When I checked those two dead men,
I found the same injury in the same place on their heads.
Do you know how they got that injury?
It's not one injury, but two.
Two injuries?
One in the front, one in the back.
I'm not sure how they got it.
But I can give it a try.
Pretend that I am the killer and you are the dead?
Is it okay?
I'll be the dead man who fell into the water.
He had the fewest injuries and is the easiest to tell.
Okay.
There is a strike injury inside the right arm.
It should be caused by a punch.
There is a bruise on the left shoulder blade
which is caused by hitting a smooth hard object.
There is a bruise on the right forearm near the wrist bone.
There is also a strike injury on the left eye socket
and an injury by collision on the right back of the head.
You are...
fighting?
In this case, they all fought with someone before they died?
And the person who fought with them intentionally hit them on the face
in the same place?
That's impossible.
Feng Jie is a third-rank minister in his fifties.
Who could he fight with?
What's more, Liu Yue, the Minister of Revenue, fell off the horse
and many people saw it and later died.
He might get the injury on his head from falling off the horse.
No, it can't be.
The injury on his head was made earlier than his injury from falling off the horse.
No medicine was used on it. He didn't get it in a fall.
And eye sockets are sunken inward.
They are the lowest places on the face.
Even if he fell on his face, it was hard to hit his eye sockets.
I said before that the injury in his eye socket
was caused by a punch, instead of hitting the ground.
You are saying
that punch in the face was the fatal injury for the three of them?
No, that's not what I'm saying.
I am saying the three of them all have two similar injuries
in about the same places on their heads.
Based on their stature and injuries,
it should be the same person who injured them.
However, I'm still not sure whether they died of the injury.
It can't be.
There are many people who saw Liu Yue fall off the horse and die.
I heard that there was a group of people riding horses and hunting on that day.
They were chasing a rabbit with their bows.
[Broken leg bone]
[Bone of the left leg]
His left leg and ribs were fractured.
[Ribs Rib fracture]
There was a nosebleed which should be caused by a nose bridge injury.
[Nose bridge bones Strike injury]
Lord! Lord! Help! Hurry up.
Didn't his fall caused by his death?
- Hurry.
- Lord! Lord!
No. For those who fall to their death, their internal organs would be broken.
There will be blood coming out from mouth, eyes, ears and nose.
But this man only had a nosebleed.
His organs were fine.
The injuries on his body are not enough to get him killed.
As for the short deceased man, there is river mud
in his ear canal and nasal canal.
I think he fell into the river before he died.
Good wine. Lord, be careful.
Go away!
Lord, be careful.
I can do it.
Lord! Lord!
Hurry! Hurry!
Come on!
Lord! Lord!
These people failed to save him.
But he wasn't drowned or choked to death by water.
I'm not sure the cause of his death.
If I can check Minister Feng's body again,
I might be able to know the cause of their deaths.
Since the injuries are the same,
why can you only know it through Feng Jie?
These two men have been dead for a while.
Although it looks like they haven't rotten much yet,
there are some things I can't identify anymore.
Especially the things in the head.
The things in the head?
What is that?
I'm not sure what it is.
I can't tell you now.
You...
How long will it take you to do an autopsy for Feng Jie?
- One hour.
-  I can only give you half an hour.
Okay.
But, I need to prepare something in advance this time.
[Princess Xiping Manor]
Leng Yue?
That's right.
Leng Yue grew up in your manor.
You know her temperament best.
She loves to talk and laugh.
Wherever she is, that place is always lively.
Among your two sons,
Commandery Prince An is knowledgeable and reliable.
General Xiao is heroic and gallant.
They have come to the age to get married.
Have you ever thought about
who should marry Miss Leng Yue?
I've never thought about them
in that way.
Your Highness.
You should.
Miss Leng Yue is beautiful and she comes from a prominent family.
If someone else marries her,
I'm afraid you would regret it.
It would be a pity if she marries into an ordinary family.
But if your Jing Yi marries her,
I would be very happy.
Jing Yi?
Don't flatter him.
You know that they grew up together since childhood.
Miss Leng Yue listens to Commandery Prince An for everything.
Maybe her heart has belonged to Prince An.
With their childhood friendship, it's just a matter of time
for them to be together.
But we are not her parents.
She doesn't have her parents anymore.
No matter what she thinks,
we should ask her grandfather first, right?
But with my uncle's temperament...
Never mind, it's too early to talk about this now.
[Funeral]
Fortunately, the eunuch from the Palace warned me today,
otherwise, I would be fooled by the Commandery Prince An.
Although the Emperor issued a verbal edict and forbade him to keep looking into it,
I still can't rest assured.
General Zhou. How much does Eunuch Qin hate Minister Feng?
Why did he ask us to destroy his body?
That's not for you to ask.
If other people know that Master died under a skirt,
his reputation will be ruined.
Madam, don't worry.
Although Commandery Prince An came, he didn't ask anything, right?
That coroner is just a little girl.
I guess she is a novice and she couldn't find out anything.
I can't stop worrying it
until Master gets buried.
Madam, if you are worried, why don't we bury Master in advance?
You are right. Let's not wait for twenty-one days.
Tomorrow, find a Taoist who can perform the religious rite.
Tell him we want to bury Master after the first seven days.
Yes.
Keep an eye on them. We will do it as soon as Madam Feng leaves.
It's getting late.
Tomorrow morning, Master's relatives and friends will come to offer condolences.
You should go back and rest earlier.
Is the Second Madam sleeping now?
The Second Madam took a medicine.
She is sleeping now.
She can still fall asleep now.
- Madam. Commandery Prince An came with that coroner again.
- Madam.
What is he doing here in the middle of the night?
Madam, why don't you go back to your room and rest?
I'll sound him out for you.
Never mind.
If he found out something, it's useless to hide it.
Serve some tea to Commandery Prince An.
Ask him to wait at the side hall.
Yes, Madam.
Commandery Prince An?
Is he here in the middle of the night to do an autopsy?
I'm going to tell Eunuch Qin.
Tell what?
You are seeking your death if you tell him now.
Let's wait and see.
Madam.
Your Highness.
You may rise.
I was being suspicious in the day and I offended Minister Feng's body.
The Emperor reprimanded me and I feel bad about it.
I can't wait to apologize to you. So I came here at night.
Please forgive me, Madam Feng.
Don't say that. It's not that serious.
I'm just a woman.
Such a tragedy happened in a sudden, I panicked
and talked nonsense to the people from the Palace.
I wasn't expecting you to be reprimanded by the Emperor.
It's my fault.
You are very generous to not blame me.
Please allow my maid to offer a joss stick to Minister Feng's spirit
to apologize for our offense today.
Steward Xu, get the joss stick from Commandery Prince An
and offer it before Master's spirit.
Yes.
We are here to apologize.
How can we let you do it for me?
If you mind my maid's inferiority, I can offer the joss stick in person.
I dare not. We dare not let you do that.
Steward Xu, take this girl there.
Yes.
Miss, please.
Master...
This way, please.
Madam Feng, did Minister Feng say anything when he came back last night?
Minister Feng went to the Southwest to inspect military affairs.
He was away for more than a month.
He must miss you a lot.
He was even drunk late at night,
he should also come to see you.
He was taken to the Second Madam's room as soon as he came back last night.
When I saw him, he was...
Madam, did the person who served Minister Feng last night
mention how he got the injury on his head?
Minister Han took his back last night.
He said that Master got drunk and accidentally hit something.
Minister Han?
Yes.
Why do you ask that?
Nothing.
It's just that Minister Feng passed away so sudden.
It's still hard for me to believe it.
Since Minister Feng was injured,
did the person who was serving him get a physician here?
The Second Madam's family runs a medical clinic.
She knows a little about medicine.
When Master had a minor injury or illness, he would go to see her.
He never saw any physician.
Is the cause of Minister Feng's death also diagnosed by the Second Madam?
Steward Xu has been away for some time.
Why hasn't he come back?
Get someone to take a look.
Don't offend Commandery Prince An's people.
Yes ma'am.
Madam, have you counted the belongings
Minister Feng brought back from the Southwest?
His belongings?
Minister Feng hadn't reported on
the inspection of military affairs in the Southwest.
There will be officials coming to take it over in a few days.
You'd better count his belongings and keep them safe.
Who is that?
Who went down?
No one, General Zhou. We are all here.
What are you waiting for? Get him!
Get him?
Listen, if anyone disturbs Commandery Prince An,
everyone in Feng Manor won't get away with it!
Yes... yes.
You, come with me!
Yes, sir.
Hurry up! Don't let the thief run away!
General Wu, what's wrong with you?
I have a stomachache.
Where is the lavatory here?
Go out and turn left...
The Feng Manor is too big. I can't find it.
- Take me there.
- But...
I'll crap my pants if you keep saying but.
Let's go. Come on.
This way.
My stomach...
[Funeral]
Not good. The coroner is inside.
She wants to do an autopsy.
Coroner?
Doesn't Eunuch Qin want to capture this coroner alive?
Why don't we go down and take her away now?
Xiao Jinyu is in the side hall right now.
If we fail to take her away, then she cries for help
and makes some noise, none of us can get out of here.
Do what I say.
Set a fire and burn the corpse and the coroner. Hurry up!
Okay!
Hurry!
Get him!
- He is over there!
- Chu Chu, you'd better hurry up.
Get him!
Okay!
General Wu?
Fire!
Stop chasing him, go to put out the fire!
Fire! Fire!
Open the door! Open the door!
Timing and subtitles brought to you by The Imperial Coroners @ Viki.com
Nothing can stop me
From missing you all the time
The moonlight appears, cold in the late night,
as the world changes
Only with you by my side can I embrace my yearning for you
When I close my eyes I meet you once again
I'll gently brush your hair by your ear
Life is long, with love and regrets in this world
With you by my side, no matter how far I go,
we'll never be apart
With your smile, in this moment, let me
cherish this lifetime
Only for you, I have to worry about the end of this life
Im still young, with my love not yet realized for you, but I'm
willing to be here for you till the end
You can rely on me in this lifetime
Hope to spend this beautiful lifetime together