Timing and subtitles brought to you by The Imperial Coroners @ Viki.com
Since the Coroner Qualification Exam,
I've done several autopsies for Commandery Prince An.
But I still failed the exam.
Vice Minister Jing was right.
Commandery Prince An seems to want me to stay.
Although he said he is not the Handsome Judge,
he is really scrupulous and chary.
None of the Shen Army's tricks escaped his eyes.
He strictly enforces the law and doesn't bow to power.
He is exactly the same as the Handsome Judge
in the Legend of the Nine Constables in Six Gates.
What's happening here?
It was you who came up with that title?
I was just joking.
There was no one else around when I said that.
If anyone knows about this, it can only be Prince Consort himself.
Could it be...
Could it be that Prince Consort is still alive
and he is in Qianzhou now?
I thought about whether Prince Consort is behind this girl.
But I got news from the Southwest
that the witch doctor who turned Prince Consort's cases into stories
was living in Pingle Town, Guanling County, Qianzhou.
Maybe it was because of some serious injuries,
he had trouble moving around for years.
Five years ago, he left his home.
Since then, he went missing.
How would a person who had trouble moving around suddenly went missing?
He didn't have many friends in Pingle Town.
The only people who were close to him were the Chu family members.
If no one from the Chu family knows it, then no one else would know it.
[The Imperial Coroner]
[Episode 9]
There should be another reason
for Commandery Prince An to go to Qianzhou.
I'm afraid something went wrong in Qianzhou.
What Feng Jie, Liu Yue, Lu Chuansheng were dealing with
is more or less related to Qianzhou.
But what's the relation between the dancing girl and Qianzhou?
Although aconitine grows in many places,
the variety and toxicity vary in different places.
I've checked it. The aconitine used by the dancing girl to commit suicide
is made in an ancient method in Qianzhou.
There are still some doubts about the case of Yan Ming.
I'll tell you about it after I verify it.
Now everything is related to Qianzhou, it cannot be a coincidence.
I'm afraid something concerning the country will happen in the Southwest.
Concerning the country?
What else did he say?
It seems to get more troublesome.
Do I have to go?
You have to go to the Southwest this time.
Besides what you need to do for Commandery Prince An,
I also have something for you to do.
Your Highness, are you all right?
I'm fine.
Your Highness.
Take these people back and find out who they are.
Yes!
I didn't expect that someone dares to assassinate you in Chang'an.
It isn't long since we met last time.
You got better at making enemies.
It's getting late.
You should go to Princess Xiping's Mansion.
If my mother asks about it...
Rest assured. I know how to make up a story. I'm leaving.
Hold on.
Are you not asking me why?
I've been doing what you told me to do since I was a child.
I don't care about the reason. You won't screw me up anyway.
Commandery Prince An likes pretty girls.
Then I'll show him a pretty girl.
This should be catering to his pleasure.
I can even fix a rotten face.
How hard can it be to fix my face?
[See the Wind and Listen to the Rain]
Miss Chu. Miss Chu.
General Wu, what's the matter?
I found your pass in that inn.
I guess you accidentally dropped it there.
You found it? Great.
Thank you, General Wu.
I've brought the pass.
Miss Chu, open the door.
I'm not quite dressed yet.
Why don't you put it at the door and place a stone on it?
I'll come out and get it later.
Thank you, General Wu.
By the way, Commandery Prince An brought back what you left in Feng's manor last night.
I'll also leave it here for you.
Really? That's great.
Thank you, General Wu.
[Pass]
By the way, General Wu.
Did Commandery Prince An see the autopsy result?
Yes, he did.
Did he say anything?
His Highness said that you are a rare good coroner.
Really? Did he really say that?
I dare not make up what His Highness said.
That's great.
General Wu, has he come back?
He should be on his way back.
If you want to see Commandery Prince An,
I'll tell him for you when he comes back.
Thank you, General Wu.
Your Highness. We've carefully checked the eight corpses.
They are not from the Shen Army.
They are all death row inmates with marks on their faces.
We haven't found out which prison they escaped from.
It's Qin Luan indeed.
Qin Luan?
It was a eunuch from the Palace to offer condolence
who exposed the identity of Chu Chu to the Feng family
and encouraged them to tell the Emperor on me
so as to prevent me from investigating the cause of Feng Jie's death.
It was the people from Shence Army who set a fire at the mourning hall
and tried to burn up the corpse.
It was also the people from Shence Army who fooled the guards at the gate
and sent Xu Rugui out of Chang'an.
Except Qin Luan, there is no one else in Court
who can order both parties.
So the person who is behind Rugui Tarven is Qin Luan.
You knew that this eunuch holds grudges.
So you went with it and locked down
the Shen Army in the name of plague,
forcing Qin Luan to use other forces to tackle you and proved your speculation.
No.
Today I asked the Emperor to allow me to leave Chang'an tomorrow.
If he wants to kill me, he has to do it tonight.
In such a short time, he had no choice but to use his reserve force that is hard to find out in normal days.
Although he has been living in the palace,
there are only a few kinds of people he can buy off,
I still can't rest assured to leave without finding it out myself.
Based on the current situation,
The Rugui Tarven isn't a determinant of Qin Luan's power.
It's not the most important thing to find evidence and prove my speculation.
What matters is my mother's safety after I left.
Memorize the contents of these papers, then burn them.
After I leave, you must do what's written in the letter in person.
Remember, you must be really careful.
Any news you have can't be passed to others.
[Keep an eye on all the parties]
Send a letter directly to me.
Your Highness. Are you not taking me to the Southwest?
How can I not worry about it?
The Southwest is not Chang'an, Your Highness.
Not to mention you will take that suspicious Chu Chu with you.
Did she act suspiciously tonight?
No.
After Miss Chu finished dinner, she has been staying in Liutao Office and doesn't come out.
- But...
- No matter why she came here,
she has no interest in my life.
I've given her many chances.
If she wants to kill me,
she would have made a move a long time ago.
Qin Luan failed to kill me tonight.
He will take action again.
Find some reliable people to protect my mother in secret.
Besides, after I leave Chang'an, the case files and items here will be coveted by someone.
These stuffs also need to be guarded well, as well as the contents in the papers.
If you don't stay in Chang'an,
I can't leave without worrying about them.
Your Highness, rest assured.
I'll take care of these things in Chang'an
and wait for you to return safely.
[See the Wind and Listen to the Rain]
Chu Chu.
Your Highness.
She is...
The way he looks at me is different.
Her look...
You...
He should like it.
Are you studying to dress up the corpse?
Dress up the corpse?
No.
How can you try it on yourself?
I...
Wash your face first before we talk.
I mean,
they said that I am impatient.
After you come back, I'm not the most impatient person.
That Sun Mingde is hateful indeed.
You asked for a reward from the Emperor
to let him lead a horse for you.
Be careful that he will retaliate against you.
Even he wants to retaliate against me, will I fear a eunuch?
You are in Chang'an now.
We are under the Emperor's watch and you don't need to worry about it.
But if you leave Chang'an,
you must be careful about everything.
I just came back. I'm not going to leave.
I want you to leave.
Where do you want me to go, Auntie?
Qianzhou, the Southwest.
You are good-for-nothing.
Master, calm your anger.
Although we missed it and didn't kill Xiao Jinyu this time,
it was still a demoralizing blow for him.
How is that a demoralizing blow?
Wise like you, Master. Think about it.
Who dares to blatantly assassinate Xiao Jinyu in the imperial city?
No one but you.
How awe-inspiring you are.
That's a glorious defeat.
Get away!
Are you afraid that Xiao Jinyu won't find it out it was me?
Who did you learn from?
How can you be that stupid?
I learned from you...
No, no... I...
I thought myself.
Thanks to Xu Rugui.
Xu Rugui... Xu Rugui was thrown out of Chang'an by Xiao Jinyu.
I do better than he does.
Master, I'm stupid.
Please enlighten me.
Order Xu Rugui to head for Qianzhou immediately.
You want him to go to Qianzhou?
Qianzhou is his hometown.
He couldn't be more familiar with the people and the environment there.
We can't kill Xiao Jinyu in Chang'an.
But in the place with those wild bandits and thieves,
it's not up to him anymore.
Master, what about the female coroner?
Xiao Jinyu keeps a close eye on her.
It's hard to get her.
Ask Xu Rugui to take her together.
Don't tell him too much about it.
Just ask him to bring her alive to see me.
Yes.
Wu Jiang said you want to see me.
What's the matter?
I was going to show you my...
My skill to dress up the corpse
and see if you like it.
That's it?
I have something for you.
This is...
This is a mirror.
Look. One side of it is convex.
The other side is concave.
The convex side can provide a wider field of view.
The concave side can magnify small things.
I named it as the universe mirror.
Universe mirror...
Make big mirrors flat. Make small mirrors convex.
There is such a rule in the ancient method of making mirrors.
You are quite creative.
But why are you giving me this?
Now you have this universe mirror, you don't need to go into places without windows.
You can use it to look inside the room at the door.
Thanks.
Do you like it?
Yes.
That's great. But you don't need to thank me.
I just put some effort.
I used your ladle to make this mirror.
My ladle?
Miss Chu, what are you doing?
I want to make a mirror.
Make a mirror with this?
I bet you don't have such a mirror in the Three Judicial Offices.
This mirror is made with a ladle.
By the way, the stone used to polish the mirror was picked up in your backyard.
Chu Chu, please keep the secret for me
that I can't enter a place without a window.
I know.
I won't tell anyone about it.
Your Highness, if you don't believe me,
we can pinky swear.
I pinky swear and keep it for a hundred year.
All right, rest assured.
Today you asked me about the exam result.
I didn't finish my words.
What?
In terms of the criteria I set for the selection,
no one passed the exam.
But right now, what I need the coroner to do is slightly different from before.
I can make some adjustments. You can try again.
Really? Can I take the exam again?
When and where?
I will leave for Qianzhou tomorrow to solve a case.
Would you like to go with me?
Qianzhou?
I remember it.
The shopkeeper who escaped is from Qianzhou.
Your Highness, are you going to catch him?
You can say that.
You will go to Qianzhou with me, and I will test you along the way.
If you pass it, I'll keep you in Chang'an to work for me.
If you fail again, I can also verify your identity in Qianzhou.
If there is nothing wrong with your identity, you will be reviewed and rated.
Going with me can also save you the expenses of going back home.
Are you willing to go with me?
Yes, I do.
But, what's the exam like?
How can I pass it?
It's up to me to decide.
You only need to do it as usual and wait for the result.
Okay, I'll do well.
[Antique Store]
[Book of Songs]
[Xiao heads for Qianzhou. Be careful.]
[Travel on an Autumn Day in the Mountain...]
Servants.
Master.
Send it to Qianzhou immediately.
Yes.
[Xiao heads for Qianzhou. Be careful.]
Fortunately, I didn't miss you.
Are you here to send me off?
Wake up from your dream.
Is that for me?
Go away.
Auntie asked me to come.
What's the matter?
She asked me to go to Qianzhou with you.
Do you want to come with us?
There is always a way out indeed.
What are you talking about?
Why are you going to Qianzhou with us?
I can do whatever he can do.
- Childish.
- How am I childish?
I'm more mature than him.
Besides, last night...
What's wrong?
I promised my auntie.
I can't break my promise.
Haven't you always refused to set foot in Qianzhou?
It's different this time.
Your Highness, I think we should let Leng Yue come with us.
Leng Yue has more experience being out there.
She might be able to save a lot of trouble for us.
Moreover, Miss Chu will have a companion in this way.
They can take care of each other.
Yes, just leave Miss Chu to me.
I'll take good care of her.
All right.
But I have something to say first.
If you want to come with me,
you need to take your temper down a notch
and follow my instructions all the time.
You can't fight as you want.
Okay, I'll listen to you.
Let's go.
Tell me. What happened
in that year?
Where have you been
all these years?
If Jinyu finds you,
please come back with him.
You must come back with him.
[Jiangshan Hall]
Soldiers, money, and news are all abnormal.
They all gather in the Southwest.
If I may be so bold, this buyer is up to something big.
I'm afraid it might jeopardize the stability of the Southwest of Great Tang.
The Southwest...
The last upheaval in the Southwest was in the Wenzong Dynasty.
The eunuchs were in great power and intervened in politics.
They controlled the Emperor and ruled the world.
The Prince Consort, Princess Xiping's husband, Xiao Heng
went to investigate the Military Commissioner of Jiannan, Chen Ying.
The head of the eunuchs, Qin Luan took the Shen Army to the Southwest
in the name of cracking down Chen Ying and supporting Xiao Heng.
But Xiao Heng never returned.
No one has ever seen him after that.
I don't know what happened exactly.
The eunuchs are no longer in power.
The Palace Domestic Service is under my watch.
I don't need to control them too tightly.
I've been makings all day long,
trying to balance the ministers and the eunuchs.
What I want is just to restore the prosperity
and make Great Tang flourishing again.
Your Majesty.
I've bought you what you wanted.
Your Majesty... mercy!
Mercy!
That's what you got?
Get up.
This is the sword of our famous founding member, Duke Li Jing.
It's normal that you are scared.
Your Majesty, I'm truly honored to be pointed by
the sword of a famous general which is held by the rightful emperor.
My life is not wasted even though to be cut into pieces.
Sun Mingde.
You didn't learn much from your master.
But your tongue does get glibber.
Thank you for your praise.
All right.  I'll keep the sword.
Take the rest of these back.
Yes, Your Majesty.
Take it.
Master, I was scared to death.
Oh my goodness.
I mean, what did His Majesty want to do?
He just drew the sword out
and pointed it at the tip of my nose.
I thought I was going to die there.
You always teach me to guess the Emperor's intentions.
I keep guessing and racking my brains,
but I still can't figure it out.
The Emperor suddenly did that to me, what does he mean?
To tease you.
The Emperor shouldn't pick a fine sword for no reason.
But there is no war now.
What does he want to do?
I mean, Master...
What does the Emperor want to do?
[Princess Xiping's Manor]
Your Highness.
Miss Leng Yue came back.
Have you ever asked her about it?
What do you mean?
She and Commandery Prince An.
Well,
all Jinyu thinks about is the official affairs.
They left before I found a chance to ask them.
Anyway, Yue went with him.
They might be together when they come back.
It would save me the trouble to talk to them and annoy them.
But I heard that Commandery Prince An brought another girl
to the Southwest this time.
That's the new coroner he hired.
Are you worried that Jinyu, a first-rank prince, will marry a coroner?
Of course not.
Commandery Prince An is noble.
That coroner is lowly.
It's even inappropriate for her to be a maidservant
for Commandery Prince An.
Even if Commandery Prince An has any absurd idea,
the Emperor won't allow that.
I think you should ask the Emperor
to grant marriage to Commandery Prince An and Miss Leng Yue.
They are perfectly matched.
The Emperor won't object to it.
With the imperial decree, this will be a godsent marriage.
You can rest assured earlie, if they settle down earlier.
They said that I'm impatient.
Right now, you are more impatient than I am.
It's about their happiness. How can I not worry about it?
You are born to worry about people.
Your Jing Yi has been attractive to girls since he was young.
There are countless girls who fall for him.
I think your manor must be thronged with girls.
What's the use of that?
That kid flirts with different girls every day.
Sometimes I think he is interested in every girl.
Sometimes I think he is interested in no girl.
When I ask him, he just jokes about it.
He never takes it seriously.
If his reputation as a playboy spreads out,
I'm afraid no decent girl will marry him.
Speaking of him, he hasn't written a letter to us since he left.
Only I am worried about him.
I'm not worried about
his eating or sleeping.
He would never treat himself badly.
I'm just worried about Qianzhou.
I heard that there are wild bandits and the people are suffering.
Where did you hear that?
Even though Qianzhou is far away, it's still the territory of Tang.
Not to mention it's heavily garrisoned by the Military Commissioner,
The bandits in the Southwest have been terror-stricken long ago.
They are far less wild than in the Sui Dynasty.
What's more, The Emperor has approved Jinli
to lead troops to protect their safety in Qianzhou.
Don't worry about it.
They will be fine.
Dear.
Dear, what's wrong?
Dear, the paper is really expensive.
What's wrong, Dear?
Dear, what's wrong with you today?
What the hell is that?
It wastes my effort and comes to nothing. I'm not doing it anymore.
Dear, calm you anger.
Dear, did you fail to persuade Princess Xiping
to ask the Emperor to grant a marriage?
She said she is not worried as his mother.
I'm the only one who is worried.
- Although I'm not like her, I'm still a Commandery Princess.
- Yes, that's right.
I suffered this all because of you!
I...
Jing Zhi. If you don't tell me
why you want them to get married in such a hurry, it won't be over!
Dear, calm down.
Dear, have some water.
Dear, I did that for the sake of our son.
You are smart.
You know that our son falls for Leng Yue.
Think about it.
The five generations of the Jing family are all royal subjects.
Our roots are deep among the ministers.
The Leng family has a big army and is occupying the Southwest.
If our children get married,
this is bound to affect the current situation.
For the two families, there are all harms but no benefits.
We can rest assured earlier if we end his thought earlier.
I implore you to keep urging Leng Yue's marriage.
This is not just about the Jing family and the Leng family.
It's about everyone.
Everyone?
I just got news from the Southwest
The camp of the Military Commissioner in Qianzhou
is slightly abnormal.
Leng Peishan is not as healthy as before.
He needs to burn mugwort every day.
It can be seen that something is wrong with his body.
But he refuses to report it to the court.
He is training soldiers in private and building his army.
It's suspicious indeed.
Well... What does Leng Peishan...
What does he want to do?
Leng Peishan hides it deliberately.
We can't be sure what his intention is right now.
But if Leng Peishan is gravely ill,
I'm afraid he will make a big move
to preserve his power in the Southwest.
Does Leng Yue know that?
It's hard to say.
What if...
No way.
You have to tell our son about it.
He is with Commandery Prince An all the time,
and with Leng Yue following them.
This matter can't be said by any of us in our Jing family.
I will find out another way.
Dear, remember.
You can't say one word about this to anyone else.
[Qianzhou]
[Guanling Border, Qianzhou]
Your Highness, we've arrived at the Guanling border.
Your Highness. We will arrive in Pingle Town soon after we pass through the border.
We used to use the rope as a bridge.
A few years ago, the former prefectural government built a stone bridge.
It's much easier to get to our town now.
How can you use a rope as a bridge?
We would swing on a rope first
[Hillstone River]
and then climb for a while.
[Cross the river with a rope]
When there was no stone bridge, that was the only way for us.
It was really dangerous.
Master, I've sent the spices to Princess Xiping as you asked.
Is everything okay?
Banxia said Princess is doing well.
She thanked you for your concern.
She also asked me that if you receive any news from Commandery Prince An.
Well? Didn't Princess Xiping get news from Commandery Prince An?
No.
But the Emperor has ordered General Xiao Jinli
to lead troops to protect Commandery Prince An in Qianzhou.
I think they should be fine.
The Southwest is turbulent.
No news is the best news.
The time is up.
Master, it's time to enter the Palace.
I don't like this. I'm really scared.
Don't talk.
The terrain is complex. We can't stay long.
Let's hurry up.
What's the rush, Commandery Prince An?
Long time no see since we met in Chang'an last time.
I heard that you even painted a portrait of me to look for me.
I'm truly honored.
I've been waiting for you for a while.
I will send you to the underworld right now!
Timing and subtitles brought to you by The Imperial Coroners @ Viki.com
♫  Nothing can stop me  ♫
♫  From missing you all the time  ♫
♫  The moonlight appears, cold in the late night,
as the world changes  ♫
♫  Only with you by my side can I embrace my yearning for you  ♫
♫  When I close my eyes I meet you once again  ♫
♫  I'll gently brush your hair by your ear  ♫
♫  Life is long, with love and regrets in this world  ♫
♫  With you by my side, no matter how far I go,
we'll never be apart  ♫
♫  With your smile, in this moment, let me
cherish this lifetime  ♫
♫  Only for you, I have to worry about the end of this life  ♫
♫  I’m still young, with my love not yet realized for you, but I'm
willing to be here for you till the end  ♫
♫  You can rely on me in this lifetime  ♫
♫  Hope to spend this beautiful lifetime together  ♫