Timing and subtitles brought to you by The Imperial Coroners @ Viki.com
He is not Mr. Xue.
If it weren't for Chu Chu to find something odd,
I would still have been kept in the dark by Xue Rucheng.
From Chang'an to Qianzhou,
I even rushed to the military base.
[Qianzhou]
I've suspected countless people to be the leader of those rebels.
But I didn't suspect him.
How can there be such a stupid judge in Tang?
Minister Han,
there are deep strangulation marks on the deceased's neck,
from his neck to his ears.
It's for sure that he hanged himself.
All right, you are done here.
Go to the Ministry of Justice and give your statement.
- Yes.
[One child]
[The Imperial Coroner]
[Episode 33]
Guards, takedown the survivor of the rebellious party.
I was wondering where Commandery Prince An got another female coroner.
It's still you.
Commandery Prince An has always been fair and upright.
But now he deceived the emperor.
I'll take you to the emperor today.
I'd like to see how Commandery Prince An explains it.
Take her down.
Minister Han, when did I deceive the emperor?
Commandery Prince An, you came just in time.
Do you dare to say
that this woman is not the survivor of the rebellious party, Chu Chu?
She is Chu Chu.
But she is also a coroner working for me.
Since she is a coroner of the Three Judicial Offices,
is there any problem that she works for me?
Commandery Prince An, don't forget
it's not up to you to decide if she can be a coroner or not.
It requires the certificate jointly issued by
the Ministry of Personnel and the Three Judicial Offices.
Minister Han, are you talking about this?
[Certificate of Coroner]
[Appointment with immediate effect]
[Minister of Rites Judicial Offices]
Minister Han, it's true.
Well...
Han Ji.
When I'm still in charge of the Three Judicial Offices,
I'll still be your superior.
If you dare to offend me again,
don't blame me for not showing you mercy.
You...!
Watch out your steps.
Your Highness, when did you get the certificate issued by the Ministry of Personnel
and the Three Judicial Offices?
That was before the exam.
I asked the emperor for a blank identity certificate signed by the Ministry of Personnel
and the Three Judicial Offices.
It will take effect immediately after I fill in the applicant's information.
Why didn't you tell me before?
I filled it in last night.
Last night?
I didn't decide to hire you last night.
I know it.
Chu Chu.
I haven't filled it in
because I want to give you a chance to regret.
You need to know this is a certificate of the government.
Once filled in, it cannot be changed.
I told you I never regretted it.
You still don't believe me?
I believe you.
I believe this is how you really think at this moment.
But I don't know if you will still think in this way in the future.
After all, no one ever said
it's a pleasure to work for me.
I don't want to trap you with a certificate.
I want you to be free.
I want you to want to stay with me every minute.
You do have a point.
But no one said that I have to be your coroner forever.
A married couple can still divorce.
If I don't want to work for you one day,
I can resign and go home.
Fine.
But if there is such a day,
I'm not sure if I can bear to let you go.
You are just a coroner.
But I'm a first-rank commandery prince.
If I play dirty and not let you go,
there is nothing you can do.
You...
How can you make fun of me at this point?
Princess Xiping has arrived!
[Imperial Medical Service]
Greetings to Your Majesty.
Xiping, do you plead guilty?
Your Majesty, you summoned me.
I don't know what you mean.
Your Grace, Doctor Zhang Shu was found dead
last night in the Imperial Medical Service.
After an on-site investigation and evidence collection,
it has been verified that he committed suicide.
But he was forced.
He gave up his life in a desperate situation
to protect the family.
Your Grace, don't you plead guilty?
That's nonsense.
Doctor Zhang and I have no grudges.
Why would I harm him?
Why?
Can you recognize what His Majesty is holding?
Take a look by yourself.
[Bear one child]
It's my medical record.
Since the time of Emperor Wenzong,
Doctor Zhang has been my doctor.
Is there any problem that he has my medical record?
Your Grace, can I have it?
Everyone, please take a look.
This medical record is about Princess Xiping's pregnancy.
I've asked the doctors in the Imperial Medical Service to read it.
The signs are that Princess Xiping only bore one child at that time.
- One child?
- Something is going to happen.
Minister Han, during pregnancy, even the pulse can be inaccurate sometimes.
Everyone in Chang'an knows that I gave birth to twins.
Now my children have grown up.
You don't believe the facts.
But you want to believe the old medical record.
The fact is you only gave birth to one child.
The other child was adopted from somewhere else.
You are talking nonsense.
As a princess of Tang, if I want to adopt a child,
I can just get one and raise the child up.
Why would I cover it up?
That's because the child you adopted is not from an ordinary family,
but the son of Chen Ying, the Military Commissioner who led the rebellion during the time of Emperor Wenzong.
That's nonsense! Nonsense!
If you insist that I'm talking nonsense,
then please hear out the evidence I collected.
You are a distinguished princess.
You grew up in the palace.
After you got married with Xiao Heng,
you left the palace and built your own mansion.
The person who could let you make all the efforts to adopt her son
must have a deep friendship with you.
In Chang'an at that time, only the wife of Chen Ying
was your good friend who was also pregnant.
According to the dossier,
Madam Chen had been pregnant for nearly eight months.
She got too emotional after hearing the news about Chen Ying
and died of losing too much blood before giving birth.
Logically, the bones of the child
should be still curled up in Chen's pelvis.
But I sent someone to check the coffin last night.
The child's bones are still there.
But it's straight and lying between Chen's legs.
Thus it can be seen
that someone put the bones of a dead child later to mislead the people.
Am I right?
If you still don't believe what I said,
I can bring up the witnesses.
Bring up the witnesses.
Your Grace, do you still remember these two people?
Raise your head.
The elder of these two people was a wet nurse in your mansion back then.
The other was your former maid.
In order to conceal that she adopted a child,
Princess Xiping sent the maids
and servants who knew the fact out of the mansion
and settled them down in Yangzhou.
But you also left yourself a way out.
You detained their family in your mansion as hostages.
These two people's sister and son
were detained in your mansion.
After so many years, they missed their family too much.
They saw your two sons had grown up,
so they want to take their family back.
They didn't expect that they would be rejected
and nearly assassinated.
I didn't do it.
They voluntarily left the kids in my mansion.
Those two kids were young but clever.
They left them in my mansion for a better future.
Right now, those two children are still in my mansion.
Your Majesty, you can summon them and ask them about it.
They are your servants.
There is no doubt that they are on your side.
Their statements can't be trusted.
After Princess Xiping saw these two people in Chang'an,
she worried what she did would be exposed.
So he threatened Doctor Zhang
in the Imperial Medical Service who knows that fact.
Your Grace, you harbor the survivor of the rebellious party first,
then you deceived the emperor.
To conceal the truth,
you cruelly forced Doctor Zhang to commit suicide.
I have the evidence and the witnesses.
Your Grace, don't you plead guilty?
Xiping, what else do you want to say?
Your Majesty, I didn't kill Zhang Shu.
Besides, Jinyu and Jinli are both my flesh and blood.
I have nothing else to say.
Commandery Prince An has arrived.
I have something to say.
Xiao Jinyu pays respects to Your Majesty.
You may rise.
You said you have something to say.
What do you want to say?
Your Majesty, I heard Minister Han's inference when I was outside.
I think Minister Han's inference is full of loopholes.
Commandery Prince An, you are suspected of being a son of a rebel.
You don't have the right to talk nonsense here.
Xiao Jinyu, then explain his loopholes to me.
The medical record presented by Minister Han
must have been deliberately forged by someone else.
Well, well, Commandery Prince An.
That's really a desperate move.
You are really lying through your teeth.
You haven't seen the record.
How can you be so sure?
Minister Han, have you ever thought about
that if Doctor Zhang was really in a desperate situation
and he wanted to keep his family safe,
why would he put the medical record on the table
to let you discover it?
After he died, someone would search the room.
If anyone sees the medical record and suspects Princess Xiping,
then Princess Xiping kills his family after she learns it,
doesn't it mean that he died for nothing?
Maybe Doctor Zhang wanted to use his death to reveal the truth.
What a joke.
Zhang Shu is not a common person.
As the head of the Imperial Medical Service,
he has more chances to meet His Majesty than us.
Even if he really wanted to report anything,
does he need to give up his life?
Your Majesty, I want to check the pulse record Minister Han talked about.
Han Ji, show it to him.
Your Majesty, the paper of the pulse record is old.
But the ink is new.
Those who ever read account books or registers would know
that even the same person uses the same pen and ink to write,
the handwriting would vary a little bit every day.
But this volume which recorded Princess' pulse for nearly one year
is consistent in terms of its handwriting.
What's even stranger is
that the inked used in this record
is the fragrance-free ink developed three years ago in Shezhou.
The fragrance-free ink greatly reduces the burned odor of the ink itself
with its extremely delicate ink-making process.
Unlike the previous method of making ink,
spices should be added to the ink to cover the burned odor.
That's why it's called fragrance-free ink.
This ink is only used in the palace.
Even if he got this ink from somewhere else,
how would he use it to transcribe a volume of pulse records?
I never granted the fragrance-free ink to anyone in the Imperial Medical Service.
Han Ji, what is this about?
What happened to Doctor Zhang?
Your Highness, he was hanged.
Really?
There is a black-purple strangulation mark on the front of his neck
and below his Adam's apple.
That's why his mouth is slightly open and his tongue sticks out.
This strangulation mark spreads from the front of his neck to his ear.
And there is bruising on his legs.
He was hanged.
But... I don't think he hanged himself.
Why?
Because some bruises on his body
should be caused by fighting with someone else before he died.
But it doesn't look like face-to-face fighting.
What do you mean?
He has bruises on his wrists that were clearly being grabbed hard.
But other bruises on his body
are mostly on the sides and back of his limbs.
I don't know how they fought.
[Bruises on arms, legs and back]
Where are these bruises?
He has striped bruises on the outside of his left leg.
It was caused by hitting something hard.
[Striped bruises on left legs Collision]
Your Highness, let's try it?
Okay.
[Striped bruise on arms]
[Scratches on legs]
If he struggled in this way,
would he have bruises
on the back or side of his limbs?
Yes, it must be like this.
But why did this person fight with Doctor Zhang like this?
Doctor Zhang is over 60.
He doesn't practice martial arts.
It's not difficult to take him down with a heavy blow.
Why would that person go through all these troubles?
I know it.
He wanted to smother Doctor Zhang on the bed and make him faint.
Then he hanged him on the beam.
In this way, it would look like he hanged himself.
I found some white floc in the deceased's nose.
I was wondering what it was.
Now I know it's the cotton in the quilt.
When the killer smothered him,
he must have sucked it in when he was struggling.
But... those who discovered the deceased
saw him kick away the stool in front of them.
I heard that when they saw the deceased,
he was still dangling on the beam.
If he was really killed in this way,
does it mean the two doctors who discovered the deceased lied?
Your Majesty, I found out
Doctor Zhang Shu didn't commit suicide.
He was smothered with a quilt until he fainted
and then was hanged on the beam.
That's nonsense.
The two doctors saw it with their own eyes
that Doctor Zhang kicked down the stool by himself.
But he was old and weak and he didn't make it.
Who discovered Zhang Shu's death on that day?
Let me ask you.
Did you see it with your own eyes
that Zhang Shu kicked the stool down by himself?
Yes.
Your Majesty, I believe they are not lying.
Commandery Prince An.
You said that Doctor Zhang was murdered.
Then you said the two doctors are not lying.
What do you mean?
Zhang Shu was murdered.
And the two doctors are not lying.
It's just the murderer tricked them into believing that they saw
Doctor Zhang kick down the stool and commit suicide.
Wise Your Majesty.
Wise Commandery Prince An.
Your Majesty, the room next door...
is exactly the same as where the crime happened.
I've recreated the crime scene.
Please go there and see
how the murderer deceived them.
Okay.
Your Majesty, the room has been arranged just as the crime scene.
We only need to relive the night
when the two doctors found the deceased,
then the truth will come to light.
Your Majesty, let me do it.
Doctors, was the door like this
before you pushed the door at that time?
- Yes.
Minister Han, please.
How did it happen?
Well...
Doctors, is this what you heard and saw at that time?
Yes, exactly.
Exactly the same.
How is it possible?
The wooden dummy can't kick over the stool by itself.
This is just a little trick the murderer used.
Your Majesty, after the murderer smothered Doctor Zhang,
he used this rope to make Doctor Zhang look like that he committed suicide.
Then he put the stool diagonally at the feet of the deceased.
The deceased's feet were against the stool.
Then he put a brush
against the stool to support it.
He left the door half open
and placed the rod between the door and the stool.
When someone pushes the door,
the rod would hit the brush
and the stool would fall to the ground.
The brush would roll away
and the corpse would dangle from the beam.
Save him!
This is what the two doctors saw at the time.
Your Majesty, this is the brush I just put under the stool.
And this brush was found in Doctor Zhang's room.
If you compare them carefully,
you can find out that the ends of these two brushes
have almost the same abrasion marks.
The shape of the brush tips is almost the same.
Really.
The herbs and medicine packages that scattered on the ground
were also arranged by the murderer to conceal this mechanism,
making the brush and the rod on the ground
not too obvious.
Ministers, do you have any objections
to Commandery Prince An's inference?
I have no objection.
I have no objection, either.
Xiao Jinyu, if you knew how the murderer killed him,
you must also know who the murderer is.
The murderer took all these efforts to set this trap.
But he made a fatal mistake.
After the murderer set up the mechanism,
he had to leave the room through the window.
When the murderer jumped out of the window that night,
a silk thread was hooked down
by a splinter on the window.
It seems to be...
Wise Your Majesty.
This silk thread is from the inside lining of the eunuch's clothes.
Eunuch Sun, there is your name on the access records
of the Imperial Medical Service at that night.
It also matches the time when Doctor Zhang was murdered.
After investigation, Eunuch Sun hasn't applied for a new official uniform.
Can you show your inside lining to us?
Your... Your Highness, what do you mean?
Your Majesty, he is the murderer!
Your Majesty, I know nothing about it.
I really know nothing.
Your...
Master! Master!
Master, save me!
Save me, Master! Master!
Save me!
You...!
How dare you commit a crime in front of His Majesty!
Your Majesty, this villain committed such a felony.
It's my fault that I failed to discipline him.
Today, Commandery Prince An has found out the truth.
The evidence is irrefutable to convict him.
I'm in charge of the Palace Domestic Service.
It's my duty to punish the eunuchs.
Even this villain called me his teacher,
I can't tolerate him.
I have to punish him severely.
Your Majesty, I was a little hasty.
But if this villain hurts Your Majesty out of desperation,
it will be too late to regret it.
Your Majesty, I'm loyal to you.
Please understand me.
Eunuch Qin, I don't think you only want to punish Sun Mingde.
You are afraid that if you don't kill him now,
he would confess how you want to use Zhang Shu's death
to falsely accuse my mother of harboring the son of a rebel
and deceiving His Majesty,
as to prevent me from returning to Chang'an with the irrefutable evidence
to reveal how you called white black
and wrongfully killed the Military Commissioner of Jiannan.
Commandery Prince An,
you just convicted Sun Mingde in front of His Majesty
and these ministers.
Right?
I believed your inference
and executed this villain on the spot!
Now you are saying something like this.
Look! I really can't understand you now.
Your Majesty, I beg for justice.
Xiao Jinyu, how is this about the Military Commissioner of Jiannan now?
What's going on? Make it clear.
Your Majesty, I went to the Southwest this time
and found my father, the Investigating Censor of Emperor Wenzong,
who had been missing for years.
My father passed away in Qianzhou five years ago.
I've brought his body back to Chang'an.
My father left some evidence before he died.
He also encrypted what happened to him at that time
and wrote it down in his last words.
Please allow me to present you his last words and other evidence.
Okay.
Your Highness.
Your Highness, something has gone wrong.
Everyone in Xue's Mansion disappeared.
What?
I can't get any news from the Ministry of War.
What's more, Commandery Prince An has returned to Chang'an.
He is back alive,
which means they failed to seize the base.
Don't tell anyone about this failure.
Your Highness, it's dangerous in Chang'an now.
You'd better make a plan now.
Make a plan now?
I've been planning and preparing for more than ten years with all my efforts.
It had nothing to do with him.
But he has to go against me.
He can't blame me then.
Have you arranged the people and the places as I asked you?
Your Highness, don't worry. I've arranged it properly.
Xiao Jinyu,
I'm your teacher.
Do you think you can get out of my hand?
Your Majesty, I've written down how I found my father's letter
and the deciphered content of the letter in the memorial.
Please take a look.
My father was ordered to go to the Southwest in secret
and summon the Military Commissioner, Chen Ying, to suppress the bandits.
[Summon the Military Commissioner, Chen Ying to suppress the bandits.]
Chen Ying led more than 20,000 men to Chang'an by order.
But they were falsely accused by the eunuchs of being rebels
and were brutally slaughtered.
My father tried to prove their innocence
and broke out of the siege with the secret edict.
Qin Luan's party was afraid of my father's returning to Chang'an to reveal the truth,
so they had been setting ambushes and planting informers in Chang'an
and sending people to the Southwest to hunt him down and kill him.
My father couldn't return to Chang'an to redress their grievances before he died.
I went to the Southwest this time and followed the clues left by my father,
then I found out my father's letter
and the evidence he left before he died.
That's when I learned
the grievances of tens of thousands of loyal men buried in the Southwest.
Your Majesty, I beg you to re-investigate the case
and clear the name of Chen Ying and other loyal generals and soldiers.
Qin Luan.
Your Majesty, I took the order of Emperor Wenzong
and led troops to the Southwest to suppress the rebels.
Everybody knew it in the court.
Commandery Prince An was not born at the time of the incident in the Southwest.
After so many years, he just went to the Southwest,
brought back an old corpse
and some so-called evidence that is easy to forge
to mislead people and call white black.
I think Commandery Prince An is distorting the fact with his glib tongue
to exonerate Princess Xiping and himself.
Your Majesty, this matter is of great importance.
Wise Your Majesty.
Your Majesty, I have another piece of evidence
that can prove that Qin Luan is not innocent.
What else do you have? Take it out.
Chu Chu from the Three Judicial Offices
greets Your Majesty.
Your Majesty, look.
She is the daughter of Yun Yi the rebel.
Timing and subtitles brought to you by The Imperial Coroners @ Viki.com
♫  Nothing can stop me  ♫
♫  From missing you all the time  ♫
♫  The moonlight appears, cold in the late night,
as the world changes  ♫
♫  Only with you by my side can I embrace my yearning for you  ♫
♫  When I close my eyes I meet you once again  ♫
♫  I'll gently brush your hair by your ear  ♫
♫  Life is long, with love and regrets in this world  ♫
♫  With you by my side, no matter how far I go,
we'll never be apart  ♫
♫  With your smile, in this moment, let me
cherish this lifetime  ♫
♫  Only for you, I have to worry about the end of this life  ♫
♫  I’m still young, with my love not yet realized for you, but I'm
willing to be here for you till the end
♫  You can rely on me in this lifetime  ♫
♫  Hope to spend this beautiful lifetime together  ♫