Timing and subtitles brought to you by The Imperial Coroners @ Viki.com
Do you plead guilty?
Qin Luan killed the imperial doctor and framed Princess Xiping,
trying to put Commandery Prince An and his family to death on the charge of deceiving the emperor.
Fortunately, His Highness and I found out the real cause of the imperial doctor's death
and the murderer, Sun Mingde.
With the eunuch's body hidden in the wall by my father being the evidence,
Qin Luan, you can't talk your way out of it this time.
[Domestic Service]
Xue Rucheng,
after I take down Qin Luan,
what other bargaining chip do you have to usurp the throne?
Chu Chu from the Three Judicial Offices greets Your Majesty.
Your Majesty, look.
She is the daughter of Yun Yi the rebel.
Eunuch Qin, how do you know that?
You've been long living in the palace.
When did you ever see her?
You...
Are you the female coroner taken in by Commandery Prince An?
- Yes.
- Raise your head.
Thank you, Your Majesty.
Your Majesty,
Chu Chu's biological father, Yun Yi, was a general of the Military Commissioner of Jiannan.
I've found out the whole story of the Military Commissioner's case.
To prevent Chu Chu from being murdered before I revealed the truth of this case,
I decided to bring her to Chang'an in person
and report everything to Your Majesty.
Maybe it's the will of Heaven.
Chu Chu, get up and answer my question.
Chu Chu, whose body did you bring here?
Your Majesty.
It's the body of the eunuch who failed to assassinate Prince Consort
and it was sealed in a wall by Prince Consort.
The weapon Prince Consort used to fight with him was also sealed in the wall.
After verification, he was killed in an intense fight.
The wounds on his body match perfectly with the fighting process described in Prince Consort's letter.
Lift the shroud. I want to take a look.
This was found along with his body.
[Domestic Service]
- Qin Luan.
- Yes.
Show me your token.
Han Ji!
Your Majesty,
the token is not easy to forge,
[Domestic Service]
but some people can still forge it.
- Your Majesty, please...
- The employment system was extremely strict
when Eunuch Ma was in charge of the Palace Domestic Service.
All the eunuchs' physical characteristics have been recorded.
Eunuch Qin.
You rule the Palace Domestic Service according to the old rules.
Before I came here, I asked someone to borrow the access register.
There was a person who died on the way to run some errands
matching with this eunuch.
- Qin Luan.
- Yes.
Didn't you say that Commandery Prince An was making up a story to frame you?
During the years when you were in charge of the Palace Domestic Service,
one of your subordinates killed an imperial doctor
and attempted to frame Princess Xiping, Commandery Prince An, and his brother.
Another one went to the Southwest to assassinate Xiao Heng.
Who is misleading us and calling white black?
- Guards!
- Yes!
Take Qin Luan into custody for trial.
Yes!
[The Imperial Coroner]
[Episode 34]
Han Ji.
Your Majesty.
As the Minister of Justice,
you failed to uphold justice and distinguish right from wrong.
I'll remove you from the Minister of Justice and demote you to a two-rank lower position.
Ponder over your mistakes in your room for half a month.
Come back to see me after you think it through!
Thank you, Your Majesty.
Commandery Prince An.
Sorry.
Qin Luan's case was a long time ago and it involves many parties.
Xiao Heng was also involved in it.
It's improper for his son to carry out the investigation.
Senior Jing, you are highly respected among the officials.
I'll let you take charge of the investigation.
The Ministry of Justice, the Censorate, the Court of Judicial Review,
and the Three Judicial Offices shall assist in the investigation.
You must find out what Qin Luan did
and every person who is involved in the case!
Yes, Your Majesty.
Senior Jing, Qin Luan's reaction was not quite right.
He must have prepared something.
Be careful.
Your Highness.
How is the plan going?
The news from Zhou Han
said that Qin Luan was counter-attacked by Xiao Jinyu and was arrested.
Then act on the plan.
Yes.
Where is Zhou Han?
Mother, you got frightened today because of me. It's my fault.
What are you doing?
Get up. Get up now.
You saved me today.
You also convinced the emperor to conduct a thorough investigation.
I should thank you two on behalf of Prince Consort,
the Chen clan, and the 20,000 loyal and righteous soldiers
of the Military Commissioner of Jiannan.
Your Grace, Prince Consort wore it all the time when he was alive.
He left it to me before he died.
Now it's time to give it to you.
Is this made of stone?
Yes, stone.
Where did you get the stone?
I picked it up by the koi pond in my house.
You are really frank.
I'm glad you are back.
You have suffered a lot along the way.
The traitors have been removed,
the truth will come to light one day.
Jinyu, there is one thing
I need to tell you now.
Mother, I know it.
I am a descendant of the Chen family.
How do you know it?
When Chu Chu first saw you at the Imperial Medical Service,
she knew you and Father were not my biological parents
from your looks.
Your Grace, His Highness asked me to tell him.
I couldn't lie to him.
You went through fire and water with Jinyu
and you always put Jinyu first.
How would I blame you?
Mother, please rest assured.
Before I came, Senior Jing asked me to tell you that he had asked the emperor.
If it was a miscarriage of justice
that you protected the descendant of a royal general. It's a good deed.
I don't care about that.
It's just I've been feeling guilty.
During all these years,
I couldn't let you fulfill your filial duties to your parents.
We had no choice back then.
Now that you know who your biological parents are,
you should worship them as their son.
I understand it.
I will serve incense in the mansion
to thank my parents for giving me my life.
Mother, if it weren't for you to save me
and to take good care of me for so many years,
there wouldn't be me now.
If my biological parents knew it,
they would also be grateful to you.
I still want to serve you just as before.
I don't know...
I don't know if you still want me to stay by your side.
Get up.
I never said I didn't want you.
You and Jinli are both my children.
You were my son before,
you are my son now,
and you will always be my son.
- Do you remember it?
- Yes, I remember it.
Mother.
♪ Shence Army marched westward ♪
Senior Jing, we've brought him here.
♪ They came to the Southwest ♪
Get in.
♪ They scampered off like frightened rats ♪
It's about 4:00 p.m. now.
Is there anything urgent that you need to do?
Look, look! Well, I'm here now.
What urgent thing can I have?
I'm just used to it.
I've been serving His Majesty for too long.
I live my life hour by hour.
I can get myself killed
if I'm faster or slower.
Therefore, no matter where I go,
I can't help but to look at these timers.
Now that you are in the prison of the Court of Judicial Review,
you can take a good rest.
Everything is rough and simple here.
But you have enough time.
Since I entered the palace and started to serve Emperor Wenzong,
in the blink of an eye,
well, I've served three emperors.
By the way, you also became an official during the time of Emperor Wenzong, right?
I remember it was the second year of Taihe.
Eunuch Qin, your memory is good indeed.
I wouldn't say that.
Senior Jing,
you and I have both served three emperors.
You should also understand
that replacing the emperor is not as difficult as what common people think.
And it's not as predictable as what the emperor thinks.
Those inauspicious signs
are all made up by the Imperial Astronomers to make a living.
Senior Jing,
you and I know clearly why
the emperor let you handle this case instead of Commandery Prince An.
If Commandery Prince An handles this case,
with his personality, he would definitely make a thorough investigation.
That's pulling out the radish with the mud.
I'm afraid in the end,
most officials in the court couldn't get away from it.
His Majesty ordered you to handle this case,
you should know the best
what kind of result he wants. Right?
What His Majesty wants is to enforce the law impartially
and let the truth come to light.
Enforce the law impartially?
Qin Luan, the reason the Jing family has gone so far
is because we remain true to our original aspiration.
We always stay alert,
learn lessons from our mistakes,
and correct our mistakes.
Jing Zhi, look at you.
You're too old to
believe in such naive nonsense.
Qin Luan, I'm giving you a chance.
A chance?
I entered the palace at the age of seven.
Now I'm the acting chief eunuch.
It's not because of any chance given by other people.
It's my fate.
Look. I have a hold on politics in the Division of Eunuchs.
I have a hold on military power in the Shence Army.
I participate in national affairs and share the military and political power.
The emperor is nothing but a man who is surviving in the palace temporarily.
Even the common people know that emperors come and go in Tang,
but the Division of Eunuchs is always there.
The Division of Eunuchs is my chance.
What kind of chance are you talking about?
Eunuch Qin,
do you think you still have a way out?
In your situation,
only confessing everything might get you decently buried
considering that you have served His Majesty for years.
I can even add the beard on you.
I don't need you to serve me.
Thank you.
Senior Jing,
winner takes all.
My time hasn't run out yet.
Take him in.
Yes, Sir!
Get in.
♪ Shence Army marched westward ♪
Your Highness, how is it going?
He has been paying attention to the time and counting the hours.
We guessed it right.
He has been prepared before leaving the palace.
If he doesn't go back to the palace at the agreed time,
his men in the palace will take action.
Now he is just stalling it.
What does he want to do?
To kill the emperor and usurp the throne.
Senior Jing, have you learned the Senza Misura
I taught you in the Royal Garden last time?
How was my singing just now?
Qin Luan, think it through.
Whether to be abandoned in the wilderness
or buried decently,
it's up to you.
I mean, Senior Jing.
Thank you for your kindness.
You'd better save your saliva and stay healthy.
Hold on!
Go ahead.
You are thoughtful indeed.
Father! Something happened!
- What is it?
- His Majesty...
His Majesty...
What?
Qin Luan, you...
How dare you kill the emperor!
Get... Get off me...
Senior Jing, don't be too sad.
His Majesty loves Huzhou Zisun the most.
He must have a cup of it at 7:00 p.m.
I think I've done my best to serve him
by letting him die from his favorite tea.
Get off me.
Huzhou Zisun.
It's a waste of good tea.
Senior Jing, don't be too sad.
Eunuch Qin, are you laughing at Senior Jing?
Commandery Prince An.
You must have seen through the trick of the water clock, right?
That's right, Commandery Prince An.
Senior Jing is an old sly fox indeed.
He brought a faster water clock on purpose.
Look. He even covered up all the windows
to prevent me from seeing the changes in light and shadow outside.
Didn't he just want to
mess up my sense of time?
Then he played a show in front of me
to make me blurt out the truth
when I got carried away.
It's a pity
that Senior Jing never served in the palace.
He would never know
that someone like me who has been serving His Majesty
for most of my life
already has an accurate water clock in my heart.
That clock can't be disturbed by any means.
No.
Senior Jing thought about it.
He thought about it?
It was my idea to bring an inaccurate water clock.
But Senior Jing reminded me
that those who have been serving in the palace for a long time
are extremely sensitive to time.
It's very hard to change your perception of time in a short time.
So I decided to go with it.
What do you mean by that?
You think you know Senior Jing is acting.
In fact, Senior Jing also knows that you are acting.
You know that Senior Jing is good at recognizing lies,
so you must've told the truth when you said that the emperor would die of drinking the tea.
Only in this way can you fool Senior Jing.
But it's not what it means when you first heard it.
Looks like it's not the tea leaves that will kill the emperor.
It's not the water for making the tea.
But the cup for holding the tea.
Commandery Prince An.
With his look,
we can be sure that your inference is right.
Senior Jing, please take care of His Majesty.
Qin Luan, you are seeking your own death.
Commandery Prince An, even if you know it,
it's still too late.
Look. From the prison of the Court of Judicial Review to the palace,
it takes 30 minutes to get there riding a fast horse.
When the time is up, all the gates will be closed.
Even if you muster the soldiers outside and rush into the palace,
the palace will be bleeding at that time.
Then the young master will ascend throne,
and the Daming Palace is still mine.
Xiao Jinyu, what else can you do?
You are extremely sensitive to time,
but your perception of direction is no different from that of ordinary people.
We had too little time to prepare for the interrogation today.
After some thinking, I bet on two things.
Tell me about it.
First, I bet you don't go out of the palace very often.
You are unfamiliar with the way from the Imperial Medical Service
to the prison of the Court of Judicial Review.
Second, I bet that you are not familiar with
the interrogation room of the prison of the Court of Judicial Review.
What is this place?
This is the Yeting Prison in the palace.
From here to Jiangshan Hall,
it takes less than 7.5 minutes with Jing Yi's speed.
[Token]
Qin Luan announced false imperial edicts and rose in rebellion!
He committed an unforgivable sin!
If you don't throw down your weapons and surrender now,
you will be executed now and have three generations of familial exterminations!
Qin Luan, do you think you can
sack the Daming Palace by closing the gates?
Xiao Jinyu.
I've lived an illustrious life.
I didn't expect to lose to a young man.
I won't accept this.
It's a pity that the white jade teacup from my brother can't be used anymore.
Deal with it.
Maybe it's my brother who protected me again.
Yes. Rest assured, Your Majesty.
Everything is going well as per Commandery Prince An's plan.
Qin Luan's people in the Forbidden Armies have all been arrested.
I really didn't expect that Qin Luan could be so bold
that he even tried to kill you as Commandery Prince An expected.
Qin Luan has a hold on military power.
He has been scourging Tang for a long time.
The accumulated abuses are hard to eliminate.
Even if I'm sitting on the throne,
I have to use such a way to deal with them.
It has been hard for you
to take risks for me during such a long time.
Jinbao, keep a close eye on him.
Yes.
I have found out that Rugui House keeps many killers.
The instructor behind the manager...
Eunuch Sun, I haven't thanked you for letting me stay.
Look at you.
Sun Mingde!
Rest assured and stay by my side.
I won't treat you badly.
Thank you, Your Majesty.
I'm willing to go through fire and water for Your Majesty and never shrink from dangers.
Zhou Han went missing just after Qin Luan was taken into prison today.
There is also a group of people missing from the Shence Army.
I guess they fled with Zhou Han.
Zhou Han is lustful, greedy for money,
and simple minded.
Now Qin Luan is dead.
The only chance for him to regain wealth is to turn to Xue Rucheng.
Xue Rucheng is also in urgent need of people.
Not to mention someone like Zhou Han who knows everything about Chang'an.
Then I'll send more people to arrest him as soon as possible.
No hurry.
Let him go. He is useful for us.
The tyrant is ruthless and immoral.
When he just took the throne,
he ordered his soldiers to disguise themselves as bandits
and slaughter more than a hundred innocent people in my mansion
just out of fear.
But God bless Tang to let me survive till this day
and have a chance to kill the tyrant in person.
I promised before that one day
I would lead you to avenge your families.
This day is coming.
Avenge!
Avenge! Avenge! Avenge!
Your Highness! Right now, we are outnumbered.
We lost Qin Luan's help.
Our people can't hide among the examinees.
It's not a good time for revenge now.
Shen Yu,
you've just become the Capital Liaison Representative
and taken salary from the Li family for a few days.
Now you have forgottenhow your father died.
Uncle Chi, you know that is not what I meant.
What do you mean then?
I...
I just think Xiao Jinyu is pressing hard.
The situation is against us.
I think we should
take a break and recover ourselves, waiting for a better chance.
Well...
Your Highness.
Not many of you experienced the tragedy of that year.
I understand that you cringe now.
But I believe if those who died tragically in my mansion
were lucky enough to survive, they would join me
to kill the tyrant and fight to the last moment
to defend the rightful emperor of Tang.
Now an ignorant young man is playing the saboteur.
If I withdraw now,
how can I deserve to be the descendant of the Li clan?
How should I face my parents in Heaven?
How should I face those hundreds of innocent people
who died tragically in Qianzhou?
I swear allegiance to Your Highness!
You guessed it right again.
Li Zhang's mother was an embroiderer in Duke Chang's mansion.
Zhao Jie's father and brother were guards in Duke Chang's mansion.
Wu Chen's eldest sister was a chef in Duke Chang's mansion.
And also, the dancer who killed Yan Ming,
her mother in Chang'an was not her biological mother.
Her biological mother was also a servant in Duke Chang'an mansion.
When the bandits ransacked the mansion,
their families in there were all killed.
I guess Xue Rucheng made use of it
to muster them to work for him.
Guess which doctor treated Duke Chang
when he left the palace because of smallpox?
Zhang Shu?
Lord Jing, you're back.
Are you eating?
I just made some snacks for His Highness.
Have some too.
Now we've taken down Qin Luan.
Xue Rucheng lost his greatest help.
My father cared for the examinees
and his proposal of providing food and housing was approved by His Majesty.
In this way, the rebels of Xue Rucheng
among the examinees won't live there to make sure they can act freely.
Then we can roughly infer the number of rebels according to
the number of examinees in Qianzhou who sign up for the accommodations.
But are those examinees willing to be kept together?
They can save money on food and accommodations.
It's convenient to make friends and expand contacts.
They should be happy about it.
But... without Qin Luan's help,
if the number of rebels is exposed,
will Xue Rucheng flee out of fear?
That would be troublesome then.
He won't.
He has been planning for years.
Now, he is only one step away from the throne.
There is no way he can go back to the old days when he hid himself and bided his time.
Even to pull chestnuts out of the fire,
he will take the risk and do it.
Without Qin Luan's help in the palace,
he has to figure out a way outside the palace.
With limited men and no source of news about the emperor,
he can't take actions
in the heavily guarded banquets or the royal sacrifices.
His only chance is a small event
that can gather the royal family and the officials.
What could it be?
It should be out of his expectation that Qin Luan lost his power.
Instead of letting him look for a chance,
we might as well offer him one.
Offer him one?
To draw him out?
I got it.
I read it from the Prince Consort's story
that scholars from various places will gather in Chang'an during the Imperial Examination.
The court will also hold some poetry parties and tea parties.
The emperor and ministers would also attend it.
Are you talking about that?
It's definitely not what His Highness is talking about.
Why?
That is exactly the problem.
His Highness means that we need to arrest the rebels.
But we can't make a lot of noise about Duke Chang.
For the people,
Xue Rucheng has been burned to death.
Duke Chang has also been dead for years.
These rumors were just spread by some bored people.
So we'd better wipe them out as quietly as we can.
I still don't understand it.
Because once we make any waves,
whether he succeeds or fails,
those who harbor ill intentions
in the neighboring regions and countries might make a big deal out of it.
Then the state will be in chaos
and the innocent people will suffer.
What should we do then?
Let me think about it.
Timing and subtitles brought to you by The Imperial Coroners @ Viki.com
♫  Nothing can stop me  ♫
♫  From missing you all the time  ♫
♫  The moonlight appears, cold in the late night,
as the world changes  ♫
♫  Only with you by my side can I embrace my yearning for you  ♫
♫  When I close my eyes I meet you once again  ♫
♫  I'll gently brush your hair by your ear  ♫
♫  Life is long, with love and regrets in this world  ♫
♫  With you by my side, no matter how far I go,
we'll never be apart  ♫
♫  With your smile, in this moment, let me
cherish this lifetime  ♫
♫  Only for you, I have to worry about the end of this life  ♫
♫  I’m still young, with my love not yet realized for you, but I'm
willing to be here for you till the end
♫  You can rely on me in this lifetime  ♫
♫  Hope to spend this beautiful lifetime together  ♫