Timing and subtitles brought to you by The Imperial Coroners @ Viki.com
Zhao Jie killed Wu Chen after he learned that Wu Chen was exposed.
He led his men and attacked the base.
[Qin Luan caught two maids who were dismissed from the Princess's Mansion]
[The Leng clan...]
Fortunately, Commandery Prince An saw through his scheme.
He made a plan to lure the enemy in
and wiped out the rebels.
[Wu has been eliminated. We can't meet as scheduled.]
No. It's not over.
This is the place where Wu Chen dealt with military affairs.
Commandery Prince An, go ahead and investigate as you want.
Okay.
These are too many.
These are the accounts of procurement over the years.
They're all here.
Was Wu Chen responsible for all the accounts of procurement?
He had three deputies.
But the final accounts need to be approved
and signed by Wu Chen.
Your Highness, this cabinet is strange.
Look.
It looks thick on the outside.
[Half side of the cabinet]
But it's really thin inside.
[Front Side]
[Abnormal thickness]
There are still account books inside.
[Account Book]
The content is the same as the book I just took.
Is this Wu Chen's handwriting?
Yes. Wu Chen once told me
that we can't only have a copy of the account book.
It's dangerous if it leaks out.
Therefore, he made a copy of it by himself.
This is the first time I've seen the backup.
Wu Chen was meticulous indeed.
He even made a backup.
The money of the government was not wasted.
[2,2000 coins for herbs]
Your Highness, what's wrong?
No. This is not a backup.
This is a different account book.
But these two account records are exactly the same.
Your Highness, did you find any code words?
It's not about code words.
General Leng, please make an order now
to search every barrack and warehouse on the base.
If I guess it right,
there should be a lot of supplies and weapons hidden here.
Commandery Prince An, the account records match the remaining money.
If Wu Chen bought twice the supplies every time,
how did he pay the other half of it?
With that money!
What money?
- Soldiers' pay.
- Soldiers' pay?
When I arrived in Qianzhou,
I borrowed some soldiers' pay from Jinli
and there were illegally minted coins among it.
Soldiers in the army rarely have a chance to spend money.
They can hardly tell the genuineness of the coins.
Not to mention these counterfeit coins are well-minted and can be mistakable for the real ones.
Besides, how would the soldiers
suspect the genuineness of the money from the government?
These people are really smart.
They got the money from the treasury in the name of soldiers' pay.
Then they replaced it with counterfeit money and paid the soldiers with it
so as to keep the genuine money.
It's a sure bet.
Unforgivable!
[Account Book]
This bunch of treacherous rebels.
[The Imperial Coroner]
[Episode 31]
General Leng, this is all the money I have.
It's my salary given by Commandery Prince An.
It's genuine.
It's not a lot,
but it can help you a little bit.
Please take it.
Grandfather, this is all I have.
Don't worry.
I've been living on my own, but I never steal or rob.
The money is clean.
Take the money back.
Take it back.
This is official business.
It has nothing to do with you two girls.
It's my fault for being an old fool.
I let those rebels put me in this position.
I already feel embarrassed to let Commandery Prince An
clean up this mess for me.
If I take your money,
what would that make me look like?
Grandfather,
just pretend that the money is from my father. Okay?
If my father were alive,
he wouldn't bear to watch you get in trouble.
He would find some way to raise money for you.
Take it as the help from my parents.
General Leng,
my family lives in Guanling County, Qianzhou.
Bandits used to rob us.
If it weren't for your army to teach them a lesson
and scare them off,
the people in Guanling County wouldn't live such a peaceful life.
We never had a chance to thank you.
Take the money as I repay you on behalf of
the people of Guanling County.
Kids, I know your good intentions.
I'll thank you on behalf of the soldiers.
But you should take the money back.
Miss Chu, as Military Commissioner, it's my job
to protect the people's safety for the imperial court.
It's the best reward for us
that the people can live and work in peace and contentment.
It's late.
Go back and have some rest.
I'm old now, but I can still take it.
According to the schedule,
the people from the south are coming soon.
Get ready to welcome them in the city.
Yes.
[Antique Store]
That's a lot.
Where did you get the money?
From the county offices nearby.
The far one will be here later.
The rebels have just been wiped out, and we found the supplies they hid.
The soldiers have started to feel edgy.
If we ask the soldiers to turn over their salary now,
I'm afraid there will be a big mess.
Yue, what he said is true.
General Leng, don't worry.
The best way right now is to raise enough genuine money
and use it to replace the counterfeit money of the soldiers.
Exchanging money for money won't neutralize the army.
I'm under the order to investigate the case of illegal minting of coins.
Leave the illegally minted coins to me.
I'll take care of them.
Then it can be solved justifiably.
Commandery Prince An, you...
General Leng, don't worry.
I didn't use my identity
to force them to take out the money.
Then...
Why were they willing to give us so much money?
When the emperor ordered me
to investigate the case of illegal minting of coins,
he granted me the right to act at my discretion
and ordered Qianzhou officials at all levels to fully cooperate with me.
Jing Yi and I took the imperial edict
and went to the surrounding county offices.
We ordered the county offices to take out 50,000 coins
from their treasuries and send the money to the army in the name of the investigation.
The Military Commissioner will send soldiers to assist in the investigation.
They dare not defy the order.
The coins in their treasuries
were directly from the place where the money was made.
And they are afraid of being implicated.
They have verified the coins carefully before they sent them to us.
I also checked some of the coins.
They are genuine.
It's a temporary solution,
but it can help you out for now.
But, Commandery Prince An,
these troubles will all fall on you in this way.
If I can't raise enough money,
how are you going to deal with those county offices?
If they tell on you to His Majesty
and accuse you of playing favorites, then...
Don't worry, General Leng.
Since it's for screening,
it will take some time to verify the coins.
It makes sense even it takes us
two or three months to verify the coins one by one.
After I return to Chang'an and report it to His Majesty,
the government will give you a grant
and you can return the money to them in batches.
Thanks a lot, Commandery Prince An.
General Leng, there is one more thing
that is more important than the coins.
Jinli.
I took the seal of Commandery Prince An and checked the recruitment of the Qianzhou Army.
I found out that the Qianzhou Army has been harassed by bandits.
They couldn't beat the bandits,
and some soldiers were taken captive.
Li Zhang never tried to solve it.
He just kept recruiting to replenish the army.
These were copied from the record book.
There is an important reason
why these wild bandits in Qianzhou can't be wiped out.
Prefect Li Zhang was protecting them.
First, Li Zhang recruited the rebels into the Qianzhou Army
and trained them above board.
After the training was almost over,
he would order those bandits
who took orders from him to rescue the rebels from the Qianzhou Army
and blend them into the bandits.
Then when your army went to suppress them,
they would surrender and join your army.
In this way,
batches of rebels kept sneaking into
your army in a reasonable way
after they changed their identities three times.
Li Zhang is a talent indeed.
But he didn't use his cleverness in the right way.
Wait.
This number doesn't match the number of rebels we captured.
There are still many of them outside.
I guess they took the pass provided by Li Zhang
and headed for Chang'an.
But it's not easy to get into Chang'an.
They not only need a pass to enter Chang'an,
as out-of-town visitors, they will also be questioned many times by the guards at the gate.
If they go to the inn, they will be questioned again.
There are many of them.
How can they enter Chang'an?
The Imperial Examination.
More than a month later is the day of the Imperial Examination.
Right now, candidates from various places
and writers are flocking to Chang'an.
They want to take this opportunity to blend into them.
That's not good.
They are going to create a disturbance.
We must catch them immediately.
Blending into the candidates is like hiding wood in the forest.
How to catch them?
Your Majesty, I heard that Chang'an has been quite lively these days.
The Imperial Examination is coming.
All kinds of students have arrived in Chang'an one after another.
Scholars and writers gather in Chang'an.
The poetry and tea gatherings go on all day long.
Another collection of masterpieces will spread in the world.
When your posterity recites the poems,
they will be grateful for your keen intelligence and your grace.
How dare I talk about grace
in the land left by my ancestors?
I only hope that Tang can restore some of its prosperity.
Only in this way can I not fail
my ancestors and my people.
Your diligence and your care for the people have been seen by Heaven.
It's really exciting to think about all the talents of Tang
gathering in Chang'an.
That's true, Your Majesty.
But I have something inappropriate to say now.
Go ahead and say it.
Your Majesty, all kinds of candidates are flocking to Chang'an,
which means the number of people entering Chang'an from other places every day
is several times higher than usual.
I heard that the guards are understaffed
and it takes them too long to question every person,
leading to congestion and riots at the gate.
Did that happen?
Your Majesty, I dare not lie to you.
The examination is coming up.
There will be more candidates entering Chang'an.
The guards at the gate have to give up accuracy
and seek quickness because they are short-staffed.
If someone treacherous
takes advantage of it and sneaks into Chang'an,
there might be some serious trouble.
You have a point.
Your Majesty, my Shence Army has been enjoying your grace for a long time.
We would like to share your worries.
Good.
The Shence Army has been guarding the Imperial Palace well.
During the Imperial Examination,
I'll let the Shence Army stop and search the passengers.
Select good men
and make sure not to let any suspicious person in.
Yes, Your Majesty.
[Jinguang Gate]
All the soldiers, attention!
The Imperial Examination is coming up.
From now on, the Shence Army will be responsible for stopping and searching every passenger at each gate.
You shall carry out the order and make no mistake.
Yes!
Do you have feelings for that boy from the Jing clan?
Me?
How could I have feelings for him?
He is the last man I would have feelings for.
Yue'er, tell me the truth.
When did it start?
I...
I don't know.
It's been a while.
Does he know your heart?
I don't know.
But I know he has feelings for me.
He has feelings for you?
That's good. That's good.
General... General Leng...
Why are you here?
Come over and sit down.
- General Leng...
- Drink it first.
That's impolite.
Well? That's all you can drink?
Where did you get the gall to enter my base disguised as a wounded soldier?
General Leng, it was my idea to enter your base disguised as a wounded soldier.
I apologize for offending you.
Please don't blame others.
Aren't you afraid that I won't allow you to see Yue'er again?
General Leng, I'm sorry.
I didn't do it on purpose.
I just thought you were brave and reliable.
Then, you act like this?
I don't feel like you are insulting me.
Isn't the Jing family best at reading signs?
Well, you can't even tell whether I'm praising you or insulting you now?
Hold on.
I still have something to tell you.
General Leng, please rest assured.
I will take good care of Leng Yue.
You mustn't think I don't know anything about the court
just because I'm in the Southwest.
It's your father who encouraged the emperor to grant marriage to Yue'er and Xiao Jinli.
There must be some misunderstanding.
Yes, there is some misunderstanding.
Sit down.
If I guess it right,
it must be that your father's informers found out that I'm seriously ill
and I keep it from the court.
That combined with the illegal minting of coins in Qianzhou,
he thought I was going to die soon
and I planned to occupy the Southwestern territory
for the Leng clan before I died.
He is afraid that I will do harm to your family in Qianzhou.
So he came up with such a way to keep me at bay by letting them get married.
Your father is an old fox.
He is still full of cunning tricks,
just like when he was young.
Now the truth has come to light. Please rest assured.
I'll write a letter to my father right away
and ask him to clarify this matter with the emperor.
You are too young.
You need to know the misunderstanding between your father and me is not new.
I heard that Commandery Prince An came here this time
to look for Prince Consort.
Have you found out the truth about
the miscarriage of justice of the Military Commissioner of Jiannan?
You knew what happened back then?
We have our own sources in the army.
What happened back then is little known.
But with all the pieces put together,
I knew a thing or two about it.
The Leng clan did something unethical
in order to protect ourselves.
After I took over the Leng clan,
I wanted to do something to make up for it.
I tried my best to save those so-called rebels
who escaped from your father.
But I had no evidence at all.
I knew the fact but I couldn't convince others.
Your father and I have been at odds,
but he is a man of honor and righteousness.
All the things that my father did
is because Prince Consort exonerated my father and saved his life.
No one knows the pain of being wronged better than my father does.
Now he knows the truth,
he won't stand by and do nothing.
You are a notorious boy,
but after my observation in the past few days,
I think you do have some balls.
I'll trust you this time.
After I get back to Chang'an,
I will have a good drink with your father
and say out loud all the swear words we have been saying
behind each other's back all these years.
General Leng, are you not going back to Chang'an
and find some good doctors to treat your illness first?
After so much chaos,
the army has been undermined.
Before the court appoints someone
to take over my job,
I'm not going anywhere.
Your trip back to Chang'an will be dangerous.
No matter what I say,
Yue'er will share weal or woe with you.
I only have one granddaughter.
I'll entrust her to you.
You must take good care of her.
Otherwise, I'll wipe out the Jing family
even at the cost of my life!
General Leng, please rest assured!
I don't seek merit or fame.
Leng Yue is my only pursuit in life!
You entrust your granddaughter to me.
I will never fail your trust!
[Jinguang Gate]
Hold on.
General Wu.
Candidates are gathering in Chang'an these days. Thank you for your hard work.
It's my job.
I dare not take credit for it.
- General, are you leaving Chang'an?
- Yes.
Are you trying to hack me?
Wu Jiang.
You can read?
Where are you going so early in the morning?
It's official business.
Is Commandery Prince An back?
Are you asking me?
General Zhou, I need to ask you whether Commandery Prince An has returned.
Since His Majesty ordered Commandery Prince An to return to Chang'an,
you've been lingering around the gate day and night with your men.
You have almost worn out your eyes.
You are like a little wife waiting for her husband.
Am I right?
Commandery Prince An hasn't come back.
I am not as tired as you are.
Look. You've been really busy while Commandery Prince An is away.
You even lost weight.
Don't say that.
I'm only busy with my own work.
I'm not like you.
You need to handle your work
and keep an eye on what others are doing at the same time.
You should all learn from General Zhou.
He only gets one paycheck,
but he does two jobs!
Give it back to me.
What? I haven't checked it out yet.
I can't leave without it.
I don't know if you are Wu Jiang if I don't check it out.
You want to play it in this way.
Your Highness.
I don't have time to make jokes with you.
I'm in a hurry to leave.
By the way, General Zhou.
You can keep following me as you want.
If you don't want to follow me, just wait for me right here.
I'll see you later.
Let's go.
[Notice]
Hey.
Yes, Sir.
What are you putting up?
It's the notice for the candidates.
There is a good harvest this year. His Majesty made an order to provide accommodation for all candidates.
Candidates need to register and move in right after they enter Chang'an and follow the arrangement.
Do you know who suggested that to His Majesty?
Sir, His Majesty said that Senior Jing's idea is good.
For the benefit of the candidates, His Majesty ordered us to do carry it out immediately.
Sir, do you have any other orders?
No orders, go away!
Let's go.
Well, now you have someone to back you up,
you are different now.
You don't even bother
to have a serious fight with an underdog like me.
My good sister.
I need to ask you a favor.
You must help me out.
According to the message from Wu Jiang,
Qin Luan has laid an ambush on the way to Chang'an
to prevent Commandery Prince An from returning to Chang'an.
Do you want my bros to escort you back?
No.
I need you to play a show with us.
Commandery Prince An has guessed what Qin Luan is up to.
Their fire and thunder bombs have been replaced by Wu Jiang.
We'll just pretend that we know nothing
and get attacked as they expect.
So you want me to
disguise myself as Chu Chu?
Darn! It's not her!
Draw out those who lay in ambush and wipe them out to
not let the court know that Commandery Prince An is returning to Chang'an.
- Let's go!
- Go!
Beauty, are you all right?
These little bandits are not enough for me to flex my muscles.
- Right.
- Go!
- Master, thanks.
- Hurry up!
You don't need to thank me.
I did it for Yue's sake.
Otherwise, the Zhenyuan Escort
would never get into your mess.
There is news from Commandery Prince An.
It goes well. Stick to the plan.
Your Grace, Jing Yi sent it to me from Qianzhou.
You know Jing Yi's handwriting.
[To Father]
[Father]
[They blended into the candidates and entered Chang'an...]
I really didn't expect
that the truth about my uncle is this.
It's also my fault for having a prejudice against General Leng.
I was impatient and careless.
I almost made a big mistake.
Thanks to these kids.
Otherwise, the consequences would be hard to imagine.
Sorry that I blamed you wrongly.
Please forgive me, Senior Jing.
Don't say anything like this, Your Grace.
I'm truly embarrassed now.
We both did it for the safety of Tang.
Yes.
Have you heard that the emperor has ordered
the kids to return to Chang'an?
Banxia already told me about it yesterday.
Don't worry, Minister Han.
You are fine.
Thank you.
Dr. Zhang, you have a benevolent mind and heart indeed.
If I remember it correctly,
you have been working in the Imperial Medical Service
since the time of Emperor Wenzong.
Yes.
When Princess Xiping was pregnant,
it was you who took care of her. Right?
To make sure Commandery Prince An and the kids can arrive in Chang'an safely,
I hope you can tell me the truth about one thing.
Please go ahead, Senior Jing.
Your Grace, is one of your sons
the child of Chen Ying, the former Military Commissioner of Jiannan?
Doctor Zhang, speaking of the twins,
I have something to ask you.
Commandery Prince An and General Xiao are twins,
but why are they so different in terms of looks and temperament?
Doctor Zhang, don't take me wrong.
I'm just curious about it.
I'm just asking.
I guess you got the news
that Qin Luan found in secret the two maids
who worked for you before.
That's why you sent people to stop them at the gate.
Senior Jing, Xiao Heng was your best friend.
He saved your life when you were in distress.
How can you bear to slander his sons?
Your Grace, Heng was a friend worth dying for.
That's why I asked you that question.
In this case, I won't keep it from you.
Before Heng left Chang'an, he asked me
to take good care of you in Chang'an.
Over these years, I've been sending people to secretly guard your mansion.
I've never been neglectful to this day.
Some time ago,
I heard that Qin Luan was secretly investigating your former maids.
I thought the emperor wanted to investigate it for General Xiao.
Later, I learned that you were also looking for those maids.
Then I started to suspect it.
Your Grace, I think you know why
Heng went to the base of Military Commissioner in Jiannan at that time.
Timing and subtitles brought to you by The Imperial Coroners @ Viki.com
♫  Nothing can stop me  ♫
♫  From missing you all the time  ♫
♫  The moonlight appears, cold in the late night,
as the world changes  ♫
♫  Only with you by my side can I embrace my yearning for you  ♫
♫  When I close my eyes I meet you once again  ♫
♫  I'll gently brush your hair by your ear  ♫
♫  Life is long, with love and regrets in this world  ♫
♫  With you by my side, no matter how far I go,
we'll never be apart  ♫
♫  With your smile, in this moment, let me
cherish this lifetime  ♫
♫  Only for you, I have to worry about the end of this life  ♫
♫  I’m still young, with my love not yet realized for you, but I'm
willing to be here for you till the end
♫  You can rely on me in this lifetime  ♫
♫  Hope to spend this beautiful lifetime together  ♫