[Summon Military Commissioner Chen Ying to Chang'an with his troops.]
Although Father left some evidence,
it's still not easy to redress an old case.
Qin Luan and his eunuchs buy and sell information in Rugui House
and monitor the court.
[The imperial stateliness is gone]
Chang'an is disturbed by Duke Chang.
Qianzhou is even more perilous.
Take her!
I don't want to implicate Commandery Prince An.
- Minister Xue.
- I can only do my duty as a coroner.
Tell me the truth.
When did you fall in love with Chu Chu?
Sir…
It's true that I haven't married.
But at my age, do you think I can't figure out
what is going on between you two?
The way you protected Chu Chu.
Jinyu, you lost your mind.
I dare not justify myself in front of you, sir.
In addition to the complicated situation, I did have a selfish motive
when I protected her today.
I know I was being unfair, but it's my own wishful thinking.
If you want to scold me, I won't have any complaints.
Well, well. I don't know what you are thinking.
There are so many noble girls in Chang'an.
Why do you have to fall for a coroner?
If Princess Xiping learns of it, if the emperor learns of it,
do you think a scolding is all you are going to get?
She's not only a coroner.
I know what you want to say.
Her biological parents were also officials.
But she was raised and educated by a family of coroners.
She even went to Chang'an to take the Coroner Qualification Test in the Three Judicial Offices.
Her being a survivor of the rebellious party has been widely talked about in court.
Now everyone in Chang'an knows it.
You should know these taints of her are difficult to clean.
If you are going to make such a mistake,
I will have no choice but to take her away.
I don't mean to offend you.
- But right now, I won't leave her to anyone.
- You...
The so-called taints are what made her who she is today.
I cherish them and value them.
I don't see them as taints.
Besides, you were also born in poverty.
Your achievements are attributed to your own efforts.
I've been listening to your teachings since childhood.
I know that one's fate is not decided by God.
I never judge people by their family.
What you said today contradicts what you taught me before.
I'm confused. Please enlighten me.
Forget it. You've gotten more articulate now.
Thank you for giving me a chance.
Timing and subtitles brought to you by The Imperial Coroners @ Viki.com
[The Imperial Coroner]
[Episode 23]
I mean, I know you don't like drinking or socializing
but you can't afford to not eat.
Here. I brought something you may like.
Have a little bit at least.
Isn't this a spoon?
Don't touch it.
Who is this? Why are you drawing her?
This is Chu Chu's mother.
She restored her mother's original appearance based on her mother's skull.
I'm drawing her by her statue.
Oh, right.
She talked about it when the coffin was opened that day.
But I didn't expect that she could actually restore a person's
original appearance based on the skull.
Miss Chu is not an ordinary coroner indeed.
I wish she were.
If she were just an ordinary coroner,
she wouldn't go through so many dangers.
Living a peaceful and happy life can be a good thing.
I can't believe you actually said that.
Looks like Jing Yi is right about it.
Qianzhou is not a land of plenty, but it nourishes humanity.
I can't believe I heard you agree with Jing Yi during my lifetime.
It seems that it won't take long for you two to become the same kind of people.
How can you compare him with me?
I'm much better than him.
Hurry up and eat.
If you don't eat it, I'll… I'll write a letter to Mother about it.
How is tomorrow's search for Xu Rugui in the mountain?
It's arranged now. Don't worry.
My boys didn't bring shame on General Leng.
They dressed up and have been searching the mountain these days.
Although they haven't found Xu Rugui, they have found some traces.
Do you have to go to the mountain in person tomorrow?
If you find Xu Rugui tomorrow,
you will go back to Chang'an immediately?
I heard from Jing Yi
that Leng Yue has been keeping an eye on you these days.
Since she knew the emperor wanted to grant us a marriage,
she has been haunting me like a ghost.
I guess she is still waiting outside right now.
Why?
She said if I dared to agree to marry her, she would dare to kill me.
What about Jing Yi?
He is drinking with someone in the front yard.
Go get Leng Yue here.
My Lord.
Come in.
Leave us.
My Lord.
What's the situation in Guanling County?
Has the survivor of the rebellious party been arrested?
Not yet.
Not yet? Are they going to arrest her or not?
I just want to take credit for it,
but I got nothing except for all these injuries!
I made a fuss for what?
My Lord, don't worry.
Minister Xue is still in Guanling County. He hasn't left.
I think he has other plans.
I also found out
that Commandery Prince An is going to search Phoenix Mountain tomorrow and capture Xu Rugui.
What do you think...?
What do I think?
I think...!
My Lord.
Send more people to keep a close eye on them!
- Go now!
- Yes!
- Hurry!
Xiao Jinyu is a scourge.
I have to figure out a way to get rid of him.
If you two don't want to get married,
you need to answer one question truthfully.
Not to mention one. I can answer a bunch of questions.
Is there anything unusual in the Military Commissioner's army recently?
I haven't been in touch with that person for many years.
How would I know if there is anything unusual?
Unusual? What king of unusual things?
Let me put it in this way.
During these days, is there any news about General Leng?
Any news.
Do you mean this marriage thing has something to do with General Leng?
It's he who wants me to marry Xiao Jinli?
It's still not very clear why the emperor wants to grant you a marriage.
But I'm sure it's related to the interests of the Military Commissioner of Qianzhongdao.
How come?
Everything was fine when I left the army.
There is no news from the army during this time.
This doesn't make sense.
That person and I are total strangers.
I will never agree to this marriage.
If he wants to force me,
I'll just give my life back to the Leng family.
Nothing is settled yet. Calm down and let Jinyu talk.
Leng Yue, you need to write a letter.
Write a letter? To whom?
General Leng.
What do you want me to write?
Any homely greetings will work.
Jinli, after Leng Yue finishes it,
you get someone to send the letter to the barracks immediately
and present it to General Leng.
Homely greetings?
To sound him out.
Leng Yue, I don't mean to intervene in your family affairs.
But it concerns the security of the southwest border of Tang,
and also the safety of tens of thousands of people in the Southwest.
I hope you can help me, and also help Tang.
Don't worry, I understand.
But you need to write a draft first.
I will copy it.
I can't write any homely greetings to that person.
Okay.
Stop tidying up. Get me a cup of tea.
I'm about to choke to death.
Every time you come back at this hour, you ask people to cook for you.
I will tell Commandery Prince An if you do it again next time.
General Wu, there is news from Pingkang Residence.
Qin Luan is somehow investigating the servants in Princess Xiping's mansion
who were dismissed in the early years.
The servants who were dismissed in the early years?
Yes.
And it's the year when Commandery Prince An and General Xiao were born.
How is it going in Princess Xiping's mansion now?
Everything is fine. No one came to make trouble.
Princess Xiping hasn't noticed it.
Should we warn Princess Xiping?
Keep an eye on Zhou Han first.
Wait for my news after I tell Commandery Prince An about it.
Yes.
To see him.
Not to see him.
To see her.
Not to see her.
Not to see him.
Your Highness.
Chu Chu.
Your Highness, this is the medicine from Miss Leng.
She has something else to do.
I decocted it.
Take it while it's hot.
Thank you.
You...
Come in first.
Your Highness, I...
I'm ready for your punishment.
Ready for my punishment?
I promised you on that day that, after we found Sir Witch Doctor,
I would accept any punishment from you.
Get up first.
Okay, I need you to do three things as my punishment for you.
Whatever you want.
First, get up.
That simple?
That's… one of the three things?
Second, forgive me.
Is that a punishment?
It was my fault when Chu He fell in the water on that day.
- It's me...
- Well...
That doesn't count.
I lost my temper and made you angry.
I should be the one to ask you for forgiveness.
Okay, then let's forgive each other.
That's your mother's relic.
Do you want to see it?
Go ahead.
So, this is the color my mother liked.
I drew this based on her appearance you restored and these clothes.
I only finished the lines.
I haven't colored it.
Don't worry.
These things will be returned to you later.
My mother was so pretty.
She's smiling at me.
You are so smart.
If she were alive, she would be proud of you.
I'll send it to you after I color it.
Thank you, Your Highness.
Chu Chu, as for the third thing…
I don't know what my father went through over the years.
He was living here alone and suffering from illness.
His life must've been hard.
As his son,
I couldn't stay by his side and take care of him.
It was you who were by his side in his hardest days.
Chu Chu, thank you.
Your Highness, what are you doing?
I can't take this.
I should be the one to thank Sir Witch Doctor.
He didn't despise me like other people did.
He spent time with me, told me stories,
and encouraged me when I was a kid.
I'm really grateful to him.
I will never forget him.
And you.
Have you decided?
I...
I don't know.
You don't know because the court wants to
arrest you and convict you
and you are afraid you will implicate me and leave me in a difficult place. Is that right?
Your Highness, you can give me up to them.
I believe you will reveal the truth to the world.
I'll go back to Chang'an and stay in jail for a while.
I'm not afraid.
Chu Chu, think about it.
I just found out your identity a few days ago.
There are still many things to be verified.
But the order was already made in Chang'an thousands of miles away to arrest you.
Do you know what this means?
Someone is on to you.
On to me? Who?
The Acting Chief Eunuch, Qin Luan.
He found your stone pendant and concluded that you knew my father.
Qin Luan is afraid that what happened back then will be revealed.
He wants to find my father through you and kill you both.
If you go back to Chang'an now, you are going to die.
Right now, there are many doubts in the case of the illegal minting of coins in Qianzhou.
A lot of people may be involved.
If I go back to Chang'an with you to protect you,
I'll fall for the trick of the person behind it.
Therefore, Chu Chu, if you insist on asking me to give you up to them,
you are leaving me in a difficult place.
What should I do then?
If you trust me, just stop worrying and stay by my side.
I know how to deal with my teacher.
What we can only do now is advance and retreat together.
I'll listen to you.
Are you willing to come back to me and stay with me forever?
Of course, I do.
I'm willing to be your coroner forever.
Not as a coroner.
Chu Chu, I want to spend every day with you
and take care of you forever.
Will you marry me?
You want to marry me?
Yes.
♫  With your smile  ♫
♫ In this moment ♫
♫  Let me cherish this lifetime  ♫
The medicine is almost cold. You should take the medicine first.
♫  I have to worry about the end of this life  ♫
♫  I’m still young  ♫
♫  With my love not yet realized for you  ♫
♫  But I'm willing to be here for you till the end  ♫
♫  You can rely on me in this lifetime  ♫
Chu Chu.
What's wrong?
Didn't you go to apologize to Commandery Prince An?
He didn't forgive you?
Or he scolded you?
Don't cry.
Tell me about it. Maybe I can help you.
How about this? Have some wine.
After a drink, you will forget all the troubles when you wake up tomorrow morning.
I'll drink with you.
Commandery Prince An proposed to me.
Did you say yes?
I'm willing to stay by his side as his coroner and stick with him.
I can do whatever he asks me to do.
But I can't marry him.
Why not?
Don't you like him?
I know what kind of person Commandery Prince An is.
Since he said that to you,
he is definitely not just talking about it.
Marrying a man is not the only important thing in a woman's life,
but if you miss the one you love,
you will regret it for the rest of your life.
Think about it carefully before you make any decision.
Your Highness.
Why did you ask me to come here from Chu's mansion in the middle of the night?
I think I did something stupid today.
Then learn from it and don't do it again.
Your Highness.
I proposed to Chu Chu and she rejected me.
You proposed to Chu Chu?
You said that I have someone in my heart and I need to think it through.
I thought about it. The person in my heart is Chu Chu.
But I didn't ask you to propose to her.
How can I be with her if I don't propose to her?
When? What did you say?
Tonight. She came to apologize to me.
And I just confessed.
What are you doing?
I want to see if you're out of your mind. Who would chase a girl in that way?
You proposed to her and confessed to her too soon.
You scared her off. How could she say yes?
It looked like she really was scared off.
It's my fault. I should have taken you out to enrich your experience.
Look what you did.
Come on.
Let me tell you...
Master, what are you burning?
Aren't these the files we brought from Rugui House?
Now we have gotten rid of Xu Rugui.
Do we need them no more?
You told me that Princess Xiping gave birth to two sons in that year, right?
I told Zhou Han about it.
Tell me about the rumors in Chang'an again.
Normally, when a woman bears two children,
it can be diagnosed by the doctor after six or seven months.
But the doctor who felt Princess Xiping's pulse
reported the good news to the palace
after Princess Xiping gave birth to her two sons.
At that time, Xiao Heng had left Chang'an for quite a long time.
Think about it.
How could the rumors sound good?
Go Ask Zhou Han to get some people to find them.
Make sure to bring them back to me alive.
Here are the clues.
Master, rest assured.
I'll ask Zhou Han to do it now.
Hurry up.
Why are you here?
I asked the imperial cook to make some snacks.
I'm here to bring the snacks to Eunuch Qin.
Jinbao, come here.
Yes.
What a bootlicker!
[Guanling Yamen]
Yesterday, I contradicted you.
I was being reckless.
You must think it over carefully.
Yes, I understand.
It's all ready.
Where is Vice Minister Jing?
Your Highness!
Your Highness. Something happened.
What's wrong?
It's my brother. He is missing again.
What? What do you mean again?
I noticed that Chu Ping didn't look right
when I was picking Chu He up.
I asked him and he knew that Chu He went out yesterday afternoon to find Xu Rugui.
But he didn't come back last night.
Leng Yue has sent people to find him.
Ridiculous!
He almost lost his life last time because of Xu Rugui.
He is not fully recovered yet and he did it again.
Your Highness, my father said my brother was determined to
get Xu Rugui back to redeem his mistake.
Otherwise, he would feel shameful and unqualified to work in the County Office.
Don't panic.
Only Chu He can find Xu Rugui in this place.
I've sent a lot of people into the mountain to search for Xu Rugui
and they didn't find him. Can Chu He find him on his own?
You mean Chu He is more familiar with this area
than the soldiers of the Military Commissioner.
It might be easier for him to find Xu Rugui.
Jinli's men didn't find him, but Chu He might be able to find him.
I've asked people to keep an eye on the few roads into the mountain.
I should've known it if he went into the mountain yesterday.
Unless there is another possibility.
Xu Rugui is not in Phoenix Mountain?
Not in Phoenix Mountain?
But Chu He said that he saw Xu Rugui going in the direction of Phoenix Mountain.
Xu Rugui is very familiar with this area.
I'm afraid that going in the direction of Phoenix Mountain
was just a smokescreen for those who were chasing him.
Chu He should have thought about it and figured out
where Xu Rugui might be hiding, that's why he left alone.
Chu Chu, think about it carefully.
Is there any other hiding place in the county
where Xu Rugui and Chu He both know of?
The hiding place...
He was injured.
He won't keep moving.
I think he should be hiding in a place.
He may think when we think he has escaped from Guanling County,
we will give up searching this place
and head for somewhere else to look for him.
Then he will take the chance to escape.
So it should be a place where he can get water and food easily.
Maybe it's a secret place. Maybe it's in a busy area.
A secret place in a busy area?
I know it.
The letter has been sent out?
What did you write?
None of your business.
I...
Do you remember what I told you yesterday?
But I still feel a little...
But what? You must listen to me at this time. Trust me.
Go ahead.
Your Highness, it's over there by the big tree.
Come on!
We found him! Hurry up!
Yes!
Brother.
Hurry up. Put him here.
Be careful.
Brother.
Come on. One, two.
Your Highness, have mercy!
Is my brother okay?
He's fine. He was knocked out.
Greetings to Commandery Prince An.
I got drunk last night and overslept.
Cut it out. What's this place?
Vice Minister.
This is a century-old tree, also the legendary Tree of Love.
Those who pray for love here will get what they want.
Your Highness, Xu Rugui lost too much blood.
He must be sent back to the County Office for treatment now.
Brother, you are awake.
Xu Rugui is still in the tree hole!
We found him. Brother, you found him.
You knocked him out.
I knew he must've been hiding here.
There is food and drink.
It's also convenient to ask for information.
It's just that I was careless and didn't notice the moss by the tree.
You are not careless, you are lucky.
If he didn't lose too much blood,
do you think you could talk about being careless right here?
But it's me who knocked him out.
All right, let's get back first.
Your Highness, about my brother letting go of Xu Rugui...
He has redeemed his mistake. He is reprieved.
Thank you, Your Highness.
Take Xu Rugui away.
- Come on. Go.
- Brother, get up.
Your Highness, I have something to tell you.
What is it?
[Princess Xiping's Mansion]
- Your Grace.
- How is it going?
The imperial astronomer has matched the horoscopes of General Xiao and Miss Leng, saying they are a good match.
I'm afraid after Mr. Xue comes back and General Xiao is promoted,
the emperor will grant a marriage to them.
[Memorial]
Han Ji is so greedy for credit.
He has been trying different ways to ask me
to urge Xue Rucheng to return with the survivor of the rebellious party.
He is not young anymore.
For such little credit, his manner looks too bad.
Your Majesty, I think Minister Han's concerns
are not totally unreasonable.
This is strange.
It's the first time you speak for Han Ji.
I'm not speaking for Minister Han.
I'm worried about you.
Worried about me?
Then tell me what you are worried about.
Your Majesty, Xue Rucheng was born in a humble family.
He got good grades in the examination
and got Senior Jing's appreciation.
Then he acquainted himself with Princess Xiping
and became Commandery Prince An and General Xiao's teacher.
Without those things, how could he become who he is today?
How do the things you said have anything to do with me?
Your Majesty, Xue Rucheng has a close relationship with Princess Xiping.
It's possible that he has feelings for Princess Xiping.
Right now, he is in the Southwest
inspecting the military affairs of Qianzhou for Your Majesty.
If he stays there for too long and gets in touch with the Leng clan...
Your Majesty. Commandery Prince An, General Xiao, Vice Minister Jing,
and Leng Peishan's only granddaughter are all in Qianzhou.
We have to guard against them.
You are even more prudent than I am.
I just always bear Your Majesty in mind.
[Jing's Mansion]
[Father]
Master, what you have done is for avenging Prince Consort.
If he knew it in the underworld...
I feel guilty for Xiao Heng.
I have to finish the things he wanted to do when he was alive.
Master, if this matter is uncovered,
I'm afraid the Southwest will be in a bigger mess.
Leng Peishan concealed his illness.
Now there is illegal minting of coins in Qianzhou.
What he is plotting to have is not just military power.
If Leng Peishan is really up to something bigger,
doesn't that mean Young Master Jing Yi is in great danger over there?
At this point,
I have to take a gamble.
Master, what are you going to bet on?
He has a favorable geographical position.
I'll bet on timing and people.
I have asked the emperor to give them more power
in the name of dealing with the illegal minting.
I hope Commandery Prince An can play to the score.
It should not be too late.
I can only guarantee that he won't die for now.
As for if he can wake up and talk, you need to find someone else to treat him.
Thank you for today. Go back and have some rest.
Okay.
You've found Xu Rugui.
Why are you still staying in Qianzhou?
There is something unfinished in Qianzhou.
I must stay here and find it out.
Jinyu, did you forget what I told you?
The longer you stay here, the greater the danger will be.
If anything happens to you, how should I explain to Princess Xiping?
Sir, if I don't solve it, I can't explain it to the court,
and I can't explain to my father.
Leng Peishan's affairs are military affairs.
It should be the Ministry of War that investigates it.
If there is anything special, they will ask Three Judicial Offices for support.
Even you are in charge of the Three Judicial Offices,
you can't intervene in military affairs.
What I want to investigate is not military affairs.
Then, what do you want to investigate?
When Jinli's men went into the mountain to search for Xu Rugui a few days ago,
they found some sneaky people who didn't look like villagers.
I thought it was Xu Rugui trapped in the mountain.
But now, it seems that there should be someone else.
What are you suspecting?
Sir, do you still remember
the copper coins sent to you and Senior Jing by Wu Jiang?
Of course.
I found some illegally minted coins in Qianzhou
and asked the Prefect of Qianzhou, Li Zhang, to handle the case.
I suspect that those sneaky people in the mountain
are related to the case of illegally minted coins.
Military Commissioner's soldiers dressed up and went into the mountain, which made them panic.
Maybe there is an important clue in the Phoenix Mountain about this illegal minting of coins.
You do have to investigate it.
There is another strange thing.
When Li Zhang caught me on that day, I saw his hands.
Li Zhang's hands?
There were a lot of new and old small cuts on his hands.
Cuts?
According to Chu Chu, those cuts should be caused by small flat sharp tools.
Such wounds are often found on the hands of sculptors.
That's not strange.
I heard about it.
Li Zhang was born in a poor family.
When he was a child studying in the temple,
he learned some carving skills to support his life.
As far as I know, he hasn't given up carving till now.
I've also heard about it.
But I have a question about the minting of the coins.
You also saw that the fake coins
minted in Qianzhou are nearly the same as the real coins.
The coin mold was copied really well.
However, the official coin mold is so important
that even a prefect can't reach it at will.
But if someone who can carve stuff
and have access to the official coin mold, he can memorize
its details and size, and then copy it.
That makes sense.
You suspect that Li Zhang is involved
in the case of minted coins?
It's only my speculation now.
After we find their mint, everything will be clear.
I can't intervene in the affairs of the Three Judicial Offices.
You can decide for yourself.
But it's the emperor's order to bring Chu Chu back to Chang'an.
Either I take her back, or I take back the truth of Prince Consort's case.
Please forgive me.
Neither Chu Chu nor the evidence about my father's case
can be taken away by you.
Timing and subtitles brought to you by The Imperial Coroners @ Viki.com
♫  Nothing can stop me  ♫
♫  From missing you all the time  ♫
♫  The moonlight appears, cold in the late night,
as the world changes  ♫
♫  Only with you by my side can I embrace my yearning for you  ♫
♫  When I close my eyes I meet you once again  ♫
♫  I'll gently brush your hair by your ear  ♫
♫  Life is long, with love and regrets in this world  ♫
♫  With you by my side, no matter how far I go,
we'll never be apart  ♫
♫  With your smile, in this moment, let me
cherish this lifetime  ♫
♫  Only for you, I have to worry about the end of this life  ♫
♫  I’m still young, with my love not yet realized for you, but I'm
willing to be here for you till the end  ♫
♫  You can rely on me in this lifetime  ♫
♫  Hope to spend this beautiful lifetime together  ♫