Timing and subtitles brought to you by The Imperial Coroners @ Viki.com
"We can't meet as scheduled."
[4 7 3 1 5 10 8 6 2 9 8 10 7]
Some rebels snuck into Chang'an
[We can't meet as scheduled.]
disguised as candidates.
With the help of Zhenyuan Escort,
[Jinguang Gate]
Jinli and Leng Yue attracted the attention of the eunuchs.
Then we returned to Chang'an in secret as planned.
Hope we can prevent their plot.
[It goes well. Stick to the plan.]
I think you know why
[Princess Xiping's Mansion]
Heng went to the base of
the military commissioner in Jiannan at that time.
Not only do I know it, the kids all know it.
Your Grace, there was an unborn child in Chang'an
about the age of your unborn child.
There were many reasons why you had to conceal his identity.
I guess the child you adopted in secret
is the child of Chen Ying's wife.
Qin Luan tracked down your former maids.
He wants to use the kid to make waves.
Your Grace, you have to tell me the truth.
Then I can figure out a solution to help the kids out.
Otherwise, it will be too late.
- Well...
- Your Grace.
This is...
Where's Mrs. Chen?
She took a drug to induce labor.
The blood wouldn't stop after she gave birth to the boy.
She's passed away.
- Your Grace.
Madam asked me to tell you something before she died.
When Master returned to Chang'an to report on his work,
he was excited about having a child.
He would never rebel right after returning to the Southwest.
For the sake of your friendship with Madam,
please make the bloodline of the Chen clan last.
We dare not ask you to clear the name of the Chen clan.
But please save their son's life.
Your Grace.
The child is innocent.
[The Imperial Coroner]
[Episode 32]
Master, the time is up.
There is no military report from the Southwest.
Really?
No news at all?
Right. Should we act on the plan?
Hold on.
General Zhou.
Who are in the carriage?
The girls we sent out last night to drink with our customers.
We are just bringing them back.
- Are there any newcomers?
- Yes.
- Let me take a look.
- Go ahead.
General Zhou, do you still remember me?
I really miss you.
Yes, your name is Cuixiang.
Move yourself. Let me take a look at the newcomers.
Give me a smile.
Great.
Sit tight.
Go.
General Zhou, you are welcome to visit us.
Thanks, girls.
You are welcome, Mr. Jing.
General Zhou, nothing suspicious.
What are these?
Sir, these are fresh foods for Guangtai House. It's a long trip.
To keep the foods fresh, we use ice to keep them cold.
You just saw it. We prepared ice cubes for this trip.
Zhenyuan Escort even started to deliver fresh foods.
It's a difficult time to make a living now.
We are glad that our old clients hired us.
Thank you for guarding the city.
Have a drink and relax yourself when you have time.
Go.
- Thank you, Sir.
- Hurry up.
Go.
Fire! Fire!
- Fire!
- Help!
Fire! Put out the fire!
Help!
Fire!
- Hurry. This way.
- Hurry up!
Save Master!
Master is still in the study!
Master... Master...
- Master...
- Mr. Xue.
General Wu.
Commandery Prince An.
Why are you...?
Where is Mr. Xue?
Master is...
Your Highness, you're late.
- Master...
- It's impossible.
Your Highness.
It's impossible.
When the study was on fire, we were all sleeping.
The person on night watch slacked off and didn't notice the fire in time.
It was already too late when we noticed the fire.
Your Highness, you don't want to look at him.
Master is unrecognizable now.
He definitely doesn't want to meet you in this way. Your Highness.
I made the order not to tell anyone
when I came to visit my teacher.
Did you forget that?
I dare not.
I don't believe it.
I don't believe he just died.
- Chu Chu.
- Your Highness.
I want to know what my teacher went through before he died.
And...
if there is anything he wanted to say.
Okay.
Your Highness, you...
Master... Master!
Master...
Master... Master...
Jing Yi, look at the bolt.
The door must have been broken from the outside.
Are you sure?
I've broken more doors than any windows you have ever jumped out of.
How can I be wrong?
Do you mean Minister Xue didn't get out of the fire before he fainted because of the smoke?
Wu Jiang.
Here.
Your Highness, stop looking at it.
I don't believe he would be so careless.
He was never a careless person.
If there was a fire outside, there is no way he wouldn't have noticed it.
He let himself be burned to death.
If that's the case, there must be some reason.
You suspect he was murdered?
He died just as I came back to Chang'an.
How can there be such a coincidence?
But we came back in secret.
The people who know that we are back are only my father and Wu Jiang.
Who would kill Minister Xue at this time?
Why would they kill Minister Xue?
Calm down.
I know it's hard to accept.
But this might just be an accident.
The fire didn't start from one place.
There was a fire source outside the house, and also a fire source inside the house.
Look at the pillar.
It looks black at first glance.
But if you take a closer look,
you can find the smoke marks vary in shades
and are branch-like.
You are right.
That's how you find the fire source.
The darkest place is the source of the fire.
It should be this brazier.
The comburent was placed in this brazier.
This fire is definitely not an accident.
Your Highness, since this person set a fire outside the house,
why would the person bother to set another fire inside the house to cover it up?
I think the person set a fire
in the study to fully burn the house
and burn as many things as possible.
And also...
Your Highness, come here!
Your Highness.
- Chu Chu.
- Your Highness, he is not Mr. Xue.
What?
He is not Mr. Xue.
Chu Chu, you only met Mr. Xue a few times.
Are you really sure it's not him?
Yes.
The figure of this person is very similar to that of Mr. Xue.
But it can be judged from the teeth wear
[Tooth wear]
that this person was in his early twenties at most.
[About 20]
He is definitely not Mr. Xue.
Besides, his skin curled up and there is no pus or blisters.
There are marks of strangulation on his neck.
His hyoid is also broken.
[Marks of strangulation on the neck]
He was not burned to death.
[Broken hyoid]
He was strangled alive and then burned by fire.
How is it possible?
If he is not Master, why was he in Master's study?
Where did Master go then?
Who is he?
[Token]
Why do you have the...
access token of the Ministry of War?
Master worried that he would forget to take it,
so he always gave it to me when he came back and let me keep it.
I would give it to him before he left.
It's weird. How could there be such a thing?
What's wrong?
Your Highness, look at this.
There is Snake Killer.
- Snake Killer?
- What's that?
Your Highness, smell it.
It's fragrant.
Yes, this herb emits fragrance when it's blooming.
People feel refreshed when they smell it.
But snakes will hide away when they smell it.
This herb can repel snakes and detoxify snake venom.
It works much better than herbs for detoxifying snake venom like lobelia.
But there are few snakes in the courtyards of Chang'an.
Why would Mr. Xue grow this kind of herb?
Not just here. There and over there.
It was planted in several places in this yard.
I guess there is Snake Killer in other yards.
Is that true?
Yes, Master asked us to grow it.
I don't know what kind of herb it is.
That's weird.
I never heard that Mr. Xue was so afraid of snakes.
Your Highness, did Mr. Xue ever live in the Southwest?
Why do you ask that?
People in the Southwest will grow
a few Snake Killer in front of and behind the house
and also near the barn no matter if they are afraid of snakes or not.
When the people around all grow it,
if someone doesn't grow it, the snake will go to his place.
I grow the plant at my place.
It was also planted in the backyard of the Guanling County Office.
But it really looks like a weed.
And it's usually planted in unremarkable places under the wall.
Your Highness, you never noticed it. Right?
You mean even if you live in Chang'an,
knowing that there are no snakes in Chang'an,
you will still grow Snake Killer.
Yes.
I grew up watching every household grow it since I was a kid.
I know the snakes won't come when I see it.
If I don't see it in the place where I live in,
especially in the season when snakes and insects are widespread in the Southwest,
I'll still feel uneasy though I know
that there are no snakes in Chang'an.
But Mr. Xue is a native of Chang'an.
Mr. Xue, have you ever heard that Minister Xue
ever lived in the Southwest?
No.
- Wu Jiang.
- Your Highness.
- Send Chu Chu back to the Three Judicial Offices.
- Yes.
Jing Yi, come with me.
[Office of the Ministry of War]
Who are you?
We are from the Three Judicial Offices.
[Token]
Please.
Your Highness, what are you looking for?
Your Highness?
Your Highness...
It's really him.
Who?
Who's him? Who are you talking about?
This is the memorial of the Ministry of War, right?
"Rebels in Qianzhou attempted to seize the base?"
This is what happened at the base of the military commissioner.
What's wrong?
According to the rules, the military report will be
sent to the Ministry of War first.
Then he will draw up a memorial
and present it to the emperor with the military report.
That's right.
The memorial is here. Where is the report?
The report...
I sspecially told General Leng to block the message.
The military report must be presented by Jinli to the court in person.
Jinli and the military report are still on the way.
How could Minister Xue know it in advance?
Without the military report, except us,
the only person who can be so familiar with the situation
is the so-called Duke Chang.
He wrote such a memorial in advance and left it in the Ministry of War to...
To be prepared in both ways.
Uprising and seizing the base are of great importance.
Zhao Jie must have discussed with him in advance.
Ten days from the day of seizing the base
is the latest day that the urgent military report arrives in Chang'an,
which is today.
If Zhao Jie wins,
the Ministry of War won't receive the military report.
He will get rid of the identity of Xue Rucheng
and raise in rebellion in the name of Duke Chang.
What if Zhao Jie fails?
If Zhao Jie fails,
General Leng will send a military report to the Ministry of War.
The military report is a warning signal.
He carefully drew up a cumbersome memorial in advance.
If he receives the military report,
he will present the memorial and cause turmoil in court
to get more time for him to handle it and escape.
Today is my rebirth
and the day that I become Duke Chang again.
I've endured humiliation and moved carefully for more than ten years.
I hired a killer in Rugui House
and used Qin Luan's people to get rid of
the obstacles on the way to my great cause.
I carefully planted useful people
and I've been planning and preparing.
He used the dancing girl to kill Yan Ming.
I heard from Commandery Prince An that you killed Yan Ming only to steal something.
He wanted to use me to find out why Yan Ming was killed
and whip up the public opinion that Duke Chang is still alive.
Then he will lead his troops
[Duke Chang, The royal family]
to seize the Southwest,
[Duke Chang, The royal family mystery]
press forward to Chang'an and usurp the throne in the name of Duke Chang.
I didn't expect Xiao Jinyu to find out the truth
about the counterfeit money.
[Qian]
If I had more time
to fully disperse the counterfeit money among the people,
the government would lose its prestige
[County Office of Qianzhou]
and I would win the hearts of the people.
I got rid of Liu Yue, the Minister of Revenue…
To cover up the fact that he made counterfeit money in Qianzhou.
I killed Lu Chuansheng, the Capital Liaison Representative in Qianzhou…
to cut off the communication between Qianzhou and the imperial court.
And also the Minister of War, Feng Jie, who went to inspect the Southwest.
Thank you for your reward, Your Majesty.
He intercepted the news that Leng Peishan was seriously ill.
[Map of the Ministry of War]
Then he took over the position of the Minister of War.
As the Minister of War,
I can learn the movements of all parties
and carry out the military plan without a sound.
I've taken care of everything.
But Xiao Jinyu suddenly had this female coroner
who found out the truth about the death of Feng Jie and others.
Xiao Jinyu followed the clues
and investigated all the way to Qianzhou.
What I really worry about
is the person who hired killers to kill
Liu Yue, Lu Chuansheng, and Feng Jie.
Soldiers, money, and news are all abnormal.
[Guanling County, Qianzhou]
They all gather in the Southwest.
If I may be so bold,
this person is up to something big.
I'm afraid it might jeopardize the stability of the Southwest of Tang.
I should have made them disappear forever in Qianzhou.
He knew that Qin Luan would send people to intercept and kill us.
He wanted to reap the benefits.
[Qianzhou]
But it didn't go as I expected.
Xiao Jinli showed up and saved your life temporarily.
[Tang]
He learned I entered Qianzhou alive,
[Tang Chang'an]
then he created an excuse to inspect the Southwest.
I have another thing to do in Qianzhou.
[Jinyu went to Qianzhou]
Among the reports of Minister Feng's inspection of the Southwest,
there is one volume missing.
It's fine if he lost it accidentally.
But if someone doesn't want me to see the inspection report,
who would be that person?
He led His Majesty to be wary of Leng Peishan.
Then he took the opportunity and volunteered to come to Qianzhou
to cover up his conspiracy.
The wounds on Prefect Li's hands
fit these tools perfectly in terms of shape and size.
It's you who made the coin molds!
That useless Li Zhang.
He failed to kill Xiao Jinyu again.
He even lost to a female coroner.
What a rebel!
If it weren't for Li Zhang's insanity,
I would have guessed it was him.
Fortunately, I was well prepared in the Southwest.
Leng Peishan has been poisoned by cinnabar for a while.
Li Zhang used the cover of Qianzhou's soldiers to recruit and train soldiers.
Wu Chen used datura flower to make the soldiers go crazy and neutralize the military.
Zhao Jie took the opportunity to seize the base
and then take over the military power in the Southwest in the name of Duke Chang
to help me achieve my great cause.
Right now, he doesn't know Zhao Jie failed.
He thinks everything is going on as he scheduled.
He didn't flee in a hurry tonight.
He followed his plan to prepare for the next step.
I still have an important bargaining chip.
Xu Rugui.
He played a trick to take Xu Rugui away.
Then he learned the secret in my father's suicide letter.
He got Qin Luan's vital point
and forced Qin Luan to collude with him.
[Rugui]
Duke Chang is willing to join hands with you to kill the tyrant.
I can't believe
that I gave Xu Rugui to him in person.
Your Highness, what do you plan to do next?
I do not know.
Master, it's not good.
Commandery Prince An and Jing Yi went to the Ministry of War.
Xiao Jinyu is back alive?
Zhou Han is useless indeed.
He can do nothing.
Come here.
Go to do what I told you before immediately.
The prescription that Doctor Li wrote last time works really well.
Yeah.
Isn't Doctor Zhang on duty today?
Why is it dark in the room?
I remember there was light when we went there.
Why is the door not closed?
Doctor Zhang is old now. Could it be that something happened to him?
Doctor Zhang.
Doctor Zhang, are you inside?
Doctor Zhang!
Save him!
General Wu, I heard that Commandery Prince An is back.
I cooked something for him.
Just go back, Miss Chu.
His Highness has been in Thought Chamber since he came back.
He told me to guard here and let no one disturb him.
But His Highness didn't eat anything on his way here.
He will feel uncomfortable if he doesn't eat anything at night.
General Wu, I just want to check on him.
I'll leave right after I send him the food.
I won't annoy him.
Miss Chu, just go back.
I was kicked out by him before I reached the door.
Just take my advice.
After His Highness finishes his work, I will let you know.
- But...
- Just let Miss Chu in.
Otherwise, Miss Chu can't rest at ease.
Thank you, General Wu.
Get out!
Your Highness...
Your Highness, I made some soup for you.
Why don't you have some soup first?
I'll have the soup.
It's late.
Go to sleep.
♫ If you walk into the rest of my life ♫
Your Highness, you traveled day and night,
and hardly had any sleep.
You constantly have stomachaches.
And you don't want to eat anything. You've lost a lot of weight.
♫ Spend our lives through time ♫
If you just want to give an explanation to His Majesty,
I can give you Xu Rugui.
Xu Rugui?
♫ We're by each other's side ♫
These are the cases I handled before.
Whenever I had difficulties,
I would take them out and read them.
Looking at these souls
who had rested in peace,
and thinking about
those who were still waiting for me to clear their names,
no matter how difficult it was,
I would still believe I could take it.
But now...
I'm too ashamed to face them.
Chu Chu.
My teacher, Xue Rucheng,
he is the person...
who hired killers in Chang'an to kill officials.
He killed Yan Ming
and started the rumors about Duke Chang.
He made counterfeit money in Qianzhou.
He kept soldiers in private
and hoarded soldiers, horses, food, and weapons.
He is the head of the rebellious party that attempted to seize the base.
What about me?
I investigated from Chang'an to Qianzhou,
then from Qianzhou to Chang'an.
I investigated and investigated.
It turns out this person...
has been right in front of me.
I'm like a blind man.
It's not your fault.
How is it not my fault?
He went to Qianzhou to clear the obstacles for his great cause.
But I told him everything about the counterfeit money case!
I even gave Xu Rugui to him in person!
I gave him a bargaining chip to collude with Qin Luan!
How can there be such a stupid judge?
How can such a stupid person run the Three Judicial Office?
It's not true.
Your Highness, you are just a judge of Tang.
You are not a god.
How can you know everything without any clue?
Who else could put these
irrelevant cases together?
If it weren't for you to risk your life to investigate it,
General Leng's army would have been taken down by them.
You prevented a disaster for the people in the Southwest of Tang.
They have escaped now.
But we still have a chance to catch them back.
We still can stop his conspiracy in Chang'an.
You are the best judge in Tang.
I'm not as good as you said.
I've been sick and weak since I was a kid.
I always strive for the best
and push myself to the extreme.
He is the one who taught me
to act according to my ability and that is the long-term solution.
I kept it from my mother when I started to learn the law.
She only wants me to live a peaceful life.
If it weren't for him to persuade my mother,
I couldn't become a judge at all.
After I went to the court,
I didn't understand the so-called way of the world.
Sometimes I provoked discontent from the officials
and enraged the emperor.
He always took the blame for me
and helped me out.
I can't figure it out.
If he has been planning this from the beginning,
why would he teach me
and protect me over these years?
I've suspected countless people to be the leader of the rebellious party.
I suspected almost everyone but not him.
He keeps helping you
perhaps because he knows you would still become who you are now
without his help.
He is your teacher.
You should respect him.
But he failed your respect.
He is the one who failed you.
♫ Let time pass by ♫
He used to protect you.
But you ended up like this.
From now on, I'll protect you.
♫ I'll still hold your hands ♫
♫ The pattern of destiny is engraved on the palm of your hand ♫
♫ If you walk into the rest of my life ♫
♫ Stay with each other gently ♫
Your Highness, you are always the fairest person.
Can you also be fair to yourself?
He is the one who did bad things.
He should be the one to be punished.
But why would you lock yourself up and blame yourself?
This will only make him more pleased.
You are right.
I should bring him to justice
and let him be punished...
instead of blaming myself
and making those who care about me worry.
This is the last time I will call him "teacher."
From now on,
I'm a judge and he is a rebel.
No matter where he hides,
I will arrest him.
No matter what you do,
and no matter how difficult it is,
I'll be there for you.
Remember, you are not allowed to lock yourself up again.
♫ We're by each other's side ♫
I've remembered it.
Timing and subtitles brought to you by The Imperial Coroners @ Viki.com
♫  Nothing can stop me  ♫
♫  From missing you all the time  ♫
♫  The moonlight appears, cold in the late night,
as the world changes  ♫
♫  Only with you by my side can I embrace my yearning for you  ♫
♫  When I close my eyes I meet you once again  ♫
♫  I'll gently brush your hair by your ear  ♫
♫  Life is long, with love and regrets in this world  ♫
♫  With you by my side, no matter how far I go,
we'll never be apart  ♫
♫  With your smile, in this moment, let me
cherish this lifetime  ♫
♫  Only for you, I have to worry about the end of this life  ♫
♫  I’m still young, with my love not yet realized for you, but I'm
willing to be here for you till the end
♫  You can rely on me in this lifetime  ♫
♫  Hope to spend this beautiful lifetime together  ♫