Timing and subtitles brought to you by The Imperial Coroners @ Viki.com
Xu Rugui follows Qin Luan's orders.
For all these years, he's been secretly investigating my father.
Xiao Heng escaped.
Catch him.
There must be more secrets behind the Military Commissioner of Jiannan's usurp.
Qin Luan must have held something back from the imperial court.
Maybe we can only find the answer
when we decipher the mysteries my father left behind.
Sir Witch Doctor drew these.
He likes to draw?
He didn't like it so much.
But right before he left, he somehow started to like it.
He drew nothing else.
He just drew mountains and trees.
These are the views of Guanling County.
The mountain is Phoenix Mountain.
The river is Yong'an River.
The light.
Your Highness, what's on your mind?
Does he always have such thick window paper?
No. It might have started when he began to like drawing.
At that time, he bought many drawing papers.
Some were used to draw. Others were used as window paper.
He said it was windy at night. Air wouldn't come through if window paper was thick.
Chu Chu, pull down the curtains.
[The Imperial Coroner]
[Episode 18]
Your Highness, it's done.
See if the other side's wall is different.
- The wall?
- Yes.
Your Highness, come take a look.
There's a small bright spot on the wall.
I found it.
There's a small hole that has penetrated the wall.
It was covered by both sides' drawing paper.
When the room is dim,
if we light candles in the other side's cabinet,
the candle light will
cast this bright spot on this side's drawing paper.
Did Sir Witch Doctor do this?
In the previous Sui Dynasty, construction was often performed.
Once, 300,000 taels of construction fee got lost abruptly during transport.
[Rapid constructions]
They found no trace of it
[Transporting construction fund]
until the judge found out how they hid the money.
Then, the world knew the truth.
[Judge]
The ministers involved in the case
[Notice]
used the principle of Borrowed Light.
[Truth came to light]
They used the tavern wall and the paintings to
design a map to mark the location where they hid the money.
[Borrowed light]
So they can split booty afterward.
[Treasure]
This case was adapted into novels
and was spread widely across the nation.
I think my father learned this trick from it.
Your Highness, something went wrong with the Chu family.
Let's go.
Your Highness.
It's my fault. Please punish me.
Grandfather, are you all right?
I'm fine. But your brother is missing.
Grandfather, don't worry.
His Highness is here. My brother will be fine.
What happened? Who did this?
- Where is Xu Rugui?
- Your Highness, we don't know what happened earlier.
Xu Rugui suddenly broke free from the ropes, attacked us, and tried to run away.
When we were fighting, these people who dressed like bandits broke in.
Xu Rugui was obviously their target. We were outnumbered.
Xu Rugui escaped amid the chaos.
The bandits went to pursue Xu Rugui. Zhang Yun went after them.
I stayed here to ensure the Chu family's safety.
[Rope File]
[Cut]
- Where is Chu He?
- We didn't notice that.
We also didn't hear another fight.
We only found Chu He missing, when the Chu family's seniors asked us.
Don't worry, Your Highness. I've already asked people from the County Office to pursue them.
- How many bandits ran away?
- Two.
Chu He spent time alone with Xu Rugui?
Yes, Your Highness.
Chu He brought food to Xu Rugui.
He spent around 30 minutes alone with Xu Rugui.
Chu He?
This is a tool for carpenter work.
Xu Rugui must have used this to cut the rope.
Why would Chu He help Xu Rugui escape?
Why did you allow Chu He and Xu Rugui to spend time alone?  You—
It's my fault. Your Highness, please punish us.
Your Highness.
Chu Chu, inspect the bodies first.
Okay.
The dead is well built.
There are thick calluses on his palms which were formed because of training.
The wound on his chest is fatal.
This man has the same calluses.
These people were soldiers.
Soldiers?
I can tell from the calluses on their palms.
These were formed from years of training as soldiers.
The training for soldiers is different from the training of martial art learners.
So the calluses are different, too.
Soldiers?
Are they Shence soldiers sent by Qin Luan to silence Xu Rugui?
(Shence Army was a Tang dynasty army unit, based in Chang'an, forming the core of the imperial guards responsible for protecting the emperor.)
The group of people who broke in first had Shence Army's fighting skills.
But those who broke in later are weird.
Xu Rugui broke free from the rope and fought with us.
At that moment, the first group broke in.
They were determined to kill Xu Rugui.
Then the next group broke in.
They didn't try to kill Xu Rugui.
On the contrary, they tried to protect him.
These two groups of people also engaged in fights themselves.
Those who tried to kill Xu Rugui
were from the Shence Army.
The other group were here to catch him.
Catch him?
That's weird.
No, it isn't. This is the fight between the snipe and the mussel.
The snipe and the mussel?
Qin Luan's Rugui House is the buyer.
Those who committed the crimes at Qianzhou are the seller.
This originally should be a trade that benefited both parties.
Now, Rugui House's case has been solved.
They're now the snipe and the mussel.
Now, the mussel knows everything about Rugui House.
They want to control Xu Rugui and use him as leverage
to become the buyer.
What are you talking about? I'm so confused.
How can you be confused? Let me explain it.
His Highness means that there are two parties of bad people.
- Two parties?
- Yes.
One side wanted to kill people.
But they were unwilling to do it themselves. So they paid for hitmen.
The other group of people commits murders for money.
Think about it. Killing for money is supposed to be a secret.
So, the buyer just knows whether the target has been killed or not.
They won't know who does it.
But now His Highness has shut down Rugui House.
The buyers now know Xu Rugui is the one who collected the money.
So, the buyer discovered that Qin Luan is behind Xu Rugui
and tried to use Xu Rugui to threaten Qin Luan.
I get it. Then this is a double-cross.
That's right.
Clear the floor first.
Jinli, your men are more familiar with this neighborhood.
Please send more men to search for Chu He.
Oh. Take Chu He's dog with you.
It's familiar with Chu He's scent. It can somehow help.
Xu Rugui was badly wounded after this fight.
He can't go far.
Pay attention to the hiding spots nearby.
Okay.
Jing Yi. Leng Yue. Go to the County Office and bring more people.
Clear this area. Just tell them the bandits attacked. Nothing more.
- Yes.
- Okay.
Chu Chu, come with me.
What?
Didn't you hear it? There was a breathing sound.
Someone has been following us.
No. You must have made a mistake.
It's our own breathing sound.
Xu Rugui is just ahead of us. Hurry.
Xu Rugui is very cunning.
Beware of his traps.
So annoying.
The forest is rainy. The road is muddy.
The passersby will leave foot tracks. Observe the road.
Yes!
Your Highness, actually I...
You already know, don't you?
What should I know?
About my father and mother.
You've interrogated Xu Rugui.
So, you must know everything.
He did say something about your father and mother.
But those haven't been verified.
After I verify it, I'll tell you everything honestly.
Did he tell you that my father is
the rebel, Yun Yi?
Yes.
But it's just his one-sided accusations.
We can't come to a conclusion for now.
Can you tell me the things you have verified about my father and mother?
Xu Rugui is lying, right?
Bad people all lie, right?
I went to the Xu Mansion to look for you because Xu Rugui left this hairpin behind.
You're saying that Xu Rugui intentionally left this at the scene for you?
Why would he do that?
At first, I didn't understand either.
So I rushed back to the County Office and looked through your mother's bequest.
And I found out that your father might be an officer who worked for the Military Commissioner of Jiannan.
Then I understood his intention.
What is it?
He led me on the investigation of your father,
hoping it can destroy our trust in each other
and force you to leave and become a part of his team.
So, what Xu Rugui said is real?
I told you.
It hasn't been verified. So we can't reach a conclusion.
But you've already deduced that he might be an officer for the Military Commissioner of Jiannan.
Then... is he the rebel, Yun Yi, that Xu Rugui talked about?
That's exactly why Xu Rugui is cunning.
He wanted me to discover this when I was looking for you.
I would easily forget that my original intention was to search for your whereabouts.
Instead, I would go on an investigation to see whether your father was the rebel.
In that case, he would have more time to get out of the pursuit.
But, Your Highness—
Chu Chu, finding your whereabouts is different from the investigation of your father's identity.
The only connection is the fact that Xu Rugui wants to use it to distract me.
What about now?
If my father is really the rebel, Yun Yi, will I get you in trouble?
Jinli.
General Xiao, why are you here?
This road leads to the mountain.
Are you going to the mountain area to look for my brother?
What happened?
Chu He might have fallen into the river by accident.
A clear mark at the upper stream's riverside indicated that someone fell into the water.
The mark is roughly the same size as Chu He's footprint.
When we reached the spot, we also heard a scream from Chu He.
And this dog's reaction also confirmed that Chu He was once there.
But after that, we found no trace of him.
My brother is a good swimmer. He can get back to shore soon.
Chu Chu, don't worry.
Chu He might have swum to the opposite riverside.
I was talking to Chu Chu back then. We didn't pay attention to the river.
He might have swum to the other side.
Jinli, please take some men and search the opposite riverside.
This row. Go search the other side.
Yes.
Jinyu, come over here.
What?
I haven't had time to talk about this with you.
Chu He made such a scene.
I think it's about that case.
We don't have time to waste. Just say it.
I accidentally heard Chu He and his father's conversation in the kitchen.
If I marry Chu Chu, she will be my wife then.
Whether she accepts the family or not, she is part of the Chu family.
Even if you want to, you have to get the approval of Chu Chu.
Ridiculous! He is...
What?
They're not related by blood.
And over the past days, by my observation, I think he truly has feelings for Chu Chu.
And today's incident.
Today's incident?
What are your concerns?
You found a filing blade in the coffin workshop, right?
The guards also said that Chu He spent some time alone with Xu Rugui.
Maybe, Chu He found out that Xu Rugui is Miss Chu's uncle.
He's worried that Xu Rugui may take her away,
or get Miss Chu in trouble because of his crimes.
So, he let Xu Rugui escape.
He thought if Xu Rugui escaped or got killed, Miss Chu could stay.
So you suspect that Xu Rugui escaped to avoid punishment?
Chu He's tracks follow the same route as Xu Rugui's.
Don't tell anyone this, for now, especially Chu Chu.
But do you really think Miss Chu is completely
unaware of Chu He's feelings?
Miss Chu!
Jinyu!
Your Highness.
- General.
His Highness. Hurry. Where is His Highness?
I have something I want to give you.
With this Qiankun Mirror, if you're at a place without windows,
you don't have to go inside.
You can use this to see the views inside at the door.
Do you like it?
You're Handsome Judge?
You don't have to be so distant as well.
Don't call me Miss Chu. Just call me Chu Chu.
What's the embroidery on your handkerchief? It's a bone.
The fifth rib bone on the left chest.
When you put your hand on the bone's position,
you can feel your heart pounding.
Hurry. Come on.
Jinyu, wake up.
Jinyu, are you all right?
Jinyu, wake up. Jinyu.
- Chu Chu.
-  Wake up.
- Where's Chu Chu?
- Chu Chu.
- I...
- Hurry. Here's one more.
- I don't know.
Jinyu.
Chu Chu.
Are you crazy? Why did you dive in?
I... I saw my brother's clothes in the water.
I knew that he was trapped in the river.
He took off his clothes to ask for help.
Those who grow up next to rivers all know this.
But you shouldn't jump in!
But, I...
He woke up.
He's alive.
[Guanling Yamen]
Brother.
Miss Leng, how's my brother?
He's fine. He was just startled because he almost drowned.
I'll write him a prescription. Later, you can boil it and make him drink.
Chu Chu.
Deputy Magistrate Tan.
Vice Minister Jing.
- Why are you here?
- I heard that things went wrong at the County Office.
So I came here in a hurry to see if my service was needed.
Why are you in the wild in the middle of the night?
[Foot Length: 10 inches | Foot Width: 4 inches]
Foot length is 10 inches. Foot width is 4 inches
Stride is 1.9 inches. Slightly crooked.
He's the man from that night.
Please do us the favor, Deputy Magistrate Tan.
Go get some medicine.
No need.
I know where the pharmacy is. I can buy it myself.
Deputy Magistrate Tan, please bring some clean clothes for Chu Chu.
Yes.
I'll do it right now.
Jinyu, open the door.
I'm fine.
Open the door!
I'm changing my clothes.
Open it! Or I'll break in.
I'll break in!
Jinli, I'm fine.
How can you be fine?
You drowned once when you were a kid. You were so sick that you almost died.
I'm not a kid anymore.
That won't change anything. Let Leng Yue check on you later.
The water was freezing. How can you bear it?
If you're sick, what should I do in a desolate place like this?
Who taught you how to swim?
You're not a good swimmer. How dare you dive in the flooding water?
No one taught me. I learned it myself.
What?
You said Chu Chu was mad.
I think you are.
There were many people on the shore.
Who isn't healthier than you, or a better swimmer?
What were you thinking?
She dived in the water without any notice.
What could I think of?
She lives next to Yong'an River.
The kids in the town grow up playing in the river.
You don't know how to swim, and you're unfamiliar with the river.
She might be the one who saves you.
If I say I don't even know why I jumped,
that I was already in the river when I realized it,
Jinli, would you believe it?
You!
I think you're under a spell.
On the contrary, I was indeed under a spell before.
I thought I could see through everything.
But, in the end, I didn't even understand myself.
What?
Nothing.
Listen to me!  No matter what happens,
you must stay away from water. Do you hear me?
If you dare to jump into the water again, I'll immediately escort you back to Chang'an.
I got it.
Have the men you sent to search for Xu Rugui returned yet?
No.
I left a team there. They'll keep on searching.
They'll report to me once they find anything.
Xu Rugui betrayed his master to save his own life.
They now want him dead.
He dares not to go back to Chang'an.
If you're right, Guanling County is his hometown.
He knows every bit of this place.
It's possible that he's hiding in the nearby mountains.
The Southwest Mountain has a complex environment.
It might take a while to capture a person who's familiar with it.
How about I ask Magistrate Zheng to assemble the villagers and search the mountain together?
No.
If you startle Xu Rugui, innocent people might get hurt.
Let me think about it.
[Guanling Yamen]
Commandery Prince An.
This is the map of Guanling County.
Are you responsible for guarding this area?
Yes.
Guanling County has a complicated terrain.
The mountains and waters are perplexingly intertwined.
When I first came to the office,
[County Office Pingle Town Phoenix Mountain]
there wasn't any road connecting the county to the outside world.
Villagers can only use the strop.
[Rocky mountain River Strop]
Around five years ago,
[Villager]
Prefecture Yamen allocated special funds to build official roads.
Then, people were able to communicate more with the outside world.
[Allocated fund to build road]
[More communication with the world]
But since then, there have been more bandits.
Commandery Prince An, I have reported many times to the prefecture Yamen,
asking them to send us more men.
But there hasn't been any follow-up.
About this, I...
You're feeling wrong?
No, I dare not.
Since this case happened in your administration,
no matter what the reasons are, you're the one responsible for it.
If I hear another excuse from you,
I'll report you to the Imperial Court
to decide whether you're wronged or not.
Commandery Prince An, don't be mad.
I failed my obligations.
I must be punished.
Stand up.
Thank you, Your Highness.
Point out every possible way that leads in or out of Guanling County,
whether it's a road in the mountain or one on the water.
Yes.
Commandery Prince An, this is where the Country Office is at.
There are six rivers leading to the county.
Failed to catch him. Still pursing.
A bunch of fools.
I still need to do it myself.
[Jing Mansion]
Master.
Minister Xue has arrived?
No.
Someone from the Xue Mansion said that Minister Xue went to the palace
this morning and will return later to visit you, Master.
The palace?
[The Book of Xiangjing]
Your Majesty, one of the records made by Minister Feng
during his inspection of the Southwest was missing.
Missing?
Which scroll? Where?
It was lost before it was brought to the capital.
I've read the inspection records.
The time and routes recorded in the three scrolls are consistent.
There's nothing missing from them.
Your Majesty.
I only knew this when Minister Feng's accompanying officers
handed over the work to me.
Besides the three scrolls of records already submitted to Your Majesty,
Minister Feng compiled the information of other affairs separately in another scroll.
What affairs?
I asked his accompanying officers.
They said they don't know.
I did some investigation at the Feng Mansion.
No one at the Feng Mansion has ever seen it.
Minister Feng died the night before his return to the capital.
Did this scroll get lost on its trip back to the capital, or...?
Why didn't you tell me earlier?
Your Majesty, don't be mad.
This is a serious matter. I dare not make a big scene.
I'm afraid I might be mistaken. It might have been left somewhere I missed.
Over these days, because I searched everywhere and found nothing,
I dare to report to Your Majesty.
It would be fine if it was just lost,
but if someone deliberately prevented me from seeing the records,
it means that Feng Jie has really found something on his trip.
[Qianzhou]
Your Majesty, the ministers all know that I was an academician.
I'm not an expert in military and political affairs.
Your Majesty, please allow me to
investigate Qianzhou's prefecture-level military and political affairs.
I'll allow you to investigate Qianzhou's prefecture-level military and political affairs.
military and political affairs.
Li Zhang, the Prefect of Qianzhou, has been in office for years.
He's been good at managing military and political affairs.
You can take the opportunity to learn from him.
Thank you, Your Majesty.
Who else knows about Feng Jie's missing investigation record?
Only the few accompanying officers know this.
I didn't even tell the people at the Feng Mansion.
Don't tell anyone about this before you return to the capital.
Yes.
Eunuch Qin, you asked me to keep an eye on Shen Yu, the new Capital Liaison Representative of Qianzhou.
It's been a while.
Since Shen Yu came to the capital,
he's been giving gifts to every minister.
Even I have received from him the specialties of the Southwest.
It's normal to give presents and make friends for a new minister.
Is there anything odd with the gifts?
No. Nothing.
Just some snacks or daily necessities. Nothing valuable.
They're roughly the same things the other Qianzhou officers gave to capital ministers.
Roughly the same?
What's the difference then?
Are they entirely the same or a bit different?
This... I... I'm still looking into it.
Oh! In the past, the ministers were always talking about the previous officers of Duke Chang.
I did some digging to see if they have any connections with Shen Yu.
I think the story about Duke Chang is just a rumor.
It's not that simple.
Listen up!
Keep an eye on what's going on outside the palace.
Report to me immediately when you get any news.
Yes.
And there's more.
Not long ago, Wu Jiang went to the Jing Mansion and gave Senior Jing a copper coin. It's from Qian Printing.
A copper coin?
Yes. Nothing more.
I tried my best and found some information from the Ministry of Revenue,
but I just don't know the reason behind it.
A copper coin from Qian Printing.
Eunuch Qin.
Eunuch Qin, His Majesty just gave an order.
What is it?
Xue Rucheng will visit Qianzhou.
The Southwest will get chaotic.
Xiao Jinyu went to looking for Xiao Heng.
But all he found was a copper coin from Qian Printing.
Xue Rucheng is also on his way there.
His Majesty...
is contemplating ordering a marriage.
And there's Leng Peishan.
How interesting.
I'm free today.
So I want to play chess with you.
However, you went to the palace early in the morning.
I heard that you had a long conversation
with His Majesty at Jiangshan Hall?
Seems that nothing can escape Senior Jing's observation.
I have begged His Majesty
to allow me to visit the Southwest soon.
Commandery Prince An left the capital.
Her Grace is worried for him.
Her Grace came to visit me many times because of that.
Senior Jing, have you heard any news?
The situation in the Southwest is complicated.
I'm worried that His Highness might be in an adverse situation.
Yes.
Commandery Prince An is discreet.
But they had no experience working with local officers.
This indeed makes us worried.
Senior Jing, you're right.
Illegal copper coin case involves many parties.
Commandery Prince An hasn't reported to the imperial court yet.
I don't know if he's found out anything yet.
I'm worried that if the Leng family from the Southwest is involved in it...
Commandery Prince An has always been prudent.
He won't put himself in danger.
That's right.
Their trip to the Southwest is for Prince Consort.
If they can find Prince Consort, who has been missing for years,
then the thousand-mile trip wasn't made in vain.
I'm afraid it won't be that easy.
Senior Jing, what are you worried about?
Nothing.
I was just thinking if it's that easy,
we should have heard the news about Prince Consort sooner.
[Guanling Yamen]
Your Highness.
How's Chu He doing?
Leng Yue said he's fine. She went to buy medicine for him.
Chu Chu, go home first.
But my brother...
Chu Chu, don't worry. We're here.
He's said to be fine, right?
You should go home and tell your family that he's safe.
Miss Chu, let me take you home.
I'm not going.
I have to wait for my brother to wake up.
If I go home and tell them my brother is still in a coma, they will be worried.
You must go home when I ask you to.
If you really see yourself as the coroner of Three Judicial Offices,
you must follow my orders.
If you think of my words as unworthy of your attention,
you shouldn't keep working for me.
Three Judicial Offices will be fine with one less coroner.
Timing and subtitles brought to you by The Imperial Coroners @ Viki.com
♫  Nothing can stop me  ♫
♫  From missing you all the time  ♫
♫  The moonlight appears, cold in the late night,
as the world changes  ♫
♫  Only with you by my side can I embrace my yearning for you  ♫
♫  When I close my eyes I meet you once again  ♫
♫  I'll gently brush your hair by your ear  ♫
♫  Life is long, with love and regrets in this world  ♫
♫  With you by my side, no matter how far I go,
we'll never be apart  ♫
♫  With your smile, in this moment, let me
cherish this lifetime  ♫
♫  Only for you, I have to worry about the end of this life  ♫
♫  I’m still young, with my love not yet realized for you, but I'm
willing to be here for you till the end
♫  You can rely on me in this lifetime  ♫
♫  Hope to spend this beautiful lifetime together  ♫