Timing and subtitles brought to you by The Imperial Coroners @ Viki.com
His Highness said he likes beautiful girls.
So, I...
Forget it.
But he seems to like the mirror I made.
He said he could give me one more chance
and take me to Qianzhou with him.
This time, I must do my best.
Manager Xu from Rugui Tavern ambushed us on the only way to Qianzhou.
What on earth is his identity?
Jinyu.
Chu Chu.
Leng Yue.
- Jinyu, what is it? Are you all right?
- I'm fine.
- Are you hurt?
- No.
[Xiao Jinli, Marquis Duyu]
Chu Chu, help Leng Yue get in and rest.
Okay.
Why did you come to the southwest with so few men?
- This is very dangerous.
- Many thanks, Eldest Brother.
Upon getting the edict the other day,
I went to Chang'an to receive you.
- Right after leaving Guanling County, we found you here.
- Slowly
They are dressed like bandits, but they don't act like bandits.
Who on earth are they?
The fugitives of Rugui Tavern's case.
I saw you hurt him just now. He won't get far.
I'll have my men capture him. Don't worry.
- Thank you, Eldst Brother.
- Don't mention it.
We're brothers. Also, this is a mission from His Majesty.
Thank you anyway.
Eldest Brother, do you have any money?
That's all I have. Is it enough?
I can send men to get more.
It's enough. I just want to take a look.
[The Imperial Coroner]
[Episode 10]
Stop crying. I can't see girls crying.
I'm not crying. What are you crying for?
It's my fault.
It's all my fault.
I wasn't hurt by you.
Why should you be blamed?
But you got hurt protecting me.
Sorry.
What are you talking about?
Girls are supposed to protect girls.
Cheer up.
Unfortunately, my clothes were ruined.
How about this? If you feel sorry,
why don't you buy me a new dress?
Okay.
Luckily, the wound isn't very deep.
The bones and muscles are not hurt.
It has nothing to do with luck. It's my prowess.
For martial artists traveling around, injuries are inevitable.
But there's a rule for injures.
Those getting hit head-on won't stay standing to the end.
To be a true master,
you should learn how to fail.
Like with my injury...
I knew I couldn't dodge it.
But how serious the wound would be still depended on me.
Miss Leng Yue.
His Highness said your grandfather is the Military Commissioner of Qianzhongdao.
His ranking is way higher than prefect.
Why are you traveling around the world?
I like it.
Leng Yue! Leng Yue, how are you now?
Come. Slowly.
Be careful.
How are you? Is it serious?
It's fine. Just a scratch.
Is it a scratch? You bled a lot.
No, I'll write to my father
and ask for some physicians from Chang'an.
No! Are you ill?
You're the one who's not well right now.
Let's say you write a letter to your father, it has to go all the way to Chang'an.
Then physicians have to come from Chang'an.
By then, I'd have fully recovered.
What do you want the physician see?
To make fun of me?
All right. All right. All right.
Minister Jing, don't worry about it.
Given her hand strength, does she seem unwell?
If you feel uneasy, let her punch you.
Cut it out.
Be careful not to split the wound.
You may see a physician later in the city.
Don't bother. Chu Chu is highly skilled.
She'll change the dressing, and I'll recover soon.
What about you?
Thanks to Miss Leng, I'm fine.
Eldest Brother, is there a place to rest nearby?
Before entering the city, I have something to tell you.
Sure.
Take the carriage. Come on.
[Xue's Manor]
Miss Banxia, you personally came.
Is there an order for me from Princess?
Princess hasn't heard from His Highness, so she worries about him a lot.
Thinking that there could be information in the court,
she sent me here to ask you.
Her Highness doesn't have to be worried.
To tell you the truth,
people from the Ministry of Personnel met her lately.
They've been investigating you by the edict.
She's worried if something happened to him and got you implicated.
Are they investigating me?
I didn't hear anything about it.
However... Minister Feng has been conferred.
Nothing happened in the court either.
I suppose nothing big will happen.
Tell Princess not to worry too much about it.
If there's anything related to Commandery Prince An,
I'll tell her everything I know.
Sir, I may thank you in her stead.
[Jiangshan Hall]
Your Majesty, I'm just a scholar dealing with literature.
You want me to be the Minister of War.
I'm afraid to fail my duty and disappoint you.
Unlike a general, a Minister of War only
takes charge of the appointment of military officials,
military manuals, weapons, and the like.
Generally, a military official is assigned
just because they know more about the situation in the army.
Du Ruhui, the famous Prime Minister in the times of Taizong,
was a civilian court official acting as the Minister of War. Right?
I dare not to be compared with Prime Minister Du.
You are inexperienced in military affairs,
but don't belittle yourself.
You've been working in Hanlin Academy for years.
In the court, you've been working close to me.
I know how capable you are.
Taking charge of Ministry of War isn't too hard for you, is it?
Your Majesty, many talents in the court
are qualified for this position.
I know I am not the best choice.
Think twice, Your Majesty.
There are indeed many talents for it.
Since Feng Jie's death, they've been fighting for it openly or covertly,
trying every way to let me see them.
But you, you've been hiding from me
for fearing that I'd think of you.
Quite the opposite, I will have you to be the Minster of War against your will.
- Your Majesty.
- All right. It's settled then.
Just wait for the official document.
Jinbao.
Yes, Your Majesty.
Give my blade to Minister Xue.
Yes.
Congratulations, Minister Xue.
His Majesty, thanks for the blade.
Master. Prefect of Qianzhou brings gifts.
Master. These are gifts from Prefect of Qianzhou.
This is the list. Please check it.
[Prefect Qianzhou. Rosa roxburghii, 10kg.]
Master, these are gifts from Qianzhou.
[Rose sugar, 2.5kg. Yacca tea, 1.5kg]
That Li Zhang does know the rules.
Master. I don't quite understand it.
Why does Prefect of Qianzhou
give gift to those officials in Chang'an from time to time?
[List of Gifts]
He's never asked you for any favor.
What is he up to by giving gifts?
You don't know it.
He's an orphan from a humble family.
In childhood, he studied in a temple.
Perhaps he sees many things of hypocrisy in the world.
[List of Gifts]
After growing up, he knows well the ways of the world.
He's evasive and worldly-wise, but not greedy.
He became a prefect at a young age.
His future is promising.
All right. Accept all the gifts.
Yes, Master.
Go and ask around tomorrow if he gave gifts to any other manor.
As usual, buy some Chang'an specialties at the same price and give them in return.
Yes, Master.
Master.
General Wu from Three Chief Judicial Ministries is come by.
He asked me to give you this.
[Qian]
Just one copper coin?
What does he mean by this?
[Kaiyuan Coin]
- Where is he?
- He gave me this letter and left.
He only asked me to give you this.
[Qian]
Go get the carriage ready.
Yes, Master.
This is an open area. Let's rest here.
Sure.
Miss Leng, are you all right?
I... I'm fine.
Why don't you lie on my lap?
You can feel better.
Thanks. I'm fine.
Really?
You are nagging like Xiao Jinli.
General Xiao? He didn't say anything just now.
He won't nag me.
He only nags His Highness.
He will nag him half a day for some trivia.
You'll know it later.
What is that saying?
He's the apple of his eyes.
General Xiao and His Highness
are so intimate.
His Highness is kind to General, too.
These two brothers have been different since childhood.
When His Highness was a kid, he was weak and quiet.
But Xiao Jinli was like a monkey, climbing up and down every day.
They were once playing by the lotus pond in the manor.
Xiao Jinli climbed on a tree very quickly,
but he ended up falling into the pond.
His Highness couldn't swim, but he jumped in to save him instantly.
Luckily, Aunt Banxia heard the sound and got people there in time.
Otherwise, they could've been drowned.
Princess must've punished General Xiao, right?
Punishment was no big deal.
It was early spring back then.
The water was very cold.
His Highness caught a cold in water.
He didn't get better until the summer.
Princess beat Xiao Jinli and got the pond leveled.
Xiao Jinli has behaved better since then.
I wonder if he's terrified or he felt guilty.
Ever since then, Xiao Jinli has been closely watching over him.
So, do not mess with Xiao Jinli.
I'll keep it in mind.
Leng Yue. How are you?  How about I carry you?
I'm fine.
We've arrived. Can you move? Let me help you.
I can walk. Get off.
I'm fine. I can do it.
"Fail to repair the room, for no worker can be found."
[Marquis Zhang]
Bravo. Bravo.
Wang Xizhi's "Clearing After Snowfall".
The penmanship is stable and tidy, with round and sharp fonts.
It's easy to imitate the fonts, but not the conception.
It says, "Fail to repair the room".
It's upset to fail to do it.
But from the strokes, the writer is obviously in a peaceful state.
You imitated not only the form but also the conception.
You are really great.
These days, you must've put lots of efforts on it.
It didn't take much time.
But the paper and pen did take lots of money.
You're flattering me, Mentor.
I have a strange thing as well.
You may take a look at it.
I'm much flattered.
In terms of paintings and calligraphy, I know a thing or two.
But about antiques, I dare not show off in front of you.
[Kaiyuan Coin]
You are injured.
Why are you still here? Go back and sit.
Stop it. Go back and sit.
You're skilled.
"Carefully cut as thin as cicada's wings.
Pile up like yarn. Separate like snow.
Fly with the wind. The edge keeps moving".
What? What flying snow? It's not snowing.
It was a prince's comment on fillets 600 years ago.
It means, "very good".
Really?
Enjoy yourselves then.
Jinyu, what are you trying to say?
Of these 23 copper coins printed with "Qian",
18 coins are fake.
What?
Fake?
I can't tell.
How come it looks genuine?
Let me see.
Counterfeiting coins is a death penalty.
Who would do this business?
Counterfeiting coins is huge.
If they're not powerful enough, they can't afford to do this.
Qianzhou has been in peace these years.
I've never heard of anyone who could do this.
Nor have I during my travel.
Since Jinyu said it's in Qianzhou, it must be in Qianzhou.
Seriously?
Could it be Prefect of Qianzhou?
Chu Chu. You live in Qianzhou.
How is this prefect's reputation with the commoners?
Prefect Li is known as a good official.
Hadn't he allocated funds to Guanling County and built bridges and roads,
we'd still use slings now.
I contacted this prefect several times.
He's kind of cunning,
but there's nothing wrong with him.
Your coins must be your military pay.
Even in the military, there are so many counterfeit coins.
It must concern many things.
As Prefect of Qianzhou, Li Zhang must have something to do with it.
If I guess it right, this prefect
must be waiting for us in Guanling County.
Don't you believe it? A bet of five gold.
Bad habit.
Commandery Prince An sent it here but didn't say anything.
He wanted to see our reactions.
For Commandery Prince An, everyone is suspicious.
He even suspected you, his mentor.
In that case, you've also figured it out about the coin, right?
When I received his coin, I didn't get it either.
Then I got another ten coins printed with "Qian"
and made a comparison.
Turned out this coin was illegal.
He's your favorite student.
What do you think of this?
What will he do?
He sent the coin into the capital and gave us in this way.
I suppose he wanted to know our reactions.
This sounds like his style.
Illegal copper coins appeared in all dynasties.
The southwest area is remote, yet it's rich in minerals.
Illegal cooper cash casting continues despite repeated prohibitions.
I'm worried that he can't find where illegal coins are made.
It's just that this issue must concern the dignitaries in the court.
Given his righteousness, he could cause trouble unknowingly.
You worry too much.
He's also a dignity, isn't he?
If he's aware that he's one of the dignities,
why do I bother worrying about this?
I'm not worried about dignitaries.
I'm afraid it's related to eunuchs.
Qin Luan lives long in the palace.
Qianzhou is thousands of miles away.
He can barely manage this thing.
Mentor, in your opinion,
who do you think is casting coins illegally?
What? Don't you have any clue?
The other day,
you invited the newly appointed Capital Liaison Representative to your manor.
Wasn't it for the investigation of this case?
No, you misunderstood it.
I invited him to my place to learn about something
about the border military and political affairs in the prefectures.
It had nothing to do with this case.
Military and political affairs?
His Majesty ordered me to be the Minister of War.
Congratulations to you in advance, Minister Xue.
I'm Li Zhang, Prefect of Qianzhou. My respects, Commandery Prince An.
Commandery Prince An comes to Qianzhou. I'm here to visit you.
Please pardon me for any offense.
I lost to His Highness again. Li Zhang is really here.
My respects. I'm Zheng Youde.
[Zheng Youde, Magistrate of Guanling County]
[Li Zhang, Prefect of Qianzhou]
My respects. I'm Tan Gui.
[Tan Gui, Deputy Magistrate of Guanling County]
There are too many state affairs.
Even Prefect Li is disturbed to come.
Not at all.
I'm much flattered.
All right. I'll do it as His Highness said.
Who is this lady?
Military Commissioner of Qianzhongdao,
General Leng's granddaughter, Leng Yue.
So, you're Miss Leng.
My respects.
Qianzhou is remote and impoverished.
It's incomparable with Chang'an.
But you're guests from afar.
Now that you come here, we should show our hospitality.
Yes. Show our hospitality.
Well...
Rest assured, Commandery Prince An.
I've long heard of your integrity.
I dare not do anything out of line.
I just want to treat you to dinner at Zheng's place, to receive you.
Everything will be simplified so that we'll all be pleased.
Please give us the honor.
Give us the honor.
In this case...
Since you say so, I cannot refuse it.
And I have something to learn from Prefect Li and Magistrate Zheng.
My pleasure. My pleasure.
Deputy Magistrate Tan. Hurry and serve tea.
Commandery Prince An, Please. Miss Leng, please.
Please.
[Guanling County Government]
Here. Try this.
Right.
This is tasty.
Eat up.
Eat.
Isn't she the girl of the Chu's family?
That's right. Didn't she go to Chang'an?
These guys must be rich.
I agree.
How come these people come with Miss Chu?
I wonder what she did in Chang'an.
Women are not allowed in government.
Who knows?
Who do you mean by Miss Chu? Who are rich?
[Chu He, Chu Chu's brother]
Chu He, don't you know it?
Your sister is back with a bunch of men.
Come and look.
Dried goods. Herbs. Have a look.
My home is over there, not far from this fair.
Your home is quite remote.
Chu Chu. Chu Chu!
- Brother.
- Stop. Who are you?
This is my sister. I'm her brother.
Step back.
He... He's my brother.
You've been out for so long, and didn't write a letter to us.
Who are these guys with you?
Come here.
Brother, they're not bad guys.
I'll take the coroner's exam with them.
The coroner's exam? Who are these guys?
How come you take the exam in this way?
I... It's true I'm taking coroner's exam.
Let's go home.
Are you Chu He?
How come he knows my brother's name?
How did you know it?
Who on earth are you?
We're from Chang'an.
You can take her home, but we'll go along with you.
When we see your elders at home, I'll tell you who we are.
I don't even know you people. Why should I take you to my house?
Because we came here with her all the way from Chang'an.
We are strangers to you.
I understand you're vigilant.
But we can't trust you, either.
She's my sister. I'm her brother.
Why would I harm her?
Brother, they're helping me.
Since you mean no harm to her, why can't we send her home?
Fine, all right then. Listen up.
My family works for the county government.
If you have any evil intentions,
Magistrate Zheng won't spare you.
- Brother.
- Shut it.
Stop speaking.
Please lead the way.
Brother.
Chu He, Miss Chu said your family have been coroners for generations.
My family is one and only coroner here.
You can ask around here.
Chu is a household name.
In this case, Zheng Youde, the Magistrate,
contacts with your family a lot, right?
Of course.
How is he as an official?
He's a good official, never bullying people, also a good judge.
Why do you ask about this?
I'm new here. I'm just asking.
Ermao. Ermao. Ermao. Come here.
Ermao.
Grandfather. Grandfather.
[Chu Ping Chu's father; Chu's grandfather]
- Chu Chu.
- I'm back.
Chu Chu is back.
Grandfather. Father!
- Chu Chu is back.
Father.
Are you back now?
You're good, huh?
You left for so long, yet you didn't send a message to home.
Come here. I'll break your legs...
Sorry, Grandpa. I'm wrong.
Father. She's back safe and sound. Don't be angry.
- Don't defend her.
- Sorry.
If she doesn't learn a lesson, she'll do it again.
I meant to write to you.
But I wanted to pass the exam and then wrote the good news to you.
Are you arguing with me? You lass!
What if you were cheated?
What if you got harmed?
No one harmed me.
People in Chang'an are very nice. No one bullied me.
I've served as a coroner and filled out autopsy forms.
It's just that...
I haven't passed the exam yet.
Are you lying now?
Who asked you to be a coroner?
Who asked you to fill out autopsy forms?
I am not lying.
Calm down, Elder. She isn't lying.
I asked her to be the coroner and filled out autopsy forms.
Did you ask her to be a coroner?
Then... Who are you?
I'm an official from Chang'an in charge of prison affairs.
This is my elder brother,
a general under Military Commissioner of Qianzhongdao.
Chu Chu worked for me while she was in Chang'an.
She's meticulous and highly skilled, one of a kind.
She told me your family has been coroners for generations, with a long origin.
I went to the southwest for work,
passing by your place and paying a visit.
Look. Now do you believe it?
I've worked as a coroner.
Father. An official in charge of prison in the court?
I don't buy it. There's no big criminal case here.
What does an official from the court come for?
Moreover, officials from the court must come for big issues.
There should be a convoy at least for a prefect.
We're men of the world.
Don't try to fool us like this.
Lass. Be honest.
Did you ask them to make up a lie for you?
Watch your tongue.
Brother, I told you the truth.
So did he.
By the way, he has the official credential.
Since you don't believe my words,
even though I show you the credential,
you'll still doubt if it's true.
To prove my identity to a coroner, these things are not necessary.
You said your family is the only coroner in this county.
That means,
all the murder cases handled by the county government
are examined by your family. Is it right?
Yes. Then what?
On October 19th, last year, a debtor in this county
had Gelsemium elegans and killed himself to frame the creditor.
Zheng Youde originally thought the creditor was the murderer.
But the report was rejected by the court for an investigation soon after it's submitted.
In the report, it's marked that
the testimonies of the debtor's wife were contradictory.
Zheng Youde retried the debtor's wife and the truth was revealed.
How did you know it?
I also know another vendetta case on the 5th day of the 7th lunar month, the year before last.
The murderer robbed and killed, disguised as a bandit.
Zheng Youde reported it to the court as a bandit crime.
It's rejected as well.
The report was replied that the murderer was a local woman in her twenties.
Zheng Youde re-investigated several young women in their twenties.
The culprit was finally arrested.
I examined this case. I know it.
That's true.
How did you know the reply from the court
that Magistrate Zheng received?
Because I wrote these replies.
We come here for work.
To make it convenient, we're dressed as businessmen.
It's crowded in the street.
I couldn't tell you the truth. Please pardon me.
Do you believe it now?
I'm too ignorant.
Sorry for my discourtesy. Please forgive me.
I came uninvited. Skip the formalities.
Sirs, please go upstairs.
Girl, come with me.
But...
Come in, please.
Please.
We're a humble family. It's incomparable to Chang'an.
Please make do for a rest.
Please have a seat.
Please.
Thanks.
- After you, sir.
- Sit, please.
Sir. Chu Chu is a girl.
- Did she really work as a coroner in Chang'an?
- Yes.
She'd never been to the government before
and knows little about the rules.
Did she make any mistakes?
No.
Lass. Listen to me.
Why do these high-ranking officials come to our family?
Did you make any mistakes?
Listen. I won't allow anyone to bully you.
No.
I don't know either.
I want to work for him. He's still testing me.
He said if he would hire me, he'd verify my identity of the test.
They want to know Chu Chu's background.
He's already sent me home.
I guess he won't hire me.
What are you talking about? I don't understand.
Nothing.
Brother, I missed you so much when I was outside.
Silly girl.
Don't do this again. Understand?
Since she didn't make any mistakes, why do you send her home?
To be honest, I didn't mean to send her back.
I just passed by and encountered Chu He.
I was afraid she couldn't explain it and get punished
if she came back alone.
On the other hand, I'd like to come and learn about something.
Is it about Chu Chu?
I heard that a witch doctor lived in Pingle Town.
Does he still live here now?
You... Were you talking about a witch doctor?
The man who used to tell you stories, living behind our house.
What... What happened to him?
He moved away long ago, about four or five years.
Yes.
Back then, his legs were hurt. He couldn't walk.
The villagers around here thought he couldn't even cure his own legs.
They didn't trust him.
Besides, he's reluctant to do superstitious things.
He led a hard life like a beggar.
It's good that he didn't loathe our family.
I used to ask Chu Chu to give him some food and necessaries.
Her father often helped him with some work, like picking herbs.
Chu Chu was very close to him.
She's very sad when he just left.
No one has ever seen him again?
No.
Military Commissioner sent troops to suppress bandits here before.
Was he living here at that time?
Yes. Yes.
I remember I went to tell him that
the troops were suppressing bandits,
and told him to lock the door and stay at home lest he got hurt.
Didn't he say anything about the troops?
No.
Oh, right. When I left, he asked me to lock the door.
Sir, I have a favor to ask.
You're our honored guests.
Just be frank. It's my pleasure.
It's getting late now.
Would you please allow us to stay the night at your place?
Will he be staying with my family?
Timing and subtitles brought to you by The Imperial Coroners @ Viki.com
♫  Nothing can stop me  ♫
♫  From missing you all the time  ♫
♫  The moonlight appears, cold in the late night,
as the world changes  ♫
♫  Only with you by my side can I embrace my yearning for you  ♫
♫  When I close my eyes I meet you once again  ♫
♫  I'll gently brush your hair by your ear  ♫
♫  Life is long, with love and regrets in this world  ♫
♫  With you by my side, no matter how far I go,
we'll never be apart  ♫
♫  With your smile, in this moment, let me
cherish this lifetime  ♫
♫  Only for you, I have to worry about the end of this life  ♫
♫  I’m still young, with my love not yet realized for you, but I'm
willing to be here for you till the end  ♫
♫  You can rely on me in this lifetime  ♫
♫  Hope to spend this beautiful lifetime together  ♫