Timing and subtitles brought to you by The Imperial Coroners @ Viki.com
Things are odd with Minister Feng's death.
[Two Merits Hall]
The two corpses His Highness dug up from the graves
are also related to Minister Feng's death.
He somehow found the connections between the three cases,
which seemed irrelevant at first sight.
[The Imperial Family]
His Highness is the best judge I've ever seen.
I'll definitely help him find out Minister Feng's real cause of death.
Burn Feng Jie and this coroner.
Open the door.
Fire! Anyone?
The mourning hall is on fire.
She can't escape this time. Fall back.
Who?
Minister Feng.
Hurry! Go!
Go! Here's water!
- Where's Chu Chu?
- Chu Chu is inside.
Master.
Water. Hurry.
Here's water.
Put out the fire.
Hurry! We need more people!
Your Highness.
- Here's water.
- Your Highness, just let me go.
Your Highness.
More water.
- Hurry up!
- Here's water.
Chu Chu.
Your Highness.
I'm here.
- Do we have more water?
- Here.
Your Highness, Minister Feng's body is still here.
Are you out of your mind?
Let me take care of it. Your Highness, go!
There's more here.
- Hurry!
- Go!
- Let's go!
- Hurry up!
This way.
- More water?
- It's coming!
[The Imperial Coroner]
[Episode 5]
What is it? What's going on in the front yard?
Second Madam, don't be scared. The mourning hall is on fire.
The mourning hall is on fire.
How about Master?
Second Madam, don't worry.
Master was carried out of the fire in time and was unharmed.
Master's body was saved from the fire?
It must be him.
Master has come.
He's coming for me.
- Second Madam.
- Master is coming for me.
- Master is coming for me!
- It's all right, Second Madam.
Second Madam, it's all right.
Master.
Minister of War, Minister Feng's manor caught fire.
What?
Minister Feng's manor was on fire?
Yes.
I heard that Commandery Prince An was also at Feng's manor.
What will he do this time?
Someone's here. Hurry! Hide.
Shen Army's battalion.
[Feng Manor]
Hurry.
Lower the poles. Hurry.
Careful. It bumped my head.
Hurry and take a look inside.
[Feng Manor]
Hurry.
Ask them all to leave.
Yes.
Let's leave for now.
Are you hurt?
No. You just...
Where is Master?
Madam.
Master.
Commandery Prince An, have our Feng Family ever wronged you?
My Master has just deceased.
You already brought a coroner with you.
Madam. Madam. Madam.
I've decided to put what happened during the day behind us.
I didn't expect you to be so vile.
You ordered others to set fire in my husband's mourning hall.
Xiao Jinyu, I'm the one who told on you.
If you want revenge, just kill me.
Madam. Madam.
Xiao Jinyu, if you don't, I'll kill this despicable girl
who disrespected my husband.
- Madam.
What happened?
Commandery Prince An, why are you here?
Lord Han. Academician Xue.
I'm sorry to disturb you because of our fire accident.
- Lord Han.
- Madam.
Madam Feng.
You and our Master are close friends.
You must uphold justice for him.
Madam Feng, please stand up first.
What's going on?
Commandery Prince An,
I heard that His Majesty has given you a verbal order,
forbidding you from disturbing Feng Manor.
You even disobey His Majesty now?
Madam Feng, I happened to hear your conversation.
There might be a misunderstanding.
Misunderstanding?
That's a coroner.
Commandery Prince An came here in the middle of the night with a coroner.
And he set the mourning hall on fire.
That's a misunderstanding?
I think he's disregarding the emperor's order and revenging his personal grudges.
He's such a disloyal and heartless person.
How can he properly manage Three Judicial Chief Ministries?
Commandery Prince An, I'll definitely unite ministers of Three Judicial Chief Ministries
and report what happened today to His Majesty for his judgment.
Lord Han. Madam Feng.
Commandery Prince An is a student of mine.
I know his characters.
He's definitely not a vile person.
Please give him a chance to explain today's incident.
If he can't convince you,
Lord Han and I can bring him to see His Majesty in person.
Madam, how do you think of that?
What does he have to say?
Nothing.
I didn't do this.
However, I don't have evidence to prove my innocence right now.
I can only provide it when I catch the real culprit.
By then, if Madam Feng wants to take me to His Majesty,
I'll cooperate.
Madam Feng, I have a thing to show you now.
Give me your hands.
Show your hands.
She was trapped in flames.
To save Minister Feng's remains from the fire, she was willing to sacrifice her life.
These are the bruises left by dragging.
If she hadn't guarded the remains with her life,
they would've become ashes in the flames.
Whoever the arsonist is, this incident has nothing to do with her.
You mustn't humiliate her like this.
- Your Highness.
- Shut up.
Madam. Forget it.
It's late into the night.
If we disturb the neighbors and allow them to know the incident,
Master's reputation will be stained.
It's better that we let Master rest in peace sooner.
Madam. I found this in the mourning hall.
I don't know what it is.
It was found next to Master's coffin.
It must have fallen from the top of the house because of the fire.
Don't make a fuss before the lords.
Madam Feng, are there any other matters you wish me to elaborate on?
Lord Han, Madam Feng is a housewife.
It's natural that she panics and jumps to conclusions based on preliminary pieces of evidence before incidents.
But you're the Minister of Justice.
You're an expert of observing and judging cases.
You speak recklessly without research and interrogation.
Even if you don't criticize me before His Majesty, I'll criticize you.
Okay. Go ahead.
What?
It's tilted.
What's tilted?
Your bun is tilted.
It was struck by the sedan.
It's still tilted.
Move away. Where are they?
This...
Commandery Prince An!
Zhou Han, you are such a fool!
What are you capable of?
You'll get me killed one day.
- Eunuch Sun.
Master! Bad news.
Zhou Han failed again.
Failed again?
He almost succeeded.
That female coroner was almost burned to death in the mourning hall.
What?
Zhou Han! That good-for-nothing!
Who asked him to kill the female coroner?
He can't get things done but can make things worse.
Wait.
You just said that
Xiao Jinyu brought that female coroner to Feng Manor again?
He insisted on apologizing to Madam Feng.
Who will apologize to a widow in the middle of a night?
He was not there to apologize.
He was there to inspect the corpse.
We're in trouble this time.
Come closer.
Well. What can he find?
- Hurry! Go!
- Yes. Yes. Yes.
Master, don't be mad. Ease your angry.
Miss Chu. Miss Chu.
Your Higness, it's Miss Lian Qiao.
Lian Qiao.
See if the kitchen has prepared spirit-calming decoction.
Yes.
You must be frightened.
I'm not scared.
I just...
I lost all my tools.
I'm sorry. I was late.
No. No. It's not your fault.
I was so careless that I didn't notice my tools were missing.
Thankfully, those tools were destroyed by the fire.
They can't tell what they are.
Otherwise, I would have got you in big trouble again.
It's fine.
I made those tools myself.
I can make another set.
It's just that
I'm feeling a bit sad
because those tools are like old friends to me
since they've been with me for a long time.
I'll be fine soon.
In the previous situation,
it's awkward for you to ask for the return of the tools.
If you really want them, I can order someone to retrieve them later.
Thank you, Your Highness.
You were the closest to the mourning hall when it caught fire.
Do you know how the fire was started?
I don't know.
I was too busy with the autopsy.
I only found the house on fire when I finished the autopsy.
You locked the doors and windows of the mourning hall?
No, I only shut the door.
But I don't know why I couldn't open it.
Your Highness, the fire was so fierce.
Why did you run into it?
Aren't you afraid of death?
I am.
Then, why did you do that?
I was afraid that you might die.
You were afraid that I might die?
I...
I'm afraid, because if you die,
I'll stay up all night to write reports and archive the cases.
Remember, whenever and wherever
if you're in a situation like this again,
you must do everything to keep yourself alive first.
The consequences of having a corpse destroyed by fire
and having a living person killed by fire
are totally different for the ministries and for me.
But there were guards.
If you were worried about me, you didn't have to rush in yourself.
If only Wu Jiang and the other guards went in,
would you flee or would you guard the corpse with them?
Of course, I'd protect the corpse.
So that's the reason
I had to rush in and bring you out.
I know the deceased is as important as the living ones to you.
You're willing to sacrifice your life to make sure their remains are intact.
But, to me, I was the one who sent you to inspect the corpse.
I must ensure your safety.
Your Highness, you're such a nice person.
Try these grapes.
They're from the Western Regions.
Grape skin is bitter.
This is how you eat it.
[Three Judicial Chief Ministries]
You've inspected Feng Jie's remains.
What did you find?
I knew their cause of death.
I carefully inspected the wounds on Minister Feng's head.
The wound on his left brow bone was caused by a punch of the fist.
That punch caused the right side of the back of his head to crash into a smooth but hard object,
resulting in small fractures on his skull.
This is the same with the other two victims.
I'm now certain that they were all killed by a similar punch.
But according to people from Feng Manor,
Feng Jie was hurt in the tavern.
If this punch was lethal,
he wouldn't be able to walk back to the manor.
Besides, you've said that these little fractures are not fatal.
Let me put it this way.
There was a staircase where he was wounded.
You're right.
The killer chose to carry out the murder on a staircase
because it's convenient to adjust their height difference
so as to make sure the punch
land on Minister Feng's eye socket and below his bow bone.
[On the eye socket Below the bow bone]
[The punched position]
The back of Minister Feng's head hit a hard object that was protruded,
thus causing a small fracture.
[A blow on the back of his head]
[A small fracture]
This wound wasn't instantly fatal.
It didn't even inflict much pain.
So Minister Feng thought it wasn't a big deal.
He didn't take it seriously.
What's his problem?
But this small fracture
would gradually cause blood clots in his brain.
Within less than an hour, the clotted blood would make him dizzy.
He couldn't talk clearly or walk straight.
That's the thing you said that was in the brains?
Yes. I've inspected.
The wounds on the other two victims were the same.
But they've died for quite a while ago.
I won't have an accurate inspection
even if I cut open their skulls now.
Cut open their skulls?
You cut Feng Jie's skull open?
Yes.
How could I know whether he has blood clots in his brains or not if I hadn't cut open his skulls?
I've inspected carefully.
There were indeed blood clots in his brain.
Moreover, he took strong erectile medications
which caused his blood to flood his brain, worsening his wounds.
Then he died instantly.
But I just saw that Feng Jie's corpse is intact.
Of course, it is.
I stitched it back after the autopsy.
You stitched it back up after opening it?
Yes.
It's the same with the way the officers search the crime scenes.
They open doors when they go in.
But they have to close the doors when they leave.
That's why you asked for a wig before you left.
You made it into the shape of Feng Jie's bun because you wanted to
restore it to its original shape after your autopsy?
Our skin, hair, and body are given to us by our parents.
It's disrespectful to harm them.
So, you're not ignorant of that.
Do you know that coroners from capital's offices
need permits mandated by the cases' chief officers in order to perform an autopsy.
Those who perform autopsies without permits will be charged.
There's such a rule?
But I've already mended the corpse.
I put clothes back on. It's like I've never performed the autopsy.
In that case, will I still be charged?
I've never met such a lawbreaking coroner like you.
How to punish you? I have to think carefully.
I didn't break the rules.
I complied with the rules of the Judicial Service.
The rules of the Judicial Service?
Handsome Judge once said that the Judicial Service
shouldn't be restricted by doctrines when handling cases.
Any method is acceptable as long as it leads to the truth.
But we mustn't commit crimes in order to solve cases.
We mustn't ruin the remains in order to inspect them.
So, the Judicial Service's coroners
are allowed to conduct autopsy so long as they can restore the corpses to their initial shapes.
You don't know this?
I know.
Really? You really do?
- Then, are you...?
- Am I Handsome Judge?
Are you?
Why are you looking for Handsome Judge?
Is it because of your pendant?
Why does he care about the pendant so much?
So, has the person who gave you the pendant told you that
the pendant might belong to Handsome Judge?
Lord Jing, why are you here?
I've been busy all night.
Have you found the arsonist?
Your Highness,
can't you just pretend you don't know and praise me a little bit?
Stop beating around the bushes.
There were five of them.
They all wore masks and black clothes. They're all skilled fighters.
I followed them and saw them disappear into the battalion of Shen Army.
It's Qin Luan again.
Go to meet Han Ji when you're done eating.
Han Ji?
Your Highness, it's so late that even cats are sleeping.
What do I visit that old crow for?
According to people from Feng Manor,
it was Han Ji who sent Feng Jie home last night.
So, Han Ji was one of the people who threw the reception banquet for Feng Jie.
If we can find out which tavern Feng Jie was at on that night,
it won't be hard to find the real murderer.
Wait. What does it have to do with the tavern?
Chu Chu just found out the cause of death of the three victims, including Feng Jie.
They were hit at the bow bones and the eye sockets,
causing back skull fractures.
The wounds of the three victims are in the exactly same positions.
It means that the murderer is a trained killer.
So he can kill with just one strike.
As for drinking, it's the key element to conceal his killing method.
Drinking?
Chu Chu, you just said that the victims would gradually become dizzy
after they were hit in the face
and the skulls were rammed into the wall.
They couldn't speak clearly or walk steadily as if they were drunk.
Yes, that's it.
It was just like they were drunk.
Drunk?
You mean the murderer used this method
so the victims could walk out of the tavern alive
in front of the crowd.
That means someone murdered Minister of War
in front of Minister of Justice without him knowing it.
That's right.
To accomplish this crime,
the killer has to make sure that the victim was drinking when he was injured.
It's even better if the victim kept on drinking after the injury.
So, there must be someone facilitating the killer from within the tavern.
Karma is real.
Han Ji's got his turn now.
This old crow. He told on me many times before my dad.
He also criticized you many times before His Majesty.
When I see him this time,
- I'll definitely—
- You must keep your mouth shut!
When you see Han Ji tonight,
you should only find out the whereabouts of the tavern.
Once you find that out, pretend you're pursuing a wanted suspect and search the tavern.
Don't tell Han Ji anything more than that.
Don't leak any information
before all the facts of this case come to light.
Tavern?
Your Highness, if you're right,
the last meal Minister Feng had before his death
might be at that tavern.
What?
When I was performing the autopsy on Minister Feng's remains,
I found in his teeth gaps the roots of fish mints.
Judging from the degree of decay,
they might be left from the last meal he had.
Rugui Tavern.
The weather is dry. Things are flammable.
Beware of the flames.
The killer dared to commit the murder in plain sight.
Rugui Tavern must have something to do with it.
Go!
[Rugui Tavern]
Commandery Prince An. Vice Minister Jing.
Such rare guests.
How come? We just came here this morning.
By the order of Commandery Prince An, from Three Judicial Chief Ministries,
we're here to search for the wanted criminals.
Where is your Manager Xu? We have some words for him.
I'll find him for you.
This is indeed where the killer committed the crime.
Wait.
What's that place?
That's the kitchen.
It's so late.
Who are you cooking for?
We're not cooking.
Our manager wants to take a bath after auditing the accounts.
I'm heating up water for his bath.
Look. Manger's lights are still on.
He must be still awake.
Wu Jiang.
You two. Follow me.
Yes.
Manager, Commandery Prince An is here.
- Chen Feng.
- They say...
Your Highness, we found nothing suspicious.
Your Highness, we neither.
It's so weird. Where is Manager Xu?
Who are you asking? We haven't asked you yet?
Where is your manager?
He was in the room previously.
It's the middle of the night.
And the doors are locked from the inside.
I didn't hear him go outside.
Xu Rugui might have jumped out of the window and fled
when he heard our movements.
Where is his family?
Our manager doesn't have family members.
He lives here on his own.
I also heard that Xu Rugui has no family.
Although Rugui Tavern is packed with beauties,
he has no romance with any of them.
Is that true?
Vice Minister Jing, you're being too hard on me.
I'm just a small manager who's in charge of a few waitresses.
I know nothing about the manager's personal life.
Rugui Tavern is surrounded by water and is connected to various paths.
It's easy for Xu Rugui to flee when he's startled.
But he can't be perfect when he panics.
[The Map Chonghua Rugui Tavern Huaiyuan]
There must be shreds of evidence in Rugui Tavern.
- Any findings?
- Your Highness, we found nothing suspicious inside.
Pass on my words. Seal Rugui Tavern immediately.
We must find Xu Rugui, no matter he's dead or alive.
Yes.
It's so late now.
Why hasn't our son come back?
Why don't you send someone to look for him?
Madam, don't worry. How can I not?
We have so many men.
How can we possibly lose his sight in Chang'an?
Okay, my wife.
Don't think too much nonsense.
We'll know everything when we wake up tomorrow.
Your Highness, you woke me up because you told me there might be a corpse.
Are you referring to Manager Xu?
When did your manager ask you to boil water?
About an hour ago.
It took you an hour and the water was still not boiled?
Your Highness, I'm the only one on duty tonight.
I fetched and boiled water all on my own.
It's so tiring.
To do it faster, I started the fire first before
I began to fetch water one bucket at a time.
Maybe it was because the firewood was dampened.
It was so hard to start the fire.
Xu Rugui must have something to do with the series of homicides that happened here.
The fire at Feng Manor didn't destroy the corpse along with evidence.
Maybe, that's the reason he fled in a hurry.
Answer me.
Did Feng Jie, the Minister of War, drink at this place last night?
Yes.
Along with Minister Han, the Minister of Justice,
and a few other ministers.
Did Minister Feng had an argument with someone?
And he was injured.
That's true.
Then, last month, did Liu Yue, Director of the Ministry of Revenue,
and Lu Chuansheng, Capital Liaison Representative of Qianzhou,
also drink at your place?
He also got in a fight and was injured?
It seems to be true.
But having drunk guests causing trouble is inevitable for a tavern.
Why is the kitchen so hot?
It's hotter than the burning house.
What? It's not supposed to be so hot when boiling water?
No.
My kitchen is smaller than this.
But boiling water doesn't make it heat up so badly.
Careful.
Your hands were just injured. This wall is burning.
Burning?
This wall is just like that.
Maybe it's because the wall was made out of bad materials.
When the other side was boiling water, this side will get hot easily.
Commandery Prince An, how is it now?
Yes, it's fine now.
- Wu Jiang.
- Yes.
Check it from the outside.
See if the chimney is still venting smoke.
Yes.
Your Highness, you sent Wu Jiang on a worthless mission.
The stove is empty.
How can there be any smoke?
Your Highness, it's still venting smoke.
Still?
Hasn't the fire been extinguished? Where does the smoke come from?
Go fetch a bucket of water.
Pour it into the chimney vent.
Remember. Pour the whole bucket inside.
Yes.
Your Highness, I'm pouring now.
Okay.
Why's the sound so big while the stream is so little?
Your Highness, I've poured in the whole bucket.
It's all done. Not a drop is left?
Every drop is poured. Not a drop is left.
How's that possible?
The whole bucket has been emptied.
Why is there only a little bit of water on the stove?
What?
The water didn't run into the stove?
Set the fire on again.
Wu Jiang, cover the chimney vent.
Yes.
Cover the chimney vent?
Your Highness, you're trying to...
The wall behind the funnel is hollow.
There might be a dark chamber underground where fire can be lit.
The funnel of the dark chamber's stove might be hidden inside this wall.
Two tunnels converge in one at the smoke vent of the kitchen's stove.
[The dark chamber]
When it's not used,
[Kitchen The hollow wall]
it's separated by the partition.
[Partition]
When it's used, the partition is removed.
So the smoke can be disguised as the smoke vented by the kitchen's stove.
That's why this wall gets heated up easily.
I see.
It's like catching a rabbit in the mountain.
You set fire on one cave entrance,
then the rabbit comes out from the other entrance.
Your Highness, is that correct?
Sort of.
So it means that  Xu Rugui is indeed hidden inside the underground chamber.
So, we can just wait for
him to come out?
Your Highness. There're movements in Xu Rugui's bedroom.
Your Highness.
There's indeed smoke from the rabbit hole.
It seems that here's the dark chamber's entrance.
- Wu Jiang.
- Yes.
Go tell those in the kitchen.
Order them to distinguish the stove.
Yes.
Master, are you asleep?
What is it?
Everything's taken care of at Rugui Tavern.
I see.
Chu Chu, stay here. Don't wander around.
I want to go with you, Your Highness.
We need you to guard the entrance in case someone blocks it.
Then we'll be in great danger.
I'll do as you say, Your Highness.
- Stay here too.
- Yes.
[Hanbi Hall]
Master.
Master, Vice Minister went to search Rugui Tavern with Commandery Prince An.
What? Search Rugui Tavern?
Yes.
- Go and investigate the details.
- Yes, Master.
This is indeed a rabbit hole.
Your Highness, watch out.
Your Highness, what happened?  Your Highness.
Your Highness, what's going on?
You must be too tired.
You worked nonstop without any sleep.
Go back and get some rest.
Wu Jiang, investigate it with Jing Yi.
Yes.
Escort His Highness back.
Your Highness, be careful.
Be careful.
Your Highness.
Watch out.
Careful now, Your Highness.
Your Highness,
what's going on?
It's fine. I'm just a bit tired.
- Zhang Yun.
- Yes.
Where's that woman of Rugui Tavern?
She's waiting outside.
You two, go and guard her.
Don't let her talk to any people. In case they falsify their testimonies.
Yes.
Thanks.
Your Highness, are you afraid of places without windows?
Why did you say so?
My brother and I once saved an officer in a mountain cave.
He had the same reactions you have right now.
I heard people say that this is an illness.
Once the patient is in a windowless room, the symptoms attack.
But no one knows how to cure it yet.
It's said that there are better and worse episodes too.
Don't worry. I won't tell anyone.
The officer we saved told us that if we let anyone know this,
he'd lose his job.
You're so good at solving cases.
I don't want to get you fired.
This is the handkerchief I gave you yesterday.
I've washed it many times. It's clean.
You embroidered this?
If you don't like it...
Your Highness.
Jing Manor has sent someone here.
They say Senior Jing and his madam are worried
because Vice Minister Jing hasn't returned home.
So they sent people to look for him.
They saw that the officers from the Court of Judicial Review are all heading this way.
So they came to inquire about it.
Tell them. Jing Yi is handling cases with me tonight. He won't go home.
Ask Senior Jing and his madam to rest assured.
Ask them to rest please.
Yes.
Shelves filled with files
[Xiao Jinli]
that are categorized by names.
[Princess Xiping]
[Yan Ming]
[Xiao Heng]
These are monitoring records.
How daring!
This is...
Look.
This should be the partition His Highness talked about.
[25th, Princess Xiping Manor Banquet]
Timing and subtitles brought to you by The Imperial Coroners @ Viki.com
♫  Nothing can stop me  ♫
♫  From missing you all the time  ♫
♫  The moonlight appears cold in the late
night as the world changes  ♫
♫  Only with you by my side can I embrace my yearning for you  ♫
♫  When I close my eyes I meet you once again  ♫
♫  I'll gently brush your hair by your ear  ♫
♫  Life is long with love and regrets in this world  ♫
♫  With you by my side, no matter how far I go we'll never be apart  ♫
♫  With your smile in this moment, let me cherish in this lifetime  ♫
♫  Only for you do I have worry about the end of this life  ♫
♫  I’m still young with my love not yet realized for you but
I'm willing to be here for you till the end  ♫
♫  You can rely on me in this lifetime  ♫
♫  Hope to spend this beautiful lifetime together  ♫