Timing and subtitles brought to you by The Imperial Coroners @ Viki.com
Wu Chen poisoned soldiers and fabricated strange things.
He also poisoned General Leng with cinnabar.
You traitor!
Hou Bin was murdered.
Wu Chen was killed and silenced.
Duke Chang is ending his plot.
He poisoned Leng Peishan with a noxious mugwort stick,
murdered Feng Jie and kept Leng Peishan's condition from His Majesty to stall for time.
I'm sure he uses such a plan
because he wants big trouble in Leng Peishan's army.
General Leng, you think Wu Chen was the only murderer?
What do you mean? I'm all my ears.
Wu Chen is a civil official who isn't your enemy at all.
Why did he take so much trouble to poison you?
And why did he poison soldiers at this moment
to make such big trouble?
Even if he finished his plan, you died and your soldiers fell into chaos.
What benefits could he get for himself?
You think someone wants to take over my troops?
Behind Wu Chen, there must be a long and thorough plan.
I'm afraid the plan is coming to an end.
So, he doesn't need to poison you anymore.
Coming to an end?
You mean they'll take over my troops soon?
General Leng, have you heard of a case
about illegal copper coins in Qianzhou?
Illegal copper coins?
We seldom need copper coins in the army
and there's been much trouble lately.
I haven't heard about what happened in Qianzhou.
Before coming here, we crashed a hideout for illegal copper coins
and arrested Prefect Li Zhang.
Hardly had we arrested him when some of your soldiers
set fire to his mansion?
What?
I didn't send any soldiers.
Oh, Hou Bin sent some soldiers to Qianzhou for material purchases.
But Hou Bin died.
What exactly happened?
General Leng, do you recognize them?
I do.
Hou Bin recruited them from bandits six months ago.
The other day, they escaped during the training outside the camp
because they couldn't bear the hardship.
Did you meet them?
Prefect Li's neighbors identified them
as the soldiers who set fire to Prefect Li's mansion.
They're two of the soldiers.
I guess they escaped because they didn't want me to recognize them
after I came here.
If I guess correctly, someone must have coordinated with them.
General Leng, there's another man hiding in your army
who's about to make trouble at any time.
Are you interested in catching him with me?
[The Imperial Coroner]
[Episode 30]
Turn him over.
Yes.
Come on, Chu Chu.
Newly cooked ﻿white plum cakes. They're still hot.
Perfect timing.
Put the cakes on him.
All right.
Done.
After the cakes are put on him, we need to wait for a while.
I'll guard here.
Miss Leng, go and get some rest.
How can I rest when you don't?
Besides, His Highness urged me to keep you company.
Your Highness. General.
How's it going? Have you gotten anything?
Don't be anxious. It'll be done soon.
Bruises?
He didn't have bruises when he was taken out of the well.
He was drowned in the well.
The water is cold. And he just died.
Bruises on his corpse could hardly appear directly.
Normally, they appear in one or two days.
But if we want to see the bruises earlier, we can steam the corpse
on the newly burned pit for a while,
put some paper bathed in wine vinegar where there might be bruises,
and put the hot white plum cakes.
If there're real bruises, they'll appear.
[Bruises on the back and neck]
Your Highness, this bruise proves that someone knocked him out
and drowned him in the well.
[Drowned in the well]
He's the only man who could do it.
Who?
What an easy and effective way to recognize friends and enemies with the red ribbon!
You're awesome, Your Highness.
You even predicted that rebels would get changed before the fight.
It's not hard to predict.
When two groups of men fight in the same clothes,
they'll get accidentally injured
without some striking changes on their clothes.
Go!
Your Highness, how did you know Zhao Jie was the murderer?
- Time.
- Time?
The time when he killed Wu Chen.
Last night when we searched for Wu Chen, Zhao Jie came very late.
General Leng, I was taking a bath and I'm late.
We thought he was late because he was taking a bath.
But after Chu Chu found something fishy on Wu Chen's corpse,
I asked Zhao Jie's guard outside his camp.
The guard told me that he had taken a bath for one hour.
During that, he didn't ask for more hot water.
Last night, I noticed his hands.
After being bathed in water for one hour,
[Bathed in water]
[Skin on hands]
his hands should have looked pale or had winkles.
That's it.
When he said he was having a bath, he was finding an excuse.
In fact, it was when he killed Wu Chen.
That was the time.
Kill him!
End the fight.
If we want to catch them all, we must let Zhao Jie leave first.
Only when they think they can win, they'll come out together.
Upon hearing the horn,
General Leng's closest soldiers will fight back and besiege them,
so that none of the rebels can escape.
Zhao Jie!
You traitor! Surrender yourself!
This room looks neat and nothing seems special.
What are we looking for?
As the supreme commander of the rebel plan,
Zhao Jie must have had chances to contact his superior directly.
[The Book of Songs]
We may find some clues here about his superior.
Your Highness, are you sure Duke Chang is his superior?
Anyway, Zhao Jie isn't the man who manipulated the whole plan.
He doesn't have the ability or chances to make Li Zhang work for him.
He isn't able to make trouble in Chang'an, either.
So far, we've only arrested chess pieces.
We still don't know where the chess player is.
After Hou Bin died, Zhao Jie is the only man
who is experienced and powerful enough to take his place.
Once General Leng let him be the Vice Military Commissioner,
he would tell people General Leng was badly sick
and then he could take over the army.
Taking over the army forcibly is Zhao Jie's backup plan.
He didn't expect us to find out about Wu Chen,
so he had to kill Wu Chen hastily.
Before that, he might have written a letter to his master
about the changes.
He... He hasn't sent the letter yet.
Let's look for it, then.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
It's the letter Zhao Jie hasn't sent yet?
Yes.
There are ten patterns on it.
Some patterns are duplicate.
I think it's a cipher letter
[4 7 3 1 5 10 8 6 2 9 8 10 7]
where patterns are used to represent one to ten.
When there are numbers, there should be a decoding book.
It's not as easy as the cipher letter Prince Consort left us.
Expecting someone to decode it, Prince Consort left us enough clues.
With it, people will decode it unless they're idiots.
But Zhao Jie doesn't want anyone to decode it.
If he puts the decoding book in his mind,  how can we decode it?
Even if Zhao Jie has a great memory,
he won't remember such an important thing only with his mind.
He can only remember the patterns representing ten numbers.
He must have a decoding book to translate the numbers into words.
[The Book of Songs]
This is the decoding book.
The Book of Songs?
Other books of his are mainly about military or national policies.
They haven't been read for a long time.
He often read the Book of Songs.
There're over 300 poems in it,
concerning astronomy, geography, phenology and folk custom.
[Sundial, compass]
The words are abundant enough for basic communication.
[Sweet Green Rice Ball, lion dance]
Your Highness, other books on the shelf also look clean.
How do you know they haven't been read for a long time?
They look clean because Zhao Jie is a senior military officer.
Cleaners come often.
But cleaners only dust the cover of the books,
instead of inside pages.
The weather is damp in the Southwest.
After a long time, an unopened book will be musty.
If it's not opened for years, there will be mildew.
Three volumes of the Book of Songs aren't musty.
Their edges are worn out, too.
So, he must have often read them.
[Often read with worn-out edges]
Your Highness, you have a sharp nose.
It smells really musty.
We've found the decoding book. But we don't know how the patterns match the numbers.
Ten patterns represent ten numbers.
There should be...
3.6288 million types of permutations.
Ye... Yes.
[4 7 3 1 5 10 8 6 2 9 8 10 7]
[Wu failed, I killed him. Won't join you in Chang'an as scheduled.]
But only one permutation can translate the numbers
into relevant words.
If we keep trying, when can we find the right permutation?
[Wu...]
Your Highness, you're incredible!
As long as you can thoroughly recite the Book of Songs, you'll figure out the words, too.
[Wu failed, I killed him. Won't join you in Chang'an as scheduled.]
I'm too old to move quickly.
Be careful.
Grandfather, have some water.
All right.
Grandfather, are you all right?
It should be me.
What?
It should be me who died.
Grandfather, after the problem is solved, let's go back home.
Let's go back to Chang'an.
There are the best doctors in Chang'an. They'll cure you.
My silly granddaughter, don't take the doctor's words seriously.
Can I really live
as long as the doctor says?
Can't you just listen to me once?
All right. All right.
Yue'er, something in this world matters more
than keeping us alive.
Or Commandery Prince An wouldn't have come here.
You wouldn't have come here with him, either.
It's unrelated at all.
What does it have anything to do with your disease?
All right, Yue'er.
Just take care of yourself.
Don't bother about me.
General.
- How's it going, Jinyu?
- Have you found something?
It's what Zhao Jie said in the letter to his superior.
Wu failed. I killed him.
Won't join you in Chang'an as scheduled.
It meant Wu Chen failed and was killed.
Join you in Chang'an? Join?
I'm afraid there's another group of rebels.
They picked a date to join each other in Chang'an.
We'd better find the detailed list.
Even if we can't, we should estimate a number.
Otherwise, people in Chang'an can hardly deal with them.
Our priority is to interrogate the captured rebels.
Jing Yi, go interrogate them.
He doesn't need to go.
- They were all executed.
- What?
They were bandits.
General Leng didn't kill them
because he had pity on them who did bad things for a living.
In case they hurt common people, he recruited them.
About this, soldiers have a lot of criticism.
They made trouble again.
If General Leng didn't kill them immediately,
he could hardly convince his subordinates.
All right. I have no job now.
None of them are alive.
Your Highness, let me have a try.
- What do you mean?
- Let me do the autopsy.
Now that they're dead, you should let me find clues from their corpses.
They look like soldiers who have received training for years,
but we may find traces of old lives
in their internal organs or skeletons.
If I can do the autopsy, I may find some clues.
All right. Do the autopsy.
In whatever way you want.
Brother, take her there immediately.
All right.
[Antique Store]
[Modern and Ancient Antiquities]
It's a pleasure to see you, Eunuch Qin.
I'm sorry that I haven't welcomed you.
I'm sorry.
Are you an idiot?
I told you this is...
My subordinates bothered you the other day.
Please kindly forgive them.
Search the place carefully!
- Yes!
- You!
- What...?
- Go.
- Yes. Yes.
Show me all your purchasing lists of this year.
[Account Book]
These things look like imperial things. I'll take them back for inspection.
If they're not, I'll return them to you.
This one looks like an imperial thing, too.
It doesn't matter, Eunuch Qin.
The Ruyi you gave me...
I had it discerned very carefully.
It's quite a precious thing. Thank you.
It's just a little gift.
It's quite my honor that you accept it.
- The words carved on the copper Ruyi look quite interesting.
- Yeah.
I'm interested in that.
May I have a word with you?
Sure. Sure.
It's my honor.
Come, please.
Please stay, Eunuch Sun.
Come this way, please.
I...
Come, please.
Tell me. Where's Xu Rugui?
Don't worry, Eunuch Qin.
When Xu Rugui first came back to Chang'an, he was dying.
Luckily, he struggled to live.
After a period of treatment, he can talk now.
Just get to the point.
I'm quite busy with palace business
and I don't have time for useless talk!
You served three emperors and you investigated it a few times.
Then you should know
what Duke Chang suffered in Qianzhou, right?
Duke Chang?
It's said that a group of bandits
attacked his mansion in Qianzhou.
His family was slaughtered.
Everyone in his mansion was killed.
No one stayed alive.
Not bandits.
What did you say? They weren't bandits?
It wasn't bandits who slaughtered Duke Chang's family,
but an official army from the palace?
Official army?
How do you know that?
Duke Chang witnessed that.
His Highness exchanged clothes with his study companion
and hid among corpses so that he could survive.
He never forgot such a miserable scene.
I see.
But why does it concern me?
Eunuch Qin, His Highness knows that you're caring for him.
He also wants to talk to you about old affairs.
But it's not convenient for him to come now.
So, I've been asked to entertain you to resolve the misunderstanding
that we sold imperial objects
and also to reassure you.
When His Highness takes care of Xu Rugui,
it'll do no harm to you.
You're threatening me?
I don't dare to.
Eunuch Qin, His Highness wants to cooperate with you to kill the tyrant,
take back the throne belonging to him and restore our nation.
We rely on you to do such a great thing!
Cheers.
Now that His Highness wants cooperation, shouldn't I meet him first?
He's been waiting for you.
He's in Chang'an?
- Who's that?
- It's me, Master. I'm Mingde.
Master.
Aren't you on duty today?
Why are you coming here, instead of serving His Majesty?
Don't get angry, Master.
Last night, His Majesty had a cold.
When he got up this morning, he felt sick and he was angry.
He kicked me out when he didn't want to see me.
Master, we're going to make Duke Chang the emperor.
Why don't you do away with the present emperor?
What do you need your head for?
To make you look like a human?
Please enlighten me, Master.
The present emperor is quite a tough man.
He pretended to be insane and fooled everyone.
Now, he's trying to suppress our division.
He sounds us out from time to time.
Cunning Jing Zhi is also making trouble with the other officials.
Do you think we can dethrone him so easily?
If we don't act carefully and make him realize something,
we'll be killed first!
Serve His Majesty carefully.
Our priority is to kill Xiao Jinyu and his men
in case he ruins the big plan Duke Chang and I have.
Don't worry, Master.
I'll make careful arrangements.
I won't let Xiao Jinyu come back alive.
All right. Go get it done.
Yes.
Today, I come to you for a clear answer.
The soldier from Qianzhou...
Who's he?
Don't worry, General Leng. He isn't a bad man.
I certainly know he isn't.
My granddaughter looks at him
in the exact way her mother looked at her father.
Could he be Vice Minister Jing Yi,
the son of Senior Jing?
You have sharp eyes, General Leng.
So, he really is.
I hear that Jing Yi is good at identifying lies.
Did you disguise him like that and put him in my military clinic
so that he could get more intel?
It was expedient.
No offense, General Leng. Please understand.
Your Highness.
Chu Chu, what have you got?
Your Highness, it's so weird.
What have you got?
General Xiao, are you sure they were recruited as bandits?
Yes. I'm quite sure.
No way.
Not all of them are bandits.
Not all of them?
- What are they, then?
- Soldiers.
Soldiers who had been trained for years.
No way!
I picked ten corpses of different batches of recruitments.
Then I found that four of them were trained in the army.
They never lived as bandits.
They used to be bandits many years ago.
It's normal when you can't find such traces.
It's not.
His Highness said that there would be traces of any action.
There would be traces with bodies, too.
No one can easily hide what a life he used to live.
His body would record everything.
If they're real bandits, what traces should be recorded?
Bandits run about in the mountain.
So, they have strong shanks and a strong heart.
[Leg]
[Heart]
Their patellae are usually worn out
with frequent injuries and sprains.
There're traces of recovery on their skeletal muscles
after they have fractures.
[Fractures on arms and legs]
But among the ten men, only six have such features.
They were obviously bandits for a long time.
The other four men have some features
[Unknown]
like Military Commissioner's soldiers.
No way! They were definitely recruited from the den of bandits.
Brother, I remember you said that
bandits in Qianzhou not only caused trouble to the Military Commissioner's army,
but also disturbed the battalion of Qianzhou Army.
Is that so?
Yes.
Qianzhou Army isn't like us.
They never fight hard with the bandits.
When they robbed Qianzhou Army, they snatched money and food.
Did they also snatch soldiers?
Snatch soldiers?
They did, as I heard.
Maybe soldiers were taken away to do labor work.
When failing to defeat them,
did Qianzhou Army keep recruiting more soldiers?
I'm not sure about that.
Your Highness, you mean...?
Brother, go get the recruitment record of Qianzhou Army
with my official seal.
All right. I'll be on my way.
- Eunuch Qin.
- Go. Go.
Eunuch Qin.
Minister Han.
Minister Han, His Majesty forgot to tell you something when he talked to you.
He asked me to wait here for you
so that I could bring you the message.
Minister Han, may I have a word with you?
Eunuch Qin, just get to the point.
Minister Han, I told on Princess Xiping to you the other day.
Do you not remember it at all?
I'm still checking on that.
What?
With two witnesses, you still doubt that?
Eunuch Qin, I've verified the two ladies.
They did work for Princess Xiping.
But you want to tell on Princess Xiping with some useless words from two ladies?
Even if you report to His Majesty,
Princess Xiping will defend herself with clever talk.
It's a big crime to deceive His Majesty.
I can't be too careful.
Do you mean there isn't enough evidence
to close the case?
Well, please take care of the case and make further investigation.
But I'm telling you.
What's faked can't be true.
You'll find out something.
Minister Han, His Majesty has drafted a decree
to get Commandery Prince An back to Chang'an.
You must hurry up.
Let me remind you.
To do something big, you must be daring and ruthless!
Don't show petty kindness!
Trying to fob me off?
Timing and subtitles brought to you by The Imperial Coroners @ Viki.com
♫  Nothing can stop me  ♫
♫  From missing you all the time  ♫
♫  The moonlight appears, cold in the late night,
as the world changes  ♫
♫  Only with you by my side can I embrace my yearning for you  ♫
♫  When I close my eyes I meet you once again  ♫
♫  I'll gently brush your hair by your ear  ♫
♫  Life is long, with love and regrets in this world  ♫
♫  With you by my side, no matter how far I go,
we'll never be apart  ♫
♫  With your smile, in this moment, let me
cherish this lifetime  ♫
♫  Only for you, I have to worry about the end of this life  ♫
♫  I’m still young, with my love not yet realized for you, but I'm
willing to be here for you till the end
♫  You can rely on me in this lifetime  ♫
♫  Hope to spend this beautiful lifetime together  ♫