Timing and subtitles brought to you by The Imperial Coroners @ Viki.com
Xu Rugui used Lady Xu's hairpin
to lead me to discover the identities of Chu Chu's biological parents,
trying to damage the trust between Chu Chu and I.
Whatever happens, I will find out the truth.
My mother was killed by the housekeeper of the Xu family
and Xu Rugui is my uncle.
Your Majesty, I've found out
that the rumor about Duke Chang these days
came from a brat doing chores in the imperial garden.
He was new in the palace
and hasn't changed the vulgar habit he developed when he was out there.
Somehow he got the nerve and made up some shadowy stories
about the late Duke Chang.
I've severely reprimanded his supervisor
who teaches him about the rules.
Is it really a new minion who spread the rumors about
the son of Emperor Wuzong in the capital?
Yes.
He is bold indeed.
He had a few drinks and dared to talk nonsense in the palace
which was heard by the bored servants and spread outside the palace.
And everyone is talking about it.
But he is also timid indeed.
He was so scared that he had a heart attack and died
before I could bring him to you.
Did he die of fear?
Yes.
The rumors...
Are these just rumors?
Your Majesty, you know that the offspring of Emperor Wuzong
have been dead for a long time.
These words are just rumors.
If you want to stop these rumors as soon as possible,
I have a solution.
But I'm afraid you need to sacrifice a little bit.
I don't know whether I should say it.
Just go ahead.
I think these people can be incited by the rumors
because they have forgotten the fact that
that Emperor Wuzong's sons died a long time ago.
You only need to remind them and the rumors will naturally disappear.
Tell me how I should remind them.
Your Majesty, you can choose an auspicious day
and give posthumous names to the sons of Emperor Wuzong.
Posthumous names?
Good.
Only the dead will be given posthumous names.
You are showing your benevolence.
I believe no minister will object to it.
Those who are discussing Duke Chang in the court and the commonalty
will also deeply admire your generosity
and become more loyal to serve you.
Good.
Order the academician to draft an edict now and ask
the Ministry of Rites and the imperial astronomer to get on it immediately.
Yes, Your Majesty.
Order Wu Jiang to enter the palace tomorrow.
I have something to ask him.
It has been a while since Commandery Prince An left Chang'an.
Why is there no news from him at all?
If Xiao Heng is really in the Southwest,
there is no way he would avoid his biological son.
Yes, Your Majesty.
[The Imperial Coroner]
[Episode 17]
Why did you ask about Duke Chang?
Do you still remember Yan Ming?
Yan Ming?
You found a scroll at Yan Ming's place.
I told you that Yan Ming was looking for someone.
Was he looking for Duke Chang?
It's possible.
When Yan Ming was repairing a book,
he had a habit that an official would have.
When he met a deceased person
whose year of death or whereabouts are unknown, he would try to find it out through the clues from the old scrolls.
The ink on his scroll was still new.
It can be seen that he got interested in the late emperor's young son
whose year of death is unknown.
Did he suspect that Duke Chang was still alive?
Before I left Chang'an, I asked Wu Jiang
to secretly verify what's written in his manuscript.
Hold on.  A nerd scribbled a few words and you took it seriously?
You even verified it?
Yan Ming's deduction is not rigorous enough,
but it's not all unreasonable.
The three people Xu Rugui ordered to kill in Chang'an
are Lu Chuansheng, the Capital Liaison Representative in Qianzhou
responsible for the communication between Chang'an and Qianzhou;
Liu Yue, the head of the Ministry of Revenue in charge of coins minting in the Southwest;
and Feng Jie, the Minister of War
who just finished the inspection of the military affairs in the Southwest before he was killed.
He hadn't had time to report on the military inspection.
All of them are related to Qianzhou.
And Qianzhou was also granted to Duke Chang at that time.
At such a point, Yan Ming was murdered because of a scroll about looking into the whereabouts of Duke Chang.
So you are suspecting
that Duke Chang is behind these things related to Qianzhou?
He killed Yan Ming because he was afraid that someone would know he was alive.
It doesn't make sense.
If he is behind it,
the dancing girl should have destroyed the scroll when she killed Yan Ming.
Why would she hide it?
- There is another possibility.
- What possibility?
He killed Yan Ming,
not because he is afraid that people will know he is alive,
but because he wants people to know that he is alive.
Master.
There is one thing I can't figure out.
Why are you protecting that brat who took poison and committed suicide?
You think I'm protecting him?
Of course.
He must have committed suicide by taking poison
and there is someone behind it.
This Antique Store might be the clue.
But you didn't mention a word about it to the emperor.
Aren't you protecting him?
You are short-sighted.
I'm not protecting him,
I'm protecting us.
I'm foolish, please enlighten me.
The emperor asked us to look into this,
do you think he really wants to know the truth?
He was just testing us.
When the son of the late emperor was dying, we were by his side.
He suspects that we are behind it.
I have to solve it in this way to finish our job.
Master, you are wise indeed.
Mingde, let me tell you something from my heart.
Stop being that glib.
Try to be cleverer.
The channels of communication between Qianzhou and Chang'an court were cut off.
A large number of copper coins were minted.
The news about military affairs in the Southwest was strictly prevented from being reported to the court.
If there is one person behind all these things,
what do you think this person is up to?
What?
To plot a rebellion!
That's right.
Rebels of all dynasties want to be the ruler in the end.
But a dead person can't ascend the throne.
No one will support a dead man to be an emperor.
Therefore, if he wants to ascend to the throne in the name of Duke Chang,
he must bring Duke Chang back to life first.
You mean he killed Yan Ming
because he wanted you to discover the scroll
and find out Yan Ming was killed
because of his conclusion that Duke Chang is still alive,
so as to whip up public opinion
and then he can rebel in the name of Duke Chang?
That's why I've been trying to contain the news.
But I got news from Wu Jiang
that there are rumors in Chang'an about Duke Chang being alive.
I guess he realized that I'm not being used by him,
that's why he has to use the dumbest way to spread rumors.
There is no evidence but rumors.
He can't make any waves.
I'm not worried that he can make any waves with the rumors.
But I'm afraid he is so eager to spread the rumors
because everything is ready and he only needs a chance to do it.
If that's the case, we have to find him quickly.
He caused so many messes in Qianzhou.
Maybe he is hiding in Qianzhou.
This is too important to rush into.
Right now, Qianzhou is in such a mess.
A lot of things happened.
But these things are connected and interlocked.
If we can pull a thread from it, everything will be clear then.
Duke Chang is the trueborn son of the late emperor.
The emperor now is the uncle of the late emperor.
If Duke Chang is still alive and you find him,
it's fine if he is behind these things.
But if he is innocent,
how should the emperor deal with it?
That's exactly why I didn't tell you about it.
Weren't you blaming me for not taking you to handle those dangerous affairs?
I do have a selfish motive.
What?
If anything happens to me,
you are the only one I can entrust with the posthumous affairs.
And only you can coax my mother and my brother.
Your Highness.
My original intention of coming to the Three Judicial Offices was to be a rakish young master
with my father and my brother's official authority.
How can it turn out like this?
You worked for it.
Fine. I deserve it.
What should we do to Xu Rugui?
Bring him back to the county office or send him to the Prefect's Mansion?
- Keep him here for now.
- Keep him here?
He just killed the father of the Deputy Magistrate, Tan Gui.
Keeping him in the county office may cause trouble.
But if we skip the magistrate and send him to Li Zhang,
it will also bring troubles if Li Zhang looks into it.
Your Highness,
you are afraid that Xu Rugui will tell others about Chu Chu's background. Right?
It has been our speculation and Xu Rugui's side of the story so far.
Before we have any conclusive evidence, don't bring this up to anyone.
Your Highness, you are going to suffer.
What?
You have someone inside of you.
All the prisoners who have not been arrested in Tang are all here.
Of course, I have people inside.
Cut it out.
Your enemies in the court include the discontented officials of the Three Judicial Offices,
the incompetent magistrates, and those eunuchs like Qin Luan.
Do they ever stop picking on you together?
Have you ever been so pissed off by them?
It's not the time that I brought trouble to you,
when have you been so angry with me?
It's such an important clue.
You must consider it carefully.
By the way, I brought this for you.
If you won't use it as evidence,
then give it to Chu Chu as a keepsake.
Father, I want to ask you something.
What are you panicked about?
When Chu Chu's mother died,
did she die at the place of Chu Chu's uncle?
Yes.
Her brother is Chu Chu's uncle.
Have you met Chu Chu's uncle?
Yes.
Can you recognize him now?
Now? Where?
Maybe...
Did he come back to Guanling County?
Father, maybe he is locked inside our woodshed.
What? The man locked inside the woodshed is Chu Chu's uncle?
When they brought him here, his head was covered.
I was worried about Chu Chu
and didn't pay much attention to that man.
Yeah. They also said that there is one thing concerning Chu Chu's life.
- Concerning her life?
- What is it?
They spoke vaguely and I didn't hear clearly.
Father, what should we do?
Do what?
You are not sure about anything yet. Don't be in such a hurry.
I mean, Father. Are you going to let her die just because she is not your biological daughter?
What nonsense are you talking about?
I'm telling the truth.
Xu Zongfang?
Thank you.
Mr. Chu, why are you still up so late?
I worked late.
I saw the light here and I'm here to bring you a pot of tea.
Give me the tea.
Thank you, Mr. Chu The dew is heavy in the late night.
Please go back and rest earlier.
I want to go inside and get something.
Mr. Chu, please.
Thanks.
Is he the bandit who kidnapped Chu Chu?
Yes, Mr. Chu. He is very dangerous.
You'd better go back to your room.
All right.
Father, how was it?
They covered his face and gagged his mouth. I can't tell.
All right, let's leave it to tomorrow.
- Father...
- That's it.
Everyone in this world will be unable to speak or move one day.
Our Chu family is to say out loud
what they want to say but cannot say.
Grandpa, can you hear the dead?
I don't hear them I see them.
Why can't I see them?
Do you also want to see them?
Yes.
Good.
Grandpa.
I'm here to see if you are getting better.
What are you busy with early in the morning?
The room is too messy. I'm tidying it up.
Father always said the room is too messy to be a girl's room.
How does it not look like a girl's room?
If it's neat and clean, it won't be my Chu Chu's style.
Grandpa, have a seat.
Grandpa, it was my fault yesterday.
I made you worry about me.
You are like a coroner working for a high official now.
You speak like a grown-up and you know the etiquette now.
When you were at home before, I always saw you as a kid.
I thought a girl wouldn't get into the county office.
So I didn't give you any serious lessons.
Now it turns out that I was short-sighted.
Grandpa, why are you saying this suddenly?
You will always be a member of the Chu family.
I promise you.
Tell me the truth.
Don't you trust me anymore?
Of course, I trust you.
Even you trust me, you still can't feel at ease.
I understand.
A verbal promise doesn't count.
A coroner needs to write a report for the autopsy.
An official needs the case file to settle a lawsuit.
And it also needs evidence to proves that you are the daughter of the Chu family.
This is the genealogy of the Chu family.
By the ordinary rules, women can't be written on it.
But I'll make the decision this time.
If you are willing to be the child of the Chu family,
I'll write you in the genealogy.
In the future, no one can say that you are not a child of the Chu family.
Grandpa.
What are you doing? Get up.
Grandpa, I'm ungrateful.
I have a favor to ask you. Promise me you will say yes.
Get up first before you tell me.
Grandpa, just let me finish it.
Otherwise, you will think I'm being childish even if I say it.
Fine. I promise you. You can tell me now.
I don't expect my name to be written in the genealogy.
I only need you to promise me that no matter who my father is,
you must bury me beside my mother if I die one day.
When you have time, remember to visit me with my father and my brother.
What silly words are you talking about?
Grandpa, I'm serious.
Jinyu, do you hear that?
Please, don't despise me because of my background at that time.
If it's inconvenient for you, I don't need any offering or joss stick.
Just come and visit me.
I want to know if you are doing well.
I'm afraid... I'm afraid I won't be able to see you again.
Why do I feel like Miss Chu is preparing for her death?
Are you still thinking about Father?
Did you tell Jing Yi about what happened in your father's mansion?
No.
But he is clever enough.
I think he probably knows what happened.
I'm not worried whether he knows it or not.
I'm just worried he will tell the people in the palace about Chu Chu.
About Miss Chu?
Chu Chu.
Your Highness?
Have a seat.
Why did you get up so early? You should sleep more.
I... I can't sleep.
- Your Highness, is there anything you want to say but you can't say?
- Yes.
Is it about the case?
Kind of. How about you?
Me, too.
That's why you are here washing the stones?
No, I'm going to grill the mushrooms.
When there was something I wanted to say but couldn't say,
I would put it in the vegetables and eat the dish after I cooked it.
Then I don't need to think about it.
I don't know if it will work this time.
Well, I'll eat with you after you cook it.
It's better than eating alone.
Your Highness, it's nice to be your coroner.
I...
What's this?
Your Highness, what's wrong?
These stones seem to be glowing.
These are just ordinary stones.
There are a lot of stones like this right here.
I remember Witch Doctor said
that there is something like spar inside these stones. I don't quite understand.
Anyway, these stones seem to glow when being illuminated by the light.
It's very beautiful.
Light?
Lord!
Damn! You scared me.
Can't you keep your voice down?
I almost ruined the koi sculpture.
What's the fuss about?
There is a letter from Guanling County
that they found the traces of a fugitive wanted by the court, Xu Rugui.
Give the order immediately and catch the wanted criminal now!
Yes!
Hold on.
Is Commandery Prince An still in Pingle Town?
Yes.
I also heard that he dug up a woman's grave.
Dug...?
Didn't he come to find his father?
Why did he dig a woman's grave?
Does he want to get a dead stepmother for his dead father?
That's funny, My Lord.
By the way, My Lord.
You don't need to worry about
the investigation into minting coins privately.
Why is that?
The man drinking with you
and Magistrate Zheng in the County Office of Guanling on that day was not Commandery Prince An.
- Who was that person then?
- That was the Vice Minister of the Court of Judicial Review, Jing Yi.
Jing Yi?
Vice Minister Jing is just an idle young master.
He rarely does anything serious.
When you had drinks on that day,
I guess he was just making fun of you and Magistrate Zheng.
What do you know?
There must be a plan.
The Jing family is a family of foxes.
They are best at finding out the truth through expressions and voices.
I dealt with Jing Yi in the way I should deal with Commandery Prince An.
It's wrong.
It's all wrong.
It's all wrong!
They messed with me must have been because they wanted to step in the coin minting thing.
Keep an eye on Guanling County.
Let me know if you have any news!
Yes!
[Princess Xiping's Mansion]
Greetings to Your Grace.
You may rise.
Thank you, Your Grace.
You came early this morning.
Did anything happen to Jinyu?
Your Grace, rest assured.
Commandery Prince An and General Xiao are doing well.
There is something His Highness asked me to show you.
He is in a hurry so I came in early in the morning.
Please forgive me for disturbing your rest.
What is it? Bring it to me.
Yes.
[To Mother]
His Highness is investigating a case.
This hairpin belongs to a person involved in the case.
His Highness hopes that he can find out who this person involved is through this hairpin.
He said the owner of this hairpin should be a person of high status.
Maybe you can recognize it.
It looks familiar.
I got it.
This was a gift from my mother to Madam Jing.
You mean the wife of Senior Jing?
Yes, it's her.
Master.
Come in.
There is an urgent letter from Qianzhou.
[To Father]
Well...
Is it a hairpin?
It looks so familiar.
I have the exact same hairpin.
- Really?
- Yes.
I remember it.
When we got married, Princess Xiping's mother gave me a pair of hairpins.
I kept one by myself and gave the other one to someone else.
Wait.
Look!  Do they look the same?
This is the style of young people.
I haven't worn it for years.
Do you remember whom you gave this hairpin to?
It's been a long time.
I can't remember.
But I have a record of the things I gave away.
I'll tell you after I check it.
Go to find the housekeeper and tell him
that I got slightly sick last night
and I'll ask for leave for the morning court.
You are not going to the court today?
Where are you going?
We have something to do. We will be back soon.
No, you can go anywhere you want.
But Chu Chu must stay.
Missy, you haven't recovered yet. Take the medicine and get some good rest at home.
Brother, I'm recovered. I'm fine.
No, I said no.
Stay at home. You are not allowed to go anywhere.
- We have a very important thing to do.
- I don't care how important it is.
Come back with me.
Let her go!
- She is my sister...!
- She is a coroner of the Three Judicial Offices!
I'm going to take her out to handle a case.
You are also a public servant.
You should know what the crime is to obstruct your superior's work.
It's very cloudy now. What if it rains?
Well, does the coroner In Guanling County only go out to work on sunny days?
- You...!
- Brother, I said I'm fine. Just let me go.
I'm just like you.
We are both coroners working for the government.
When you were working, no matter what happened,
as long as Magistrate Zheng asked you to go to the county office, you never hesitated.
Why are you stopping me now?
I am also a coroner just like you.
Commandery Prince An asked me to work, I will go no matter what happens.
Rest assured.
Since she is leaving with me, I will take good care of her.
What happened yesterday won't happen again.
I can't rest assured.
It will be too late if what happened yesterday happens again!
Let me ask you.
Where exactly are you taking Chu Chu to?
Why didn't I hear that there was a homicide in the county?
The homicide in the county should be handled by the county office.
My work is beyond the control of the county office.
Don't follow us secretly.
Otherwise, I will handle it according to the official principles.
You can try it if you are not afraid of losing the qualification of a coroner.
Let's go.
Brother, I'll be back in a while.
Your Highness, don't be angry.
Don't harm your health because of it.
I'm not angry.
My brother isn't usually like that.
I don't know what's wrong with him today.
I guess he was scared by what happened yesterday.
Don't worry. I'm not angry.
I said those words because I don't want him to follow us.
Didn't you promise my father that you will keep the secret for him?
If he follows us, it will be inconvenient for us to talk.
You're not angry...
General Xiao, is he really not angry?
Since he said it, just take it.
All right.
What a stubborn man.
Grandpa, are you going to send food to Xu...
Send food to that bandit?
Your father went to the county office to work.
It's time for a meal.
I'll send the food to him.
Although he is a bad person and he hurt Chu, we still can't starve him.
He committed a crime and he will be punished according to the law.
Grandpa, let me do it.
He is dangerous.
I can handle such a small thing.
Go and do what you should do.
Grandpa, I also need to go there and pick up a few things.
Let me do it.
Tell the two guards that their meal is on the table.
Ask them to eat it when they have time. Don't let the food get cold.
Got it. Go back to your room.
Sirs, it has been hard for you.
I'm here to bring him some food.
Thank you, Mr. Chu.
Your meal is also ready.
It's in the kitchen.
Hurry up and have a bite.
We can't. This person is really dangerous.
We can take turns to eat.
Thank you, Mr. Chu.
I won't untie him. He can't run away.
What's more, this kitchen is so close to here.
I'll call you if he runs away.
Commandery Prince An just left with Chu Chu and that general
to investigate some case.
I'm afraid they will send someone back and ask you to go with them.
It's hard to do your job well when you are starving.
I can't afford the punishment if they blame me.
I'm a little hungry.
Thank you, Mr. Chu.
- We will be back soon.
- Okay.
- Mr. Chu, be careful.
- Got it. Go ahead.
Please.
I want to ask you something.
I'll take out the cloth from your mouth.
Don't shout.
Let me ask you.
Are you Xu Zongfang?
You must be Chu He.
- How do you know that?
- Don't worry about how I know that.
Hurry, untie the rope for me.
Chu Chu will be dead later.
What are you saying?
You just said that Xiao Jinyu and his brother took Chu Chu away.
They are going to kill Chu Chu.
But you are the one who almost killed Chu Chu yesterday!
You are killing me.
Since you came here to ask me if I am Xu Zongfang,
it means you know that I am Chu Chu's uncle. Right?
I was trying to take her away to save her.
Don't talk nonsense.
No one would...
No one would save a person in that way.
Didn't Chu Chu tell you that her biological father, Yun Yi,
is a criminal who rebelled with the Military Commissioner of Jiannan
and killed the father of Xiao Jinyu and Xiao Jinli?
Yesterday they opened the coffin of Chu Chu's biological mother, which is my sister.
They must have known the identity of Chu Chu's biological father.
I think they are going to retaliate against Chu Chu and kill her!
Well, I'll go and find them.
Don't!
Chu He, these two brothers are highly powerful
and they have soldiers in hand.
If you go now, you are taking down the whole Chu family!
I'll do it. Let me go now.
I'm Chu Chu's uncle.
I failed Chu Chu and her mother at that time.
But right now, I will protect her with my life.
What are you waiting for?
It will be too late if you don't untie me now.
Let's take the food back and eat lest anything should happen.
I'll go back, too.
Are you sure you can save Chu Chu?
Of course.
Hurry up.
Well... You two finished your meal so fast.
I think we should eat here.
Thank you, Mr. Chu.
You can leave him to us now.
Okay, I'll leave.
Call me if you need anything.
Okay, thank you.
General! Your Highness!
Has anyone been here?
No one has been here.
Brother, give it to me.
Keep watch at the door. Don't let anyone approach.
Rest assured.
Chu Chu, close the door.
Okay.
Your Highness, why do you only place these four chess pieces?
I played twice with my elder brother and I played once with Jing Yi.
Every time at the end of the game,
there would always be these four chess pieces in these four positions.
Is there anything special about these four positions?
I haven't figured it out yet.
But when I saw those illuminated stones, these chess pieces,
and the layout of this room, I still feel that something is missing,
The layout of this room?
These were painted by Witch Doctor.
Does he like painting a lot?
He didn't like painting that much before.
But during the time before he left,
he just somehow started to like painting.
He didn't paint anything else but mountains and trees.
These paintings are all scenes of Guanling County
The mountain is Phoenix Mountain.
The water is Yong'an River.
Light...
Timing and subtitles brought to you by The Imperial Coroners @ Viki.com
♫  Nothing can stop me  ♫
♫  From missing you all the time  ♫
♫  The moonlight appears, cold in the late night,
as the world changes  ♫
♫  Only with you by my side can I embrace my yearning for you  ♫
♫  When I close my eyes I meet you once again  ♫
♫  I'll gently brush your hair by your ear  ♫
♫  Life is long, with love and regrets in this world  ♫
♫  With you by my side, no matter how far I go,
we'll never be apart  ♫
♫  With your smile, in this moment, let me
cherish this lifetime  ♫
♫  Only for you, I have to worry about the end of this life  ♫
♫  I’m still young, with my love not yet realized for you, but I'm
willing to be here for you till the end
♫  You can rely on me in this lifetime  ♫
♫  Hope to spend this beautiful lifetime together  ♫