Timing and subtitles brought to you by The Imperial Coroners @ Viki.com
His Highness has poor health,
yet he stayed up all night to make autopsy tools for me.
You made these with your own hands?
He even took me to investigate the case.
But I don't know what my brother was thinking.
Why couldn't he get along with His Highness?
And why must he take His Highness to the witch doctor's house to catch the ghost?
Indeed, they've caught the ghost,
but they discovered a body, a eunuch's body.
What secret does Sir Witch Doctor hide?
[Domestic Service]
[The Imperial Coroner]
[Episode 12]
Multiple wounds caused by sharp weapons on the body.
The cuts are small and shallow.
The lethal injury was an upward stab from the fifth rib on the left
through the heart and to the upper left of the back.
The murder weapon should be a hard cylindrical object
with a sharp point.
- Like...
- Like this.
Yes, like...
No, not like this.
This is the murder weapon.
This is the murder weapon?
The murder weapon and the body were preserved together.
What was the purpose of the one who hid the body?
Oh, right!  If this iron rod is the murder weapon, what is that blade for?
The positions of the wounds are very strange.
- What do you mean?
- Most of the injuries were on the forearms,
belly, and upper part of the thighs.
[Wound positions]
The lethal injury at the top was stabbed upwards.
[In | Out]
What's so strange about that?
The dead was a martial artist.
If one were to kill him, the murderer would also be a good fighter.
Wait!  How do you know that he was a martial artist?
Miss Leng told me that martial artists know when to yield.
It means when they know they have to get injured,
they know the level of their own injuries.
The non-lethal injuries on this person are long and shallow.
Because when the murder weapon cut his skin, he drew himself back
from deep cuts, which could cause heavy damage.
That's true.
But there's nothing strange about it.
The murderer is someone who could kill a martial artist,
then he should attack the vital parts.
For example, head and throat.
But the murderer didn't do so.
Girl, is this what you're trying to say?
Yes.
But... it's not like the murderer didn't want to, he just couldn't.
Your Highness.
Tell me.
Other than the lethal injury, the rest of the wounds are shallow.
The deepest is 5-centimeters deep.
However, the iron rod is at least 60-centimeters long.
It means the murderer and the dead didn't have a close fight.
They kept about 60-centimeters away from each other.
The dead has a wound on the right forearm,
which was stabbed upwards from left to right.
Cut my neck from the left.
The dead has another wound on the right thigh,
which was cut downwards.
And the wound on the belly was cut from left to right.
The lethal injury was an upward stab.
What are you doing? Don't take advantage of my sister.
Get up!
Calm down. I didn't say your sister took advantage of my brother.
Shoo!
Brother, I was being rude.
Brother, we're trying to make an inference of how the person was murdered
and how the murderer acted.
I played the dead, he played the murderer.
Somehow, something felt strange in our inference.
The wounds on the dead are at the same height, the same side.
And judging from his height,
the murderer's attacks were so low as if he were a child.
But a child wouldn't have the strength.
If the murderer was kneeling or lying down,
that would make sense.
What sense?
Nonsense, in my opinion.
It wasn't a friendly match.
The murderer could just get up and cut his throat, couldn't he?
Why the extra steps? He just wanted to take advantage of you.
You...
I couldn't figure that out as well.
It's not that he didn't want to get up, he couldn't.
He couldn't?
- Do you mean...
- Sir Witch Doctor?
His leg is injured. He can't stand up.
So you mean the suspect is... Sir Witch Doctor?
No way. Why would he murder someone?
Didn't you see how they moved?
The eunuch wanted to kill him.
He fought the eunuch back to keep himself alive.
It wasn't his fault.
No, Sir Witch Doctor didn't do it on purpose.
Hadn't he killed the eunuch, he would have been dead.
Yes.
It was a justifiable homicide.
Why didn't he go to the law enforcement?
If he didn't want others to know, he could've buried the body.
Why would he spend so much effort keeping the body well-preserved
and hide the murder weapon and the body in the wall?
He did this because he was trying to keep the evidence.
Keep the evidence?
The evidence of the murder he committed?
Chu Chu, you said you heard a ghost's cry in this house on a random day when you were little,
then people said it was haunted.
Can you remember when it started exactly?
I can't.
I do.
My father and I helped Sir Witch Doctor build the walls.
Right after the walls were built, the house was haunted.
My father felt bad about it at that time.
He must have kept the evidence for some reason.
But he didn't want other eunuchs to find it,
so he kept the body and the murder weapon in the wall.
Also, because it's windy at night,
he made it a so-called haunted house.
A witch doctor's business is related to ghosts and spirits anyway.
His living in a haunted house makes sense to common civilians.
The civilians fear but won't doubt it.
But Sir Witch Doctor never mentioned that he had enemies.
We never saw anyone come to seek revenge on him.
Should we go to law enforcement?
I'm a law enforcer.
Since the dead was a eunuch,
the imperial palace needs to investigate it.
Listen up, the three of you.
Without my permission, none of you is allowed
to tell anyone about what happened tonight.
Especially you.
- It's late.
- Let's go.
Collect the evidence and take it back.
Father.
Chu Chu, where were you in the middle of the night?
I went to get some wine, you were all gone when I came back.
I wanted to go out to find you.
I'm a bad drinker, I wanted some fresh air,
so I asked them out for a walk with me.
For causing you worry,
it was inconsiderate of me.
No, no. I'm glad you're okay.
Where is Chu He and the general?
My brother took General Xiao for a walk at the back.
They'll be back soon.
They didn't go to the hill, did they?
It's been raining on and off these days, they mustn't go to the hill.
No, they haven't. Father, don't worry.
They'll be back soon.
Well, is the table cleaned up?
Not yet.
Let's go clean up the table and go to bed afterward.
Please rest early.
- Your Highness.
- Follow me.
Yes.
Quickly, this way.
Put him in it.
The coffin hasn't been here for years.
No one claims it.
You keep on the watch here.
Yes.
[Archive]
Chu He,
where were you and General Xiao in the middle of the night?
Father, do you remember the wall
that you helped the witch doctor build in the summer?
Yes.
He said the walls were too old
and that he was afraid that they'd collapse in the rainy season.
I heightened and thickened the walls in accordance with his requirements.
Why are you asking me this?
Father, Sir Witch Doctor killed someone,
and hid the body in the wall.
What?
The officer in charge of criminal cases from Chang'an found it out.
I thought he was a phony, so I wanted to humble him
with the haunted house, but he actually figured it out.
The ghost is in the wall.
The officer also said that it mustn't be leaked
and that the leaker would be punished.
Why are you telling me this, then?
You serve in the Yamen, how can you make this mistake?
Because I haven't been clear about his true identity.
What if he's fooling around with us?
If Lord Zheng knows and blames it on us, what do we do, then?
We're the coroners of Guanling County.
It isn't a small thing. Don't mess around.
I'll pry for information from the Yamen tomorrow.
Let's find out who the officer is first.
It doesn't matter if he's from Chang'an
or he's in charge of criminal cases,
he's the real deal.
I feel like he's insightful.
He can't stay in our house for long.
Is he suspicious of Chu Chu?
I don't know.
But she told me that the officer would
personally investigate her identity.
If he found it out, Chu Chu's life would be over.
How about this?
I'll take her away.
Nonsense. Where are you taking her to?
If you take her away now,
you're telling him that there's something wrong with Chu Chu.
I'll break your leg if you mess around.
Go to work.
Now.
Your Highness. General Xiao.
My house can't compete with those in Chang'an,
but all the bedding is new, and the table and chairs are cleaned up.
Don't worry, they're all clean.
Brother, I'd like to speak to Chu Chu in private.
I'll excuse myself, then.
Your Highness, your brother is so nice.
He listens to everything that you say.
He thinks everything that you do is right.
No, he doesn't take orders from me,
I've just been spoiled by him since I was little.
My brother spoils me, too.
But he thinks everything that I say is nonsense
and everything that I do is messing-around.
The witch doctor encouraged you, didn't he?
Why do you bring him up again?
Are you going to ask more questions about the case?
Chu Chu, what we discovered tonight matters a lot.
It's come this far, won't you tell me the truth?
Your Highness, you have questions about Sir Witch Doctor. Right?
I've told you the truth.
Sir Witch Doctor is a good man.
I really don't know where he is right now.
You know I'm not talking about that.
Your pendant was handmade by my father.
The pendants are the tokens of love between my father and mother.
This is my mother's.
It pairs with the one in your hand.
When I first saw the pendant,
I knew that you had clues about my father.
This is the only lead for me to find him.
Chu Chu, can you tell me where you got the pendant?
So it is the pendant that you care about.
Your Highness, there has never been a second test. Right?
You never wanted to hire me.
You kept me at your side because
you were investigating the pendant. Right?
You never thought of me as the best coroner.
The purpose of your praises and compliments is this pendant, right?
Chu Chu.
You can seize and interrogate me.
Don't coax me like this.
No.
What's wrong, Jinyu?
Let's count the days.
It was four years after the rebellion of the Military Commissioner of Jiannan
that the eunuch showed up.
What happened back then couldn't be that simple.
Our father didn't return to the capital city,
didn't contact Chang'an,
didn't contact the imperial garrison in the southwest.
This matter must be one of the reasons.
I know that.
I mean...
What's wrong with Miss Chu?
Up all night? What have you been doing?
Looking for the tomb of Chu Chu's biological mother.
Looking for the tomb?
Both His Highness and I think
that the tomb of Chu Chu's biological mother
is among the tombs that the Chu family often pays respects to.
But the Chu family pays respects to
every dead one that they examined or encoffined.
All my night has been spent on that.
Have you found anything?
No.
Eat something first, then.
You drank so much last night, you should eat something for breakfast.
What are these? Are these just for me?
What's your problem?
Are you going to eat them or what?
I'll take them away.
I will.
Your Highness says you aren't allowed to eat while reviewing the case records.
Are you challenging me?
Fine. I'll go tell His Highness.
[January 9, the tenth year of Taihe reign]
Wait.
No.
Out of my way!
Greetings, Your Grace.
What are you doing here?
Your Grace,
His Majesty knows it's the anniversary of the Prince Consort's death
and ordered me to pay respects.
- Ma, put the offerings on the table.
- Yes.
Who dares to take a step further!
Your Grace, years have passed.
Are you still holding a grudge
because I didn't take the Prince Consort back?
Grudge?
Eunuch Qin, stop thinking highly of yourself.
You don't deserve my grudge.
How magnanimous of you.
Had I done a good job at the time,
Commandery Prince An wouldn't need to go to the southwest,
where rebellions often break out.
Commandery Prince An travels lightly.
I've been worrying about him.
Listen!  If you dare touch my son,
I'll make sure you die horribly.
You see!  You see!  What are you talking about, Your Grace?
I spend all my time serving His Majesty in the palace.
How is it possible for me to touch Commandery Prince An?
- Nonsense!
- What's wrong?
Hasn't Commandery Prince An
sent his regards to you after he left the capital city for a month?
Eunuch Qin.
Your Grace.
Lord Xue.
What? Are you here to pay respects to the Prince Consort as well?
I'm here on behalf of His Majesty.
However, Her Grace doesn't seem to appreciate His Majesty's concerns.
How strange.
I, too, was ordered to pay respects on behalf of His Majesty.
He ordered me to take four fruits of the season
to put before the memorial tablet.
Since His Majesty has ordered you here,
why did he ask me to do the same?
Uh, uh... I guess His Majesty must have forgotten that he sent me.
Since you reject his goodwill,
I'll have to go back and tell His Majesty so.
Farewell.  Goodbye.
Come. Back to the palace.
Duke Qin, walk carefully.
Lord Xue.
Congratulations on your promotion to War Minister.
You won't have to speak behind the folding screen
in Jiangshan Hall.
Congratulations. Congratulations.
Let's go.
Quickly.
Your Grace, His Majesty asked me to bring these.
I thank His Majesty's concerns.
I haven't congratulated you
on your promotion yet.
Don't tease me, Your Grace.
I'm incompetent.
I undertake the responsibility with great humility.
I fear that I might not live up to His Majesty's trust.
Senior Jing said a long time ago that you were a man of great talent.
You don't pursue fame, but have greatness in your heart.
You will be given a peerage in no time.
You speak to highly of me, Your Grace.
- Master, you're back.
- Shut up!
What happened...?
Bastard! Bastard!
You... Why do you bring the food for the dead into the room?!
Toss it out to feed the dog! Feed the dogs!
Idiots!
- Out! Out! Quickly!
- Yes, yes!
Out!
Master, did the widow upset you again?
Calm down. Watch your health.
Xue Rucheng has Jing Zhi and the Xiaos backing him up.
He becomes arrogant right after being promoted to Minister of War by throwing my surname at me.
Who does he think he is?
A poor and pedantic scholar who crawled into the imperial palace
dares to mess with me?
A disgrace! A disgrace!
Master, calm down.
Even if he's in charge of ten ministries,
he's still a pathetic scholar.
If he disgusts you, just say the word,
I'll find someone and make sure he disappears before tomorrow sunrise.
You...
You promised me the disappearance of many people!
Answer me!  It's been so long,
what has Xu Rugui accomplished?
Where's the head of Xiao Jinyu?
What about the female coroner?
Master, when Xu Rugui ambushed Xiao Jinyu in Qianzhou,
Xiao Jinyu happened to lead the Qianzhou garrison there.
The ambush failed and Xu Rugui lost half of his men.
He's useless!
Master, please don't be mad.
Xu Rugui has now made a new ambush plan, which is a guarantee to success.
When the good news comes back, you'll be the first to know.
You know what? It feels quite strange.
The wood itself isn't scary, but once it's made into a coffin,
it becomes pretty creepy.
When the arms and legs are on a human, they aren't creepy.
When they're amputated, they become creepy.
You shouldn't say this around all these coffins.
The good thing is, the coffins are all empty.
Who says they are all empty?
This one isn't.
Don't try to scare me.
No coffin-maker would use a dead body to try a coffin out.
From my years of experience,
the coffin must have been used as a storage box.
Don't believe me? Let's have a look.
What is it? So well covered.
Don't touch it!
Stop howling.
You've seen corpses before.
What's wrong with those Chu people?
Why did you put a dead body in it?
Where should a dead body be if it isn't in a coffin?
Watch your hand!
The Chu family didn't put it in the coffin, I did.
You did?
This is an important piece of evidence.
You must figure a way to bring it back to the Yamen later.
Speak. What's the matter?
I got Chu Chu's background.
What?
This is what I found yesterday in the archive.
A suicide case in a large family.
The dead was the younger sister of the master of the Xu family
in Guanling County, who had been married.
His sister came to Guanling County, seeking refuge under him for some reason.
The brother and sister had a fight and she then committed suicide.
Why does it have anything to do with Chu Chu?
Check the date.
[January 9, the tenth year of Taihe reign]
January 9?
[January 9]
The case record says, Chu Ping collected Mrs. Xu's body.
He buried her on that very night.
So,
Chu Ping took a body on Chu Chu's birthday.
Yes. In my opinion,
Chu Chu is the abandoned baby that Chu Ping took in when he buried Mrs. Xu.
Abandoned baby?
Your Highness, abandoned babies are common in the southwest.
The land is barren in the southwest, and natural disasters often happen.
When life becomes too difficult,
a family throws away the youngest kid.
Especially girls.
They are often dumped in graveyards and let fate make the decision.
If a kind-hearted visitor sees the baby,
they may take her home and raise her.
If not, she's just another dead body in the graveyard.
Mrs. Xu should have been pregnant when she killed herself.
Yes.
I wonder how serious the fight between them was?
Why would a pregnant woman kill herself by desperately hitting her head on the wall?
Two lives!
How come the record is so brief?
What was Mrs. Xu's full name? Who was her husband?
What did she and her brother fight about?
None of these is recorded when it got archived.
Last night, Zheng Youde told me that the archive had a fire.
The old records were all burned down.
These were re-recorded after the fire.
Does the Chu family pay respects to Mrs. Xu?
Yes.
The Chu family pays respects to anyone that they encoffined or examined.
Mrs. Xu was one of them.
Are you trying to...
You go back to the Yamen.
She's rude.
Excuse me.
I'd like to ask you some questions.
Come in, please.
Mr. Chu,
this is the case record that I asked my man to find in the Yamen.
The record says you took care of the dead body in this case.
Please have a look. Any impression?
[Mrs. Xu...]
So?
Yes.
The record is too brief.
Please recall the details of that day for me.
According to the case record,
Mrs. Xu had been pregnant when she hit the wall to kill herself.
Since you took care of her body, you should know
how far along she was.
Over eight months.
Nearly nine months.
- So she was near the time of labor.
- Yes.
Why do you ask this?
She's been dead for many years.
Chu He.
Yes, Mrs. Xu has been dead for many years,
what about the baby in her?
To be honest, when I first met Chu Chu in Chang'an,
I admired her skills and wished to hire her,
so I asked my men to investigate her background.
I didn't understand what her birth was,
so that the family that raised her would rather let her be slandered
by a bastard than defend her with the truth.
Now that I've seen the case record,
I finally understand the sad story behind it.
Chu Chu isn't a bastard,
nor is she an abandoned baby rescued in the graveyard.
She is the baby that you saved from Mrs. Xu's dead body.
The folks call them...
coffin babies.
Chu Chu.
Chu Chu, don't listen to him.
He's made it up. It's not true.
Chu Chu, follow me out.
Enough.
We've been hiding the truth from her, but we can't lie to her.
Chu Chu, you've grown up.
I need to tell you something.
My Lord, she isn't my son's biological daughter.
But my son saved her and brought her back.
Since she was brought into our family,
I saw her as my granddaughter.
Father, I did it.
Let me speak.
My Lord.
Father.
In the evening, January 9, an officer from the Yamen
asked me to collect a body from the Xu family.
The officer said the county magistrate had known her cause of death
and that I didn't need to conduct an autopsy.
[Xu Family]
Mr. Xu's sister killed herself by hitting her head against the wall.
It was still the new year period, the Xu family thought it was ominous
and paid me to take away the body.
I didn't think too much
because Mrs. Xu did have an obvious bruise on her forehead.
The Xu family was cold-hearted, they just rolled her body in a straw mat.
I thought it was heartless, so I wanted to get her a proper coffin.
But something unexpected happened...
What's the matter?
Why are you holding a baby?
Father, look.
Father, she just died.
She was about to give birth.
I thought this baby...
I thought this baby could be saved, so I gave it a try.
And I did save her life.
It's a she.
Her life is strong.
I'm sure she'll have good fortune.
Who was she?
Mr. Xu Zongfang's sister.
I heard that her husband's entire family was disastrously killed.
So she went to seek refuge under her brother.
But she wasn't welcomed by her brother and his wife.
The butler paid me twenty coppers to take the body away
and bury her at a random spot.
How about I send them a message and ask them to take the baby home?
What message? Take her home?
A dead woman gave birth to a baby in the coffin room in a coroner's house,
who would take the baby?
Yeah, yeah, yeah. You're right.
It's January 9, Father. It's the Jade Emperor's birthday.
The baby has survived.
Maybe she has God's blessing.
How about we keep her in our home, and after the Lantern Festival,
when the new year is over, I'll speak to the Xu family.
After all, she's a half Xu.
Also, the Xu family is rich, They have enough food.
They can raise the baby.
She's a poor soul.
All right, all right.
We buried Mrs. Xu's body and after the Lantern Festival,
I visited the Xu family.
I then knew that the entire family had escaped from trouble.
I didn't want the baby to be involved.
I didn't know what trouble they got themselves into,
but even Mr. Xu had to escape from it,
a newborn baby surely needed to be kept away from it.
So I didn't tell anyone about her.
After all, the baby did nothing wrong.
So I brought her up as my own daughter.
I've heard all kinds of rumors.
Some say she's a bastard that my mistress and I had.
Some say I picked her up in the graveyard.
But like you said, My Lord, it's better than letting people
know a dead woman gave birth to her, a coffin baby.
My Lord, Mrs. Xu is dead.
She doesn't exist in this world anymore.
Chu Chu was born after her death.
She shouldn't take the blame.
- My Lord.
- Sir, please don't.
If you convict us of hiding the truth, we plead guilty.
But Chu Chu has nothing to do with what that Xu family had done.
Don't blame anything on Chu Chu.
The pendant. He's after the pendant.
The Chu family did nothing.
It's my fault. Don't punish them.
You investigated my background and want to punish the Chu family
because you want to know more about the pendant.
Whatever you want to know, ask me.
But please, don't punish the Chu family.
- Please!
- Is this your trust in me?
- Is this how you trust me?!
Timing and subtitles brought to you by The Imperial Coroners @ Viki.com
♫  Nothing can stop me  ♫
♫  From missing you all the time  ♫
♫  The moonlight appears, cold in the late night,
as the world changes  ♫
♫  Only with you by my side can I embrace my yearning for you  ♫
♫  When I close my eyes I meet you once again  ♫
♫  I'll gently brush your hair by your ear  ♫
♫  Life is long, with love and regrets in this world  ♫
♫  With you by my side, no matter how far I go,
we'll never be apart  ♫
♫  With your smile, in this moment, let me
cherish this lifetime  ♫
♫  Only for you, I have to worry about the end of this life  ♫
♫  I’m still young, with my love not yet realized for you, but I'm
willing to be here for you till the end
♫  You can rely on me in this lifetime  ♫
♫  Hope to spend this beautiful lifetime together  ♫