Timing and subtitles brought to you by The Imperial Coroners @ Viki.com
I shouldn't have trusted Jing Yi.
Now Chu Chu must think that I see her as...
To feed pigs?
[Lespedeza Used to feed pigs]
The wounds on Prefect Li's hands
fit these tools perfectly in terms of shape and size.
It's you who made the coin molds!
The mold is consumable.
It needs to be replaced every once in a while.
You are afraid to be found out if you make it in your mansion.
So you came here to make the mold every once in a while.
As a prefect, you've put a lot of effort into this.
Commandery Prince An, now that you know it,
you can die without regret.
[The Imperial Coroner]
[Episode 25]
Get him!
Chu Chu!
Jinyu!
Jinyu! Jinyu!
Let's go!
Hurry up!
Your Highness, are you okay?
I'm fine. Did you get hurt?
General, I'm afraid it will take a few hours to clear a way out.
It's humid inside the cave.
The gunpowder wouldn't work due to dampness if it was installed a long time ago.
It must have been installed recently.
There is no trace of movement in front of the kiln.
There must be another entrance.
You guys clean up the stones.
The rest of you come with me.
Yes!
- This way!
- Hurry up!
Commandery Prince An, I respect you as a noble official extolled by people.
I wanted to get you decently buried under the rocks and give you a quick death.
But you don't appreciate it.
All right, I'll finish your life in person.
- Don't come over!
- Go away!
Are you all right?
Go away!
- Go!
- Your Highness, what's wrong with you?
Go away!
Your Highness!
Your Highness, wake up.
Wake up.
Your Highness.
Get up.
Are you feeling better?
Don't be afraid, I'll find the way out.
I will take you out.
Are you bleeding?
Don't move. Let me take a look.
It's okay, it's just a graze.
Your bones are fine.
Let me help you up.
Come on.
Be careful.
You really scared me.
Do you have a headache?
Are you dizzy?
I'm fine.
It's my fault.
I didn't grab Li Zhang and got you hurt.
Chu Chu, I know you have feelings for me.
Why won't you...?
Your Highness, I'm a coroner.
So what?
You don't understand it.
I don't understand it.
Please tell me.
I don't want to die here without knowing the reason.
I grew up being despised.
They said coroners fiddle with dead people
and they are dirty, smelly, and unlucky.
No one wanted to be my friend.
Even the shop that sells things
wouldn't allow me in when there were many customers.
Everything I touched was called dirty by them.
Now that I've decided to be a coroner,
I'm ready to endure this all my life.
But you are different.
[The Three Judicial Offices]
You are the best judge in the world.
♫ Stay with each other gently ♫
You've been the nicest person to me
in the world except my family.
Your Highness, you not only gave me a chance to work as a female coroner,
you also care about me and protect me all the time.
Chu Chu!
You are perfect.
I'm willing to work for you as your coroner for the rest of my life.
But if you marry me, you will be humiliated and despised
because of me.
I don't want you to get hurt.
♫ Let time pass by ♫
♫ I'm still in love with you ♫
Chu Chu, we might not be able to get out today.
No one is judging us now.
Just forget about those things first.
I only want to ask you,
do you have feelings for me?
You are the only one I have feelings for.
♫ If you walk into the rest of my life ♫
From this moment,
no matter how long we are going to live,
no matter what we are going to face,
- will you always be with me?
- Yes, I will.
♫ Spend our lives through time ♫
Your Highness, we are going to die.
How can you still talk about this now?
Who said we are going to die?
I said maybe.
Your Highness.
You have the courage to face death with me.
Are you still afraid of the gossip?
Chu Chu, you are a coroner.
You should know better than anyone how long one is going to live.
Maybe there will be decades. Maybe the end is the next moment.
If you force yourself to give up the love of your life just for some insignificant comments,
regret will be all you have when death comes.
I won't give you up for that.
And also, I ask you not to give me up.
Sorry. Your Highness, I was wrong.
All right, let's go and check Li Zhang
lest he should wake up and we will be in trouble.
Let's go.
Is he still alive?
Yes.
Your Highness, do you want to kill him?
What are you thinking about?
I have a lot of questions to ask him.
Even if he wants to die, I won't let him die now.
General Xiao! There is an entrance here.
Let's go.
Xiao Jinli!
Jinli!
Why are you two here?
- We heard the explosion coming from this direction. We followed the sound here.
- Where's Commandery Prince An?
That treacherous Li Zhang placed gunpowder in the cave. They are trapped inside.
What? They are trapped inside?
What about Li Zhang? Is he also trapped inside?
They are all inside. The front entrance has been blocked by falling rocks.
We need to find another entrance now and rescue them.
Neither of them knows how to fight. I don't know how long they can hang in there.
I just saw some ruts on the ground.
This should be the way they used to send things in and out.
We should be able to find them soon following these traces.
Qianzhou's cave is complicated.
Adjacent caves are often connected to each other.
This should be the other entrance.
Let's go inside.
All right. I'm finished.
The way you tied him is different from how the prisoners are tied.
I seem to have seen it before.
- Your Highness, have you seen people selling live pigs at the market?
- Selling pigs?
Yeah. This is how pigs are tied.
This is called a trotter knot.
He can't break loose no matter how hard he unties.
The knot will only get tighter.
It's also easy to get him out of here after we find the exit.
We only need a shoulder pole and get two people to carry him down the mountain.
You are thoughtful indeed.
Let's go to find the exit.
Your Highness, can we find the exit?
Yes. I have never seen a cave like this,
but I have seen a lot of people like Li Zhang.
He came here at the last minute must be because there is a way out.
I acted on impulse and beat him too hard.
I'm afraid he won't wake up for a while.
Otherwise, we can ask him.
He can't be trusted even he told us.
It's more convenient for us to find the exit on our own
than asking him to lead the way.
If he can take you out, I can also take you out.
There is a cart!
It's gunpowder.
Looks like they used this
to transport the gunpowder to the cave over there.
Then they would hide and wait for us to come.
So they can attack us.
Damn Li Zhang.
He used his little brain to do these utterly conscienceless things.
This is easy now.
If he used this cart to transport the gunpowder,
we only need to follow the ruts, and then we can find them. Right?
Do you think they are stupid?
The ruts at the entrance have been cleared.
What if they faked the ruts on purpose to lead us to a dangerous place?
We have to find them even it's dangerous!
Those who are afraid should get out of here now.
Don't be garrulous and disturb us.
Xiao Jinli, who are you talking about?
Who do you think I'm talking about?
- You...!
- Xiao Jinli.
Leng Yue is just analyzing the situation.
She is not wrong. What are you doing?
And you. You can only talk and make trouble for us.
Xiao Jinli, are you a dog? Don't bite everyone you see.
- I'll just bite you. So what?
- Go ahead and bite me!
All right, stop fighting.
We are all here for Commandery Prince An and Chu Chu.
- Confucius said...
- Let's go.
What did I tell you?
He's bad-tempered.
He would become like a nut when it's about his brother.
All right. Don't let him get to you.
Confucius is right about this. He said...
Saint Confucius is the best weapon to deal with fighters.
Wait for me!
You are not afraid of dead people, but you are afraid of mice.
Dead people won't come out of nowhere suddenly.
It's showing us the way.
You just yelled out and scared it into the hole.
Yeah, I remember it.
Snakes, insects, rats, and ants know where the exit is.
Let's go.
General Xiao! There are wagon tracks.
It should be in this way.
This way.
Let's go.
Leng Yue, why should we go this way?
There are no ruts here,
but there are traces this way that has been swept by branches.
Only one would come here
to sweep the road unless they have other intentions.
Your Highness, hold on.
What's wrong?
There seems to be wind here.
Wind?
Yes, usually the place with the wind is the place with the exit.
What's wrong?
Are you not asking me to hug you?
I'm trying to tell the wind direction.
What are you doing behind me?
I just want to know what you are doing.
I'm trying to tell the wind direction.
Wind direction?
Heat your hands and spread your arms.
The hand that cools quickly shows the wind direction.
The entrance is blocked, but it's still ventilated.
There must be a way to the entrance.
This way.
There is the sound of running water here.
- What's wrong?
- Normally, the closer we are to the exit, it should be windier
and less humid.
The stone wall should be drier.
But on the way here, the stone wall is still very humid.
It doesn't seem to be changing.
Maybe it's because of the rainy days recently.
Your Highness, look.
There is water on the ground.
Chu Chu, does the Yong'an River run under here?
Yes.
No wonder the stone wall is always damp.
The explosion just now should have shattered the rocks.
This river is about to seep in.
It's gunpowder.
This should be the way Li Zhang took to bring gunpowder in.
We are in the right direction.
There must be an exit in front.
Chu Chu, we should hurry up.
Your Highness, it's Miss Leng. They came to find us.
Jinyu!
Your Highness! Chu Chu!
Your Highness, are you okay?
Jinli!
We need to save them now.
This bridge must have been broken by the falling rocks.
We need to get them here now.
Jing Yi, can you fly over there?
I can fly over there by myself.
But I'm afraid I can't bring them back.
I'll ask them to build a bridge with boards now!
That would be too late. The water is rising under the rocks.
- This place will collapse soon. It's too late.
- What should we do then?
Jinli, do you have any rope?
- Rope?
- Yes!
- Use the rope as a bridge!
- Bridge?
- Did you forget the bridge of rope in Guanling County?
- Yeah, you are right.
- Hurry up and get the rope! Hurry up!
- Yes!
Your Highness, take this.
Your Highness, let's go.
Chu Chu, hold me tight.
Chu Chu!
- Jinyu!
- Chu Chu!
Chu Chu...
How should we do?
Chu Chu.
- Are you okay?
- I'm fine.
- Are you okay, Jinyu?
- Are you all right?
- Jinyu, are you all right?
It's collapsing here. Let's go now.
Come on.
Hurry!
What's wrong? Are you okay?
I'm fine.
Chu Chu.
[Dislocated arm]
I'm fine.
That bastard Li Zhang, I'm going to...
By the way, where's Li Zhang?
We tied him up. He is in the cave on the other side of the kiln.
I don't know how he is doing now.
Jinli, please get some people to clean the entrance of the kiln and get Li Zhang out.
What? Get him out?
I can't wait to skin him alive!
Even you want to skin him alive, you still need to get him out first.
Li Zhang is an important witness.
And he is a small potato.
Considering what happened today, he failed it
and the person behind him won't let us go easily.
If we don't find out the person behind Li Zhang,
we will have more dangerous situations.
All right, I'll listen to you.
You guys escort Commandery Prince An and them back.
The rest of you come with me!
- Yes!
Let's go.
Didn't you go to the mountain?
Grandpa, it was my fault. I slipped
and dragged Commandery Prince An into a cave.
Are you all right?
I'm fine, Grandpa.
Wait, what's wrong with your arm?
It's nothing. I just strained it.
Strained it?
Let me see.
It doesn't matter.
You can't even move your arm.
Don't you know how serious it is?
If you don't get treatment in time and let the wind into your bones,
you will lose your arm.
Chu Chu, go and make some hot water. I'll take care of it.
Okay, I'm going.
Come on.
Okay.
Our families are coroners.
We often pull our muscles and hurt our bones when we carry stuff.
No one can treat this injury better than I can in Guanling County.
Bear with it later.
You can shout out if it hurts.
You can even cry. No one will laugh at you.
Yes.
But don't move.
Chu Chu, hold him up.
Don't let him move.
Grandpa, do it gently.
How is it?
It doesn't seem to hurt anymore.
You look gentle and weak.
But you can endure some pain.
Thanks to your excellent medical skills. It doesn't hurt anymore.
All right, take some rest here for a few days. Don't use your arm.
You need to apply ointment for some days.
Get some rest. I'll go and get the medicine for you.
Thank you, Sir.
What's wrong?
It really doesn't hurt.
Don't lie to me. I'm a coroner.
What kind of injury you got, how you got hurt, I knew it at a glance.
I know how painful this is.
You got hurt because of me.
If I make you feel guilty for saving you, I would regret saving you.
Your Highness, your life is precious.
- It's not worth it to get hurt for me...
- There is only one you in the world.
If you die, I might not be able to find another good coroner like you,
but I can't find another you.
It's worth it anyway.
Your Highness.
All right, it's okay.
- Father, what are you doing here?
- Hush.
You know what, Commandery Prince An is sincere to Chu Chu.
Of course he is.
How can you eavesdrop on them at your age?
You little bastard.
Vice Minister Jing, you are back. Where's Commandery Prince An?
He is busy now. He will come back later.
How is it going with the tree hole?
Vice Minister Jing,
I took care of the tree hole as you ordered.
Then I came back to the County Office.
Vice Minister Jing, forgive me for asking this.
What did you do with Miss Leng?
I don't mean anything else.
I'm just worried about you.
I heard a loud bang from the mountain.
Should I send some people to take a look there
lest any villagers get hurt?
That's what you are talking about. It's fine.
A cave collapsed. No villager got hurt.
But Prefect Li got trapped inside accidentally.
Prefect Li is trapped in the cave?
Magistrate Zheng, don't worry. General Xiao went to save him.
You don't need to send anyone over there.
Just stay in the County Office and take care of the affairs here.
Yes. Yes.
I see.
He asked for the trouble himself.
He won't blame you.
By the way, where is Deputy Magistrate Tan?
Vice Minister Jing.
Deputy Magistrate Tan had asked for leave for a funeral service days ago.
He hasn't come to the County Office.
Do you have any instructions?
Nothing. I'm just asking it.
You've worked hard these days. Go and rest early.
Don't say that. It's my job.
How can you not tell me that you got hurt?
I'll tell General Xiao about it later and let him discipline you.
Chu Chu, never let my brother know this.
Then you need to promise me
that you will let me apply ointment for you on time,
and you will take medicine on time and rest on time.
You can't use any excuses to refuse it to delay it.
Okay, I promise you.
You must recover before you return to Chang'an.
Otherwise, when you get back to Chang'an and let your mother know it, she will be really worried.
I'll go to get more ointment from Grandpa later.
It's a long way to Chang'an. I should bring enough ointment.
Chu Chu, I'm afraid we can't go back to Chang'an for now.
Not going back to Chang'an?
But we have found out that Prefect Li is the one who was minting coins illegally.
Is there anyone else we need to arrest?
This group of people had a comprehensive plan to mint coins.
They hid it from the government for five years.
It can be seen that how cautious and composed the mastermind is.
But today, Li Zhang led us to the mint
and tried to bury us alive in the cave.
This is a hasty plan.
He acted so hastily.
It can be seen that we are very close to the truth.
Close to the truth?
Isn't Prefect Li the mastermind of this case?
Li Zhang is just a pawn.
For the real mastermind, it's good if his cave plan works out.
If not, he would be the scapegoat for closing the case.
Your Highness, you used to say these things to Vice Minister Jing.
Why are you telling me this today?
I used to think these disputes and conspiracies in court had nothing to do with you.
I didn't want to disturb your simple and happy mind.
But now you are already in this.
I have to tell you.
I will learn well.
I'm not asking you to learn it.
I tell you this now because I want you to be more cautious
and you will be safer.
This person who is causing waves in Qianzhou
won't stay put for too long.
Prefect Li is a high-ranking official but he is still not the mastermind.
Who can be the mastermind?
[Leng Peishan, Military Commissioner of Qianzhongdao]
Say it.
[Hou Bin, Deputy Military Commissioner Zhao Jie, Military Ambassador]
General Leng.
Since you received a letter from Miss Leng the day before yesterday, you've had so much on your mind.
What happened? Let us share the worries for you.
Yes, just make an order if you need us to do anything.
We will shrink from no sacrifice.
Yeah, shrink from no sacrifice!
This is the first letter she has ever written to me.
Is Miss Leng in trouble or in danger?
She wrote that she is doing well
and asked me
if I am doing well.
With her temperament...
it's very uncommon for her to write
such a common letter.
General Leng, could it be that Commandery Prince An knows our plan?
No way.
When Xiao Jinli was in the army,
he praised his little brother countless times.
He is basically a legend.
Not to mention he is in Qianzhou now.
Even if he is thousands of miles away,
it's not impossible for him to sense our affairs.
That's true.
Where's Xiao Jinli? Is he not back yet?
He took a group of people to move away the stones all night.
Li Zhang is troublesome indeed.
I hope Jinli can arrest him soon.
Then we can leave this poor place earlier.
There are the same few dishes every day and night.
I miss the food in Rugui House.
No matter how bad Li Zhang is, he still did us a favor.
Did us a favor?
Didn't you find out
that Chu Chu and Commandery Prince An are totally different
after they came out of the cave?
It means they must have solved all the problems that need to be solved.
We will be free if they are okay.
We should thank Li Zhang for that.
You have a point.
How about this? If Li Zhang gets out alive,
I'll treat him to his first meal.
Count me in.
It's the same.
What's our relationship? My treat is your treat.
What's our relationship?
We are...
We are sisters.
- Your Highness.
- Have you had breakfast? Should I get you a bowl and chopsticks?
- No need.
His Highness must have been fed by Chu Chu before he came out.
Your Highness.
Is Jinli back?
We were just talking about that.
If he doesn't come back later, I'm going to go to the mountain to check him.
This case is at a dead end now.
It's all right if Li Zhang is alive, but if he is dead,
when can we finish the investigation in Qianzhou
and go back to Chang'an to redress the old case?
Protect Lord!
Go!
Timing and subtitles brought to you by The Imperial Coroners @ Viki.com
♫  Nothing can stop me  ♫
♫  From missing you all the time  ♫
♫  The moonlight appears, cold in the late night,
as the world changes  ♫
♫  Only with you by my side can I embrace my yearning for you  ♫
♫  When I close my eyes I meet you once again  ♫
♫  I'll gently brush your hair by your ear  ♫
♫  Life is long, with love and regrets in this world  ♫
♫  With you by my side, no matter how far I go,
we'll never be apart  ♫
♫  With your smile, in this moment, let me
cherish this lifetime  ♫
♫  Only for you, I have to worry about the end of this life  ♫
♫  I’m still young, with my love not yet realized for you, but I'm
willing to be here for you till the end
♫  You can rely on me in this lifetime  ♫
♫  Hope to spend this beautiful lifetime together  ♫