Timing and subtitles brought to you by The Imperial Coroners @ Viki.com
Chu Chu went to the river and got the mirror back alone.
I knew she did it for me.
But nothing in this world could be more precious than her life.
I always put her in danger and make her sad.
How can I really be nice to her?
The light spots in the drawing
[Phoenix Mountain]
indicate the southwest of Phoenix Mountain.
Is there any shelter over there?
There?
There isn't any shelter. That's the wetlands.
There's a big swamp,
with many vipers and scorpions. It's a very dangerous place.
Few people go there.
If he went there, I'm afraid he could hardly survive.
No, no, no, Your Highness. I didn't mean that.
Sir Witch Doctor must be alive!
He's so smart.
He left such a complicated indication.
The danger in the swamp wasn't a big deal to him.
Maybe, he put something there and then moved to another place.
I mean it's hard to get there.
If we want to get there, we must be well prepared.
Your Highness, I...
I understand.
I'm sorry.
[The Imperial Coroner]
[Episode 21]
Flowers flourish in the imperial garden.
But I remember you don't like flowers, but cattails.
Flowers are beautiful but bloom only in certain seasons.
After waiting for a long season, people can only enjoy them for a few days.
Soon, they wither and fall, leaving nothing but memories.
Cattail is better.
It looks plain, but it blooms all year round.
It makes people feel relieved.
It doesn't sound like you.
Xiao Heng said that, didn't he?
He doesn't like flowers.
He likes rocks only.
I heard that your love token was a pair of rocks.
Yes.
In A Pair of Peacocks Southeast Fly,
"Like a rock, you should withstand all the blast.
I will be a willow twig so pliant.
That, thin like silk thread, remains tough.
A-clinging to the boulder giant."
Did you get your love token because of this poem?
It's made of rock?
Yes, rock.
Where did you get it?
I picked it near the pond in my house.
You're frank.
Do you still remember I'm a princess?
I don't even want jewels or jade.
How dare you give me a rock from your pond.
I know you like cattails, though flowers are beautiful.
Then I know I can't touch you with jewels, but with a rock.
You mean the poem A Pair of Peacocks Southeast Fly?
"Like a rock, you should withstand all the blast.
I will be a willow twig so pliant.
That, thin like silk thread, remains tough.
A-clinging to the boulder giant."
It's a good poem, but it doesn't mean good.
Do you compare us to the miserable couple in the poem?
I don't dare to. Please let me explain.
Look, Your Highness.
Cattail mostly grows near shoals,
where there're many rocks.
On sunny days, rocks and cattails stay with each other quietly.
On stormy days, rocks stabilize cattails to protect them from storms.
I don't want to be a jade pendant around your waist
as an ornament to your glory.
Instead, I want to be a rock, to always protect you.
I heard that you and your husband loved each other.
I didn't know you loved each other so much.
Don't tease me, Your Majesty.
It was Xiao Heng's duty to sacrifice everything for our nation.
My sons should do that, too.
It's tough for you, though.
Your Majesty, if you think I deserve some pity,
please show some mercy on Leng Yue.
Don't let her suffer the same as me.
Do you mean all the officials shouldn't get married or have descendants?
Xiping, I kindly make a match between Xiao Jinli and Leng Yue.
As a member of the imperial family,
you should understand what an honor it is!
Don't be ungrateful!
- Your Majesty...
- Say no more!
When's Xiao Jinli's birthday?
As his mother, you don't need to calculate it. Right?
Now that you fail to divine their birthdays for days,
let the imperial astronomer do it!
Yes, Your Majesty.
Jinbao,
did His Majesty only say that to Princess Xiping?
Yes. I don't dare to lie.
How easy it is to be an emperor in the flourishing age!
There's no domestic trouble or foreign invasion.
He even tries to be a matchmaker.
All right. Go take care of His Majesty.
Yes.
Master, His Majesty is quite odd lately.
Think about it.
Yesterday, he asked about the birthday of Xiao Jinli and Xiao Jinyu.
Today, he brought it up again to Princess Xiping.
He even pressed for detailed birthdates in public.
Did His Majesty also think of...?
What?
Master, don't you remember?
In old years when Princess Xiping gave birth to the boys,
people gossiped a lot.
Even if His Majesty was biding his time or ignoring everything,
he must have heard about it.
Now that you brought it up, ask your men to check on it.
By the way, Zhou Han was sent to ask about Duke Chang.
Why hasn't he gotten anything yet?
He just hasn't.
Chang'an isn't so big.
He should have even searched the entire city.
Why hasn't he got anything yet?
Master, think about it.
Zhou Han... It's hard to comment on him.
You have no idea what he always does with your award.
The other day, I heard that he visited Pingkang Residence every day.
He's very likely to enjoy himself there, in your name.
If your senior had come back after searching for Xiao Heng in the Southwest,
I needn't have used losers like Zhou Han!
Master, no offense,
but do you really think my senior ran away depending on his great martial arts
and has been enjoying his life, regardless of anything else?
You finally used your brain.
It must be more complicated.
Someone must be opposing me very secretly!
Master, could it be Xiao Heng?
Think about it.
We last heard about him when our men came back from Qianzhou
and told us they found his trace.
Over so many years, we haven't gotten any news about him anymore.
But if it's him, that's also weird.
He rejected the bright future we offered and abandoned his family.
What's he after?
It's what always worries me.
This is ridiculous.
Not to mention years, I can't stay here for even one single day.
At night, poison gas spreads, snakes and worms run about.
How could Prince Consort live in such a place?
Your Highness, are you fooling me?
Don't talk nonsense.
Deputy Magistrate Tan, I'm warning you.
If you keep talking nonsense, I'll ask General Xiao to shut your mouth with smelly socks.
I'll say no more.
You really have smelly socks?
Put them away. How insulting!
Soldiers like us want convenience first.
We don't bother about an insult.
Your Highness, walk ahead and we'll reach the swamp.
I guess it's where Sir Witch Doctor indicated.
Now that Father indicated this place,
he wouldn't try to get us killed.
But it's quite a big place without signs to show the way.
How can we find him?
[Phoenix Mountain | Swamp]
Chu Chu, what are you doing?
It's dangerous. Come down!
I'm exploring the way.
We can't explore the way in a swamp unless we climb high.
So many martial artists are here.
You don't need to climb high. Come down!
Yeah. I'm better at exploring the way in such a place.
Let me do it!
Look, Chu Chu. What's that?
Three piles of rocks, I think.
Were they here before?
It's also my first time coming here.
I haven't seen them before.
What are you talking about?
They don't look like nests of animals.
They look like...
Tombs?
Looks like someone piled the rocks deliberately.
Your Highness, these are rocks Sir Witch Doctor used to make chess pieces.
What's wrong, Your Highness?
Father...
He's in the swamp?
What? How could Father be in the swamp?
Light spots on the wall
lead to this place where there's a large swamp.
The chess game indicates
the exact location in the swamp.
Chess game?
Three piles of rocks represent three chess pieces.
[Rook | Knight]
[Elephant | Pawn]
The fourth chess piece...
[Pawn]
Prince Consort...
No way.
It's impossible!
He hid the corpse and left a chess game!
He took so much trouble to get us here!
He couldn't have...!
Your Highness, could Sir Witch Doctor have only left a clue in the swamp?
Just like the chess game.
It's a clue, leading us to another place.
Yes, you're right.
It must be a clue in the swamp.
- Vice General!
- Yes.
Take your men with me and find out the clue!
Yes.
You guys, come over!
Yes!
No.
There isn't another place.
Why?
I think Chu Chu makes sense.
If Prince Consort doesn't want to be easily found,
it's very possible that he left more clues, leading to many other places.
Like Tan Gui said,
poison gas spreads at night.
Snakes and worms run about.
It even took strong men like us half a day to walk here.
Father had difficulty moving about.
When he came all the way here, calibrated the location,
and piled the rocks, he couldn't leave before it got dark.
Couldn't he have come a few more times and did a bit of work every time
before it got dark?
He couldn't.
Now that he used such a complicated chess game
to hide the clues for this place, it means this place was crucial
and he didn't want others to notice.
If he came frequently, someone could have tracked him down.
Then his efforts on the chess game
would have been wasted.
- But...
- Leng Yue, let's check other places.
Why?
Come and you'll know.
Come on.
What exactly do you want?
His Highness is used to thinking of the worst.
But mostly, for the safety of his subordinates.
This time, he's looking for his father.
He wants a favorable turn more than anyone else.
Now that he came to the conclusion,
he must have weighed all possibilities in his heart.
As he was weighing the possibilities, his hope was gradually shattered,
just like being dismembered.
Do you know how miserable it was?
The more he explains, the more pain he has to experience.
If you trust him, ask no more.
All right.
I was impetuous just now.
What about Chu Chu?
She understands.
What she told His Highness that it was the clue in the swamp...
She didn't even believe that.
But she never lies to His Highness.
Everyone knows how to lie,
but they just don't want to or don't need to.
If Prince Consort really died, what will happen to Chu Chu?
Will your father let go of her?
Don't worry. When I'm around,
I won't let anyone from my family hurt Chu Chu.
Chu Chu…
Say no more, Your Highness.
I trust you. I know it.
I believe whatever you say.
Thank you.
Jinyu, is Father really in the swamp?
Yes.
He's waiting for the Handsome Judge.
After staying in the swamp alone
for five years, what does Father still have?
His skeleton, or even not a complete skeleton?
- Your Highness...
- Just tell me.
Could he…
not have even crushed bones?
No, I didn't mean that.
Your Highness, do you remember the corpse your father hid in the wall?
He would also have a corpse like that.
It's called wet corpse in our industry.
Wet corpse?
Fish, shrimp, and shellfish can hardly survive in a swamp.
Because the swamp is totally airtight,
corpses can be easily preserved.
They'll be preserved in a better way than your father used to store the eunuch.
Wrapped in waterproof oilcloth, a man would be in the swamp...
As if in a natural coffin.
General, we found him!
Jinyu, if Father arranged this,
how did he wrap himself?
How...? How come?
General Xiao, may I borrow a dagger?
I'm a coroner.
After getting on with Sir Witch Doctor for so many years,
I know how to recognize him.
Let me do it.
I can recognize him.
He... He's...?
You know him?
- Does he have a scald on his left arm?
- You...?
He gave you the pendant, didn't he?
The Handsome Judge let out a sigh of relief and felt ardent.
No matter how long or how deep one thing is hidden,
it always waits to be rediscovered.
It's him.
Considering his appearance,
his height, the wound on his leg,
and the scar on his arm.
Your Highness,
I'm finished.
How did he die?
There're many blood dots
[Facial vessels]
in the fundus of his eyes, corners of his eyes, his face, and neck.
His neck has obvious blood stasis.
[Blood dots on the neck]
He was suffocated to death.
[Blood vessel engorgement]
Do you mean he was alive before he was thrown into the swamp
and he was drowned by someone?
He drowned himself.
Why? Why did he do that?
The answer may be in the casket.
What... What do the numbers mean?
The numbers are in groups of three.
I think they're ciphers.
Ciphers?
Numbers or symbols are used to replace words.
If we want to understand the ciphers,
we must know in which way the numbers are translated into words.
Numbers are translated into words?
For example, one six three. There may be a book.
One represents the first article in this book.
Six represents the sixth line of this article.
Three represents the third word in the sixth line.
So, one six three leads to a certain word.
You mean if we want to understand this, we must find the book first?
Sort of.
But there isn't any book here.
We searched Sir Witch Doctor's house but found no book, either.
Could it be an article he wrote or his favorite book?
His favorite book is Intrigues of the Warring States.
I remember all his letters and articles.
It can't be any of them.
Wait.
It's not something related to him.
In the house he stayed in and on his corpse,
he left no clue about his real identity.
He knew that the one who solved the chess game and found his corpse
might not know his real identity.
The way to decode the ciphers has nothing to do with him.
But there's nothing more in the casket.
Wait a second.
There're words on the casket.
Yes. Let me have a look.
There're words on the cover, too.
Looks like a poem.
"Peach blossoms by the river.
A boy sits aside on the boat.
The lady picks..."
Picks...
I can't read this word.
Cress.
"The lady picks cress on the river.
Water ripples."
It's also a poem on the casket.
"Spring flowers wither and summer leaves grow.
The moon shines over the bridge.
I can't help thinking of the past.
Countless sorrow comes in clouds."
What... What's this?
"I'm so sad to leave.
Can't help missing you on rainy days."
What do the poems mean?
Are they the codebooks?
I have never heard of these two poems.
I think Prince Consort wrote them.
But they're mere doggerel.
Prince Consort shouldn't have written such poor poems.
Why do you think they're poor?
These words are difficult one after another.
Groups of three numbers for two poems.
How can we decode them?
Only about fifty words in two poems.
But there are more than a hundred numbers and ciphers.
Not to mention if the poems can be translated into another meaningful sentence,
even the numbers don't match.
Lord Jing, how does this word sound?
I didn't hear clearly.
Cress, sounds likes chess.
The same pronunciation?
The reverse phonetic notation!
The two poems weren't written for no reason.
In this first poem, there're 23 words.
All initial consonants are different.
Also, in the second poem, there're 36 words.
The compound vowels are different.
The numbers in groups of three represent a word from the first poem
and a tone from the second poem.
Then we can mark the pronunciation of each word
with the reverse phonetic notation.
I'm Censor Xiao Heng, working for Emperor Wenzong.
I'm leaving the cipher text, wishing a scholarly and brave man
to solve the puzzle of my haunted house, figure out the chess game,
and find where I drown myself, so that the grievance will be redressed
and loyal men in Jiannan can be vindicated.
In the ninth year of his reign,
Emperor Wenzong wanted to wipe out eunuchs.
With a secret imperial decree, I asked Military Commissioner Chen Ying
to go to Chang'an for coordination.
Chen Ying was about to leave.
Unexpectedly, Incident Ganlu failed.
Eunuchs controlled His Majesty and killed officials.
Loyal generals including Chen Ying were slandered as rebels.
At the behest of His Majesty,
Military Commissioner Chen Ying rebelled with his troops!
They'll be executed right here!
Go!
Kill!
- Chen Ying!
- Censor Xiao, leave!
We rely on you to vindicate us!
Leave the eunuchs to us!
Leave!
Xiao Heng ran away! After him!
I broke through, with the secret decree.
But I was encircled and badly wounded.
I had no choice, but to jump off the cliff.
Luckily, a witch doctor saved me.
I was in a coma for over a month.
When I woke up, I couldn't retrieve the situation.
Eunuchs faked an imperial edict and tried to lure me out
with a heroic title and the rank of nobility
so that they could kill me to destroy the evidence.
If I took one wrong step, I wouldn't have been able to vindicate the loyal generals,
and would also have implicated more innocent people.
In desperation, after the witch doctor died of disease,
I took over his job
and dwelled in Pingle Town, Guanling, for the future plan.
Luckily, the Chu family took care of me.
I never forgot my mission.
However, Guanling County has a difficult terrain.
One can't leave unless he uses a sliding rope.
Eunuchs never stopped searching for me in the Southwest.
My legs were broken and I could hardly walk.
Local officials kept killing subordinates
of Military Commissioner of Jiannan who escaped to this town.
I've never had a chance to contact people in Chang'an.
Later, a eunuch tracked me down alone.
I was lucky enough to kill him.
I hid his corpse and sword in the wall, as evidence.
Unfortunately, my health condition got worse and I was dying soon.
I didn't want to die, but this was all I could do.
♫ Where it starts and ends, play the role of myself ♫
I'm writing this letter and will drown myself in the swamp,
burying myself in nature and hoping that someone will vindicate me.
♫ What stays in my eyes is the galaxy ♫
♫ I don't want to tear it apart ♫
♫ In madness and obsession, you've become a skeleton ♫
♫ Make flesh and blood into shackles and become amber ♫
♫ Trapped in life, your soul is imprisoned ♫
♫ However hard I try, I can't restore your appearance ♫
♫ Lies are everywhere, there's light where the mist clears away ♫
♫ In the parallel world, everything you missed is happening ♫
♫ Its wry face appears and disappears  From time to time ♫
♫ Uncover the incomplete book
And restore real and fake fragments ♫
♫ Before it comes to an end, don't close the last page ♫
♫ In the parallel world, disconnected answers connect ♫
♫ A good show is on, it ends where it starts ♫
♫ I don't want to tear it apart ♫
♫ In madness and obsession, you've become a skeleton ♫
♫ Make flesh and blood into shackles and become amber ♫
♫ Trapped in life, your soul is imprisoned ♫