Timing and subtitles brought to you by The Imperial Coroners @ Viki.com
Chu Chu cleared her name of the daughter of a rebel.
The 20,000 loyal souls in Jiannan have been proved to be innocent.
[Go to Chang'an to suppress the bandits]
The vicious Qin Luan has been executed.
Xue Rucheng it's going to be our battle next.
[Leng Mansion]
You stand behind me in the middle of the night without saying a word.
Are you pretending to be a ghost?
Since you are here,
why don't you go in and take a look?
Don't you see the door locked?
We climbed the wall when we were four.
Now we have practiced martial arts
but you start to look for the key.
I just want to go in through the front door.
Why do you care?
Welcome Miss Leng back home.
How do you have the key to my house?
General Leng rewarded it to me.
I was going to clean it up first before bringing you here.
But it's all right you come here first.
See if there is anything you need and I will buy them for you.
This was my grandpa's mansion.
He gave it to my father.
I was born here.
After I moved to Princess Xiping's mansion,
Grandpa dismissed all his servants
and locked the mansion.
After that, he only lived in the hostel when he came back to meet His Majesty.
I thought he had sold the mansion.
I didn't expect this place to still remain the same.
I think he was afraid to come back,
to remind himself of my father
and the time when our families were living together.
General Leng told me that he left this mansion to you.
He hopes you can let him stay here
when he comes back to Chang'an next time.
He really wants to come back to his house.
He wants to see you when he comes back
and see that you are living a good life.
Jing Yi, thank you.
I just passed on a message for him.
You don't need to thank me.
When you two were talking, he must've made you drink a lot. Right?
It's no big deal to drink some white liquor for you.
I thought he was going to make me bleed.
Jing Yi, come here.
♫ Sing a song ♫
♫ Like the wind slightly plucking the strings ♫
♫ Happiness shows up slowly ♫
Don't run away!
I'm a pure young man!
You should be responsible for me!
Remember to propose marriage at my house tomorrow!
♫ Make a wish ♫
[The Imperial Coroner]
[Episode 35]
[Three Judicial Offices]
I have a solution.
Your Highness, let's get married.
What?
You said you would marry me.
Do you want to take back your words now?
No. Heaven knows that I want to marry you.
But why do you mention this suddenly?
I've thought about it. As long as we get married,
what has been troubling you will be solved then.
You are a relative of the emperor, a commandery prince, and a high-ranking official.
If you get married,
the royal family and other high-ranking officials
will all come to congratulate you.
The Three Judicial Offices will be crowded with visitors.
Then when those rebels come,
we can arrest them without attracting attention.
Chu Chu, I understand that you want to help me.
I also want to find a good way
to suppress those rebels who sneaked into Chang'an.
But I can't use our wedding as bait.
Why not?
Marrying you as my wife is the beginning of the rest of our lives together.
It's an extremely precious thing to me.
I should have spent more time with you to enjoy our love life.
But I was suspicious of you first,
then I got you involved in those dangerous cases
and put you in danger again and again.
You've suffered a lot.
I know you don't blame me.
But...
But that's because you are kind and generous.
I can't take that for granted.
I owe it to you.
If our wedding also becomes bait,
it will be unfair to you.
Your Highness, from what you said,
you mean my idea can work. Right?
That's great it can work.
Chu Chu!
Your Highness, I don't care about the wedding
as long as you are the groom.
I never felt it was unfair.
If marrying you can help you,
I'm willing to marry you once a day.
Besides, it's a great thing
if we can wipe out those rebels on our wedding day.
Think about it.
You are a judge in Tang. And I am a coroner.
If we can arrest those rebels on our wedding day,
that can be an auspicious sign.
It forebodes after we get married,
we can solve every case and win every battle.
But...
Your Highness, I can't bear to see you feel troubled.
So I'm willing to do it.
You want to use your wedding as bait to entrap Xue Rucheng?
Yes.
Since you proposed it to me,
you must have figured out how to do it.
You only asked me to grant you a marriage.
You haven't told me which girl you want to marry.
Do you want me to pick a random girl for you?
I dare not bother, Your Majesty.
I have someone I like.
You do?
That's strange.
Which girl?
I beg Your Majesty to allow me to marry Chu Chu,
the daughter of Yun Yi, the former Military Commissioner of Jiannan.
The daughter of Yun Yi?
The daughter of Yun Yi...
The female corner, Chu Chu, who you signed the certificate for in person?
Exactly.
Xiao Jinyu, you are telling me you want to marry a coroner as your wife?
Don't forget your identity.
I am Tang's official and Your Majesty's courtier.
Then forget about such a disgraceful thing!
Your Majesty, you once praised her
in the official document for helping me solve the case.
Now I want to marry a woman you appreciate,
why is it a disgraceful matter?
Can you marry all the women I appreciate?
One's capability and identity are two different things.
Don't try to resort to sophistry.
You are a first-rank commandery prince.
She's a coroner.
You two are living in different worlds!
Not to mention you want to marry her as your wife,
even if you want to take her as your concubine,
it's still against etiquette.
You are in charge of the Three Judicial Offices.
Do you need me to teach you etiquette?
Your Majesty.
Xiao Jinyu, don't tell me the nonsense that you are in love.
I've also been at your age.
A young man like you can only see the romance.
Do you know why marriage has always been an important thing since ancient times?
That's because after getting married,
you will share your joys and sorrows, glory and shame together.
You will sink or swim with her.
Have you ever thought about sharing weal or woe with a coroner?
Have you really thought it through for her?
With her status, how should she live with herself among those noble ladies?
Do you think our ancestors laid down etiquette just because of a momentary inspiration?
These are the lessons they learned and summarized after their painful experiences.
Since these lessons came from their experiences,
if I may be so bold as to ask Your Majesty,
did these people ever regret when they were suffering?
If they did, did they regret marrying the one they love
or failing to keep the promise and treat each other as before?
How dare you!
Your Majesty, since there are lessons from our predecessors,
I will remind myself all the time not to repeat their mistakes.
I hope you can allow me to marry her.
Well, Xiao Jinyu.
They all said you were young by prudence.
I didn't expect you to act like a child in this matter.
Never mind.
But I have a condition.
You should know it.
Your Majesty.
[Certificate of Coroner]
It was really hard for you to get the certificate issued by
the Ministry of Personnel and the Three Judicial Offices.
I know how important it is to you.
Therefore, Chu Chu, I can't marry you now.
Your Highness, you wanted to give up your title to be with me. Right?
If we want to arrest the rebels, we have to make sacrifices. Right?
Then, why can't it be me?
Everything you've got now is the result of your own efforts.
You put in a lot more effort than I did.
Don't worry. I can figure out another solution.
That will be too late.
- There is no better way than this.
- Chu Chu.
Your Highness, the identity of the coroner is important to me indeed.
I tried really hard to become a formal coroner
not because I want to hold the certificate in my hand,
but because I want to be like my grandfather, my father, my brother
and the constable in Prince Consort's story.
I want to be qualified to eradicate evil people and get justice done.
If giving up my identity as a coroner
can wipe out those rebels in one fell swoop and save the people in Tang,
then I would rather give it up.
Please allow me to do it.
Chu Chu is the descendant of a loyal general.
Your father had been trying to exonerate the Military Commissioner of Jiannan until his death.
You brought the evidence all the way back to Chang'an to reveal the truth.
In this way, you do have some sort of connection with the Yun family.
Marrying Yun Yi's daughter as your wife
can be a consolation to those loyal martyrs.
You deserve to be praised.
It does make a good story.
Xiao Jinyu, if you insist on marrying Chu Chu,
I can grant you two a marriage.
Thank you for your grace, Your Majesty!
It's rare for us to hang out together.
The sugar figure is the best in the Western market.
Let me buy one for you.
Sir, I'll have one.
Here. Take it.
Long live Duke Chang! Long live Duke Chang!
Jing Yi, look there.
We are from the Court of Judicial Review.
There are words on his clothes.
[Duke Chang retakes the stolen country]
Yeah.
It's a miracle!
What's written on it?
[Duke Chang retakes the stolen country]
It must be a miracle from Heaven.
Yeah. It's amazing. That's impressive.
How did Commandery Prince An know that there would be people playing tricks in a crowded place in Chang'an
and making these strange things related to Duke Chang?
Chen Sheng and Wu Guang hid a message in a fish at the end of the Qin Dynasty.
It's an old trick used by our ancestors,
[Duke Chang retakes the stolen country]
but also a necessary step to rise in rebellion.
That's how they buy people's hearts.
Commandery Prince An knows that Xue Rucheng wouldn't miss this step.
It's aconitum. He died of poison.
But the words on him really came out of nowhere.
That's pretty strange.
It's not strange at all. It's a little trick of a juggler.
Juggler?
The gift for Xiao Jinyu has been prepared.
You only need to make the order.
Go ahead.
Yes.
[The Imperial City]
Wait!
What's this?
Open it.
- Your Highness.
- Calm down. Wu Jiang told me
that someone threw Xu Rugui on the street behind the Three Judicial Offices. Right?
Yes. General Wu was afraid that I would get hurt.
He wouldn't let me see Xu.
I've checked the ruts at the gate.
I found some moist lees.
It might be a carriage of a distillery in the city.
Distillery?
Your Highness, Xu Rugui is awake.
Your Highness.
Did Xu Rugui go to the Three Judicial Offices?
Yes. Please rest assured.
The plan is perfect.
By the way, Xiao Jinyu asked the emperor to grant him a marriage.
He will get married two days later.
The emperor, the royal family members, and the ministers
will all attend the wedding at Princess Xiping's mansion.
Who will he marry? That coroner?
Yes.
I heard that in order to marry Xiao Jinyu,
that girl gave up being a coroner.
I thought she was an aspiring woman.
Looks like everyone will make the same choice
in the face of wealth.
But this time, it's not up to her to be a coroner or not.
Of course.
Everything is under your control.
Where's Zhou Han?
He went off on the errand you gave him.
Send someone to keep an eye on him.
He is an unfaithful slave and an opportunist.
He is totally unreliable.
Yes.
He seems to have been frightened.
He is barely conscious and very weak.
He also has a fever.
Save me. Save me.
Be quiet.
I didn't handcuff you because you look weak.
- Don't handcuff me...
- You won't be this comfortable if you don't stay quiet.
Don't... I'll be quiet.
Your Highness, it doesn't look like he caught a cold.
If he has some wounds that weren't treated properly,
he might die if the injury gets worse.
Wu Jiang, hold him down.
Go ahead.
Chu Chu, save me. Chu Chu, save me.
Don't move. I'll just check your wound.
Xu Rugui, look at me.
I'll ask you a few questions.
Think carefully before you answer me.
Only in this way can I know how to save you.
Do you understand me?
Yes. Yes.
Your Highness, something went wrong.
Jing Yi exposed our miracle in public at the Western market.
Long live Duke Chang!
[Duke Chang retakes the stolen country]
What's going on?
It's a little trick of a juggler.
Juggler?
[Liquor Vinegar]
What is he doing?
What does he want to do?
I can't tell.
I just smelled lime on him.
Lime generates heat when exposed to water.
He just played a trick of hiding the words with vinegar.
Come on, let me show it to you.
Leng Yue.
What?
Pour the lime on me.
Don't worry. I'll be fine.
He imitated us and used vinegar to write.
Lime generates heat when exposed to water.
He used it to warm the clothes and make the words show up.
Look. There are words! The words are showing up!
He wrote a love poem.
[Wish to win one's heart]
Everyone is all talking about his romance.
No one cares about the words we left.
The so-called miracle is not a crucial factor,
but the icing on the cake.
It's just like when Chen Sheng and Wu Guang spread rumors through fish and fox,
and Empress Wu Zetian used stone to buy people's hearts.
After I kill the tyrant and ascend the throne as the rightful emperor,
the people in Chang'an will know
how they have been deceived over the years.
Give them my order.
Make this loyalist Marquis Zhongyi.
Treat his wife and children generously.
Yes!
Everything is ready now.
Let them keep struggling for a while.
After the hourglass runs out,
take your place and let's wait to catch turtles in the pot.
I swear allegiance to Your Highness.
Do you know who left you at the gate of the Three Judicial Offices?
I don't know.
On my way back from Qianzhou,
I was abducted by bandits.
When I woke up, I found myself in Chang'an already.
They kept me in several different places.
But they covered my head every time.
I don't know who they are
and where I have been.
If you don't know where they kept you,
how did you know that you were in Chang'an?
There were drums.
There were drums at dawn.
Drums at dawn in Chang'an.
Did you hear any other special sound?
Or did you smell anything special?
Smell...
I smelled... liquor.
[Liquor]
I smelled lees.
Is it a tavern?
It's not a tavern.
I ran a tavern before.
They are lees.
The smell of lees from a distillery.
What else?
And... when I went out,
I heard someone yelling...
Charcoal!
Good. Keep thinking.
What food did they give you during this time?
Was there any food that you are familiar with?
Like you ate before in a restaurant in Chang'an
or at the stall in the street?
They... They only gave me
pickles and steamed buns.
And water.
And a lot of medicine.
Medicine?
Were they treating you?
I don't know. It's just medicine.
It's really bitter. A lot of medicine.
They made me take medicine every day.
When I didn't want to take it, they just poured it down me.
Good. Good.
What else can you remember?
Any detail.
Whatever you've seen, heard, smelled, tasted.
Anything you felt.
Before I went out this time,
they didn't give me steamed buns.
What?
They made me eat a ball.
But they wouldn't let me bite it.
I swallowed it down. It was big.
To prevent me from biting it,
they grabbed me by the mouth and shoved it in.
Shoved it in... Shoved it in...
The ball... The ball...
Your Highness.
There are only a few stab wounds on him caused by fighting with others.
The wounds are not infected.
But it's so weird.
He doesn't show any symptoms of wind chill.
Theoretically, he shouldn't have a fever for no reason.
Xu Rugui, did you have the fever before you ate the ball?
No.
I got in the carriage,
the carriage was swaying
and I started to feel sick... sick...
Your Highness, what's going on?
- You guys.
- Yes!
Keep an eye on him. Don't let him move.
Pay attention to his condition.
Let me know immediately if anything goes wrong.
Yes!
Help me... Help me...
I plead guilty.
Help me...
[Chang'an]
Your Highness, what's this?
Xu Rugui must've been sent by Xue Rucheng.
He took Xu Rugui captive
to make Qin Luan work for him.
Now Qin Luan is dead.
Xu Rugui is useless for him now.
He was supposed to kill Xu Rugui.
But now he sent Xu Rugui here alive.
He must be up to something.
Wu Jiang, pass my order down quickly.
Ask those who went out
to report back to me all the information they gathered.
I want every detail. You must hurry.
Yes.
I am back.
What's this?
This is the miracle Xue Rucheng showed at the Western market.
Aconitum with the trick of the juggler.
It's really perfunctory.
- Where is that person?
- He has been sent to the autopsy room.
Your Highness, I heard that Xu Rugui was left at the gate of Three Judicial Offices.
- Is he still alive?
- It's a little troublesome.
Leng Yue, I need you to take a look at Xu Rugui.
What's the situation?
Chu Chu will tell you the details.
- Okay.
Your Highness, this is all the news we found today.
[Ancestral Hall of the Xiao Family]
Ancestral Hall of the Xiao Family?
- Ancestral Hall?
- Yes.
Our person who went to follow Zhou Han today reported back
that Zhou Han showed up around the Ancestral Hall of the Xiao Family with some men.
- They were sneaky. Looks like they were...
- ...casing the joint?
- Right, casing the joint.
Casing the joint? Why would they case the joint at that place?
There are only the spirit tablets of your ancestors.
Even if Xue Rucheng was pissed off by you,
he wouldn't vent his anger by destroying your family's ancestral hall at such a critical time.
How is it?
It looks like symptoms of being poisoned by a small amount of castor bean.
From his condition now,
he will have a fever and nausea at most.
Even if he doesn't take any medicine, he won't die.
Did Xue Rucheng send him here just to let us see him suffer?
What kind of trick is this?
Does Xue Rucheng want to use him to stall us
so that we can't find out his plan?
I don't know.
I don't know anything.
I really don't know.
Let's talk outside.
What did you call Xu Rugui?
A weapon?
I'm afraid he can't even hold a spoon now.
What kind of weapon can he be?
Do you remember I said
that Xue Rucheng is waiting for a chance?
Sending Xu Rugui here should be a chance he made.
Is it the chance that can gather the royal family members and the important officials?
That's right.
What are you talking about?
Why can't I understand your words?
Your Highness, what do you think Xue Rucheng sent Xu Rugui to the Three Judicial Offices to do?
To kill me.
I got it.
If you are killed because of this,
the emperor will highly commend you.
Plus the case of Prince Consort,
in order to comfort Princess Xiping and Xiao Jinli,
he will bring his family members and the courtiers
to visit the Xiao family's ancestral hall in person.
That's the chance Xue Rucheng wants to create.
That's why you said Zhou Han showed up around the ancestral hall to case the joint.
They are frantic indeed.
I won't allow him to hurt you. I'll tie him up now!
Come back.
It's not that simple.
I don't know what exactly Xue Rucheng did to Xu Rugui,
but the key must be the ball he fed him.
Your Highness, do you suspect that the ball is poisonous?
Do you remember how Xu Rugui described the way he ate the ball?
They wanted him to swallow it.
They didn't let him chew it or give him any water.
I suspect that there is something inside the ball.
Now he is digesting the outer layer.
After the outer layer is completely digested,
it's hard to tell what's inside.
No matter what it is, the top priority is to send Xu Rugui away as far as possible.
Yeah, Your Highness. Jing Yi is right!
The top priority is to send Xu Rugui away.
Your Highness, even if it's a bomb inside the ball that will explode,
as long as it doesn't hurt anyone when it blows up,
Xue Rucheng's trick...
Chu Chu, it's a life-and-death matter.
We can't have it both ways.
Your Highness, can I have a try?
Try what?
I want to take the ball out
before its outer layer is digested.
You want to cut Xu Rugui open alive?
No.
I just want to take that thing out
like treating a patient.
But, Chu Chu, a living person is not like a dead man.
Not to mention Xu Rugui is really weak now.
We don't know if he can take it.
And… he is your uncle.
What if...
Your Highness, Xu Rugui is a criminal wanted by the imperial court.
Whether he is dead or alive,
it should be determined by the law of the court.
He shouldn't be manipulated by Xue Rucheng.
If he died from that ball,
whether it hurts anyone or not, the winner will still be Xue Rucheng.
If I cut him open and take out the ball,
disrupt their conspiracy and bring them to justice,
then the winner will be us.
Your Highness, I would like to help Chu Chu.
Leng Yue, it's too dangerous.
Your Highness, I think Chu Chu has a point.
She knows the structure of the human body very well.
I know some medical skills.
With my help, the chances of keeping him alive are bigger.
Thank you, Miss Leng.
Your Highness.
I don't know what to do with you.
Go and return quickly.
I've asked His Majesty to grant us a marriage.
We will get married a few days later.
There are still many things to prepare.
Okay, I will prepare it now.
Wu Jiang.
Ask someone to carry Xu Rugui to the autopsy room.
- Follow Chu Chu and Leng Yue's orders.
- Yes.
What's more, leave ten guards at the Ten-Commandment Hall and strictly guard the courtyard.
Leave two guards at the door of the autopsy room
to act in concert with Chu Chu and Leng Yue anytime.
The rest of them should all leave.
No one is allowed to approach the Ten-Commandment Hall without my order.
Yes!
Jing Yi, you should leave too.
Your Highness, you are all here. Where can I go?
I don't care. No matter what kind of danger it is,
I will be with you all.
I'm going to support Chu Chu and Leng Yue.
The anesthesia powder is ready.
Let me do it.
[Map of Chang'an]
The rebels are hiding in various places in Chang'an.
Xue Rucheng knows that I'm back in Chang'an.
He dare not move around right now.
Xu Rugui is an important bargaining chip of his.
[Guangde]
He had to keep him under his nose to feel at ease.
[Liquor]
Charcoal!
The charcoal seller. Lees.
A distillery that a charcoal seller passes by.
A place where the dawn drum can be heard.
It should be near the Drum Tower.
The deceased who took poison and faked the miracle at the Western market
had oil stains on his cuffs.
He had bisquits before he died
- Take it.
- Thank you.
There are shavings used to absorb moisture in the container under his soles,
which means he went to a warehouse for storing valuable goods.
[Map of Chang'an]
Your Highness.
The white line marks the traces of Zhou Han.
[Ancestral Hall of the Xiao Family]
The blue line marks the places
[Ancestral Hall Fu'an Distillery]
where the dead who faked the miracle might go before his death.
[Xue Mansion]
[Wonton]
The red line marks the possible last place where Xu Rugui was kept.
Give me something to eat, sir.
- Thank you. Thank you.
- Go away.
The gathering place of the rebels must be in the area
where the three lines intersect.
[Fengle]
- Go get Jing Yi here.  And...
- Yes.
send someone to Princess Xiping's mansion and ask Jinli to come here.
Yes.
Your Highness, Chu Chu...
What happened to Chu Chu?
Timing and subtitles brought to you by The Imperial Coroners @ Viki.com
♫  Nothing can stop me  ♫
♫  From missing you all the time  ♫
♫  The moonlight appears, cold in the late night,
as the world changes  ♫
♫  Only with you by my side can I embrace my yearning for you  ♫
♫  When I close my eyes I meet you once again  ♫
♫  I'll gently brush your hair by your ear  ♫
♫  Life is long, with love and regrets in this world  ♫
♫  With you by my side, no matter how far I go,
we'll never be apart  ♫
♫  With your smile, in this moment, let me
cherish this lifetime  ♫
♫  Only for you, I have to worry about the end of this life  ♫
♫  I’m still young, with my love not yet realized for you, but I'm
willing to be here for you till the end
♫  You can rely on me in this lifetime  ♫
♫  Hope to spend this beautiful lifetime together  ♫