Timing and subtitles brought to you by The Imperial Coroners @ Viki.com
I misunderstood His Highness.
He checked on my family background
because he wanted me to work for him.
And I finally learned who my mother was.
Fate is such a fantastic thing.
I never expected to meet such a good man like His Highness
in the Coroner Qualification Test.
Life had mercy on me
so that I managed to meet her.
Did His Majesty dream that
the late emperor's son Duke Chang came back to life
and would take back the throne?
Don't talk nonsense.
Go. Go get some tea.
I'm the lineal son of Emperor Wuzong.
You're simply my father's uncle.
If you hadn't pretended to be insane and let the eunuchs kill my family,
you wouldn't have taken the throne.
I'm doomed to be the emperor.
[The Imperial Coroner]
[Episode 14]
Manager, a letter from His Highness.
[Antique Store]
[The fish]
[rose]
[to]
[the bait.]
"The fish rose to the bait. Stand by."
Your Majesty.
Your Majesty, please enjoy some tea.
Qin Luan.
I'm here.
There are rumors in the palace about the late emperor's son, Duke Chang.
Have you heard about them?
Your Majesty, as you said, they're mere rumors.
Ignorant men are wrongly informed.
Don't bother to trust them.
Ignorant men?
Censors reported to me about it.
Are my censors also ignorant men?
All sons of the late emperor died.
It's been recorded in the genealogy.
Nothing will go wrong.
It's ridiculous to say that Duke Chang is still alive.
If it becomes a serious problem, our state may be harmed.
Nothing comes out of nothing.
Who would make an issue of a long-gone duke?
- Qin Luan.
- I'm here.
- You served three emperors.
I make you the Acting Chief Eunuch because I believe that
you can take care of everything in the palace.
When I assign you to figure out where such rumors came from
and who started them, this isn't a tough job. Is it?
Your Majesty, I'll do my best and will not disappoint you.
[Guanling Yamen]
General Xiao, I was on my way to see you.
Lend me some soldiers.
It's getting dark. Why do you want them?
His Highness hides a dead man in the Chu family. He wants to bring the body here.
Why are you in official costume? Were you recognized?
What? Li Zhang went back to his mansion.
Let's talk about it later. Lend me some soldiers first.
How can you do it secretly like this?
Doing it secretly means not letting people know about the dead man,
instead of seeing me.
You were with His Highness last night.
Do you know who the dead man is?
Well, it's hard to explain.
Ask him yourself.
Then, what are you coming for?
To get some medicine for Jinyu and see how it is going with you.
We must get Jinyu to live at the Yamen as soon as possible.
He should no longer live in Chu Chu's home.
Why?
It's hard to explain.
Leng Yue told me that Chu Chu annoyed His Highness.
It's...
Hard to explain again?
Yes.
I simply left His Highness for one day and so many things happened?
You four work for Vice Minister Jing.
Yes!
Anybody in?
- My Lord.
- Is Miss Chu Chu in?
- Yes.
Chu Chu? Chu Chu!
Come down.
Father.
Greetings, Your Highness.
You may rise.
What do you come for?
I want to borrow something from the Chu family, for some business.
What business?
General Xiao's subordinates captured a bandit.
Unexpectedly, they fought hard and accidentally killed him.
We need to take his corpse back for inspection,
but we might ruin him on the slippery road after the rain.
I hear that the Chu family sells coffins.
I'd like to buy one.
May I?
Yes. Yes.
We have coffins available. Let me take him there.
Please stay, Sir.
Let Chu Chu take them there.
No matter which one they pick, I'll pay according to the fixed price.
Don't bother paying.
We're coroners.
It's our duty to work for officials.
It's generous of you, Sir.
Chu Chu, let's go back to the Yamen with Jing Yi
and take care of the bandit thing.
Yes.
I'm sorry!
I'm sorry, Your Highness!
Last night, I was drunk and I overslept.
Your... Your Highness...
This is Commandery Prince An.
I'm Vice Minister of the Court of Judicial Review.
But-But... But yesterday... Yesterday...
Yesterday, you and Prefect Li greeted me without recognizing me.
I didn't say anything.
Greetings,
Your Highness.
It's just a misunderstanding. Don't bother about it.
You may rise.
Thank you, Your Highness.
Your Highness, the coffin...?
Well, it's a bandit General Xiao's subordinate killed.
We brought the corpse back in a coffin from the Chu family.
Ask no questions about this issue.
I'll have it handled.
I'm sorry.
I had weak governance in Guanling County,
so that you were disturbed by bandits.
Please punish me.
It takes a long time to annihilate bandits.
Just work hard on it.
Yes. Yes.
I've got something else to do.
Magistrate Zheng, could you take me to the archive?
Ar... Archive?
What? We can't go?
You... You can.
This way, please, Your Highness!
[Guanling Yamen]
[Archive]
This way, please.
Come in, please.
Your Highness, this is our archive.
This way, please.
Where's the household register?
Your Highness, these are local household registers.
Find out the household register of the Xu family.
The Xu family?
It was a big family that moved away years ago.
Your Highness, do you mean the Xu family where Deputy Magistrate Tan lived?
Deputy Magistrate lived there?
Your Highness, his father, Tan Hong, was the butler
working for the Xu family.
After they moved away, the Tan family lived in the old mansion
to take care of it.
Is this the family you're looking for?
Yes.
Please wait, Your Highness.
Please, review it.
[Household register of the Xu Family]
[Xu Zongfang, unknown. Lady Liu, unknown.]
Why is there only the record of Xu Zongfang and his wife?
What about his ancestors?
Does he have siblings?
Where did he move to?
Why isn't there any record?
Please don't get angry, Your Highness.
I'm not too lazy to make records.
Before I took up my post, the archive had a fire.
Nearly all files were burned.
I made up all the files you're reading.
There're some omissions, without a doubt.
I'm telling the truth.
I don't dare to lie.
Do you remember when the fire occurred?
I don't know. I was on my way to this county.
I simply knew that the previous magistrate left.
I guess the fire happened after he left and before I came.
I see.
Thank you.
You're welcome, Your Highness.
Get back to your business.
Yes.
Isn't she Chu Chu?
Why is she staying with His Highness?
[Archive]
- Your Highness.
Your Highness, are we going to the Xu family and ask Butler Tan?
It's not time to go yet.
Who else can we ask, then?
Deputy Magistrate Tan?
I want to ask someone before the Tan family.
But I need your permission.
I permit. Go wherever you want.
I permit.
I don't mean going somewhere.
I mean seeing someone with your permission.
Who?
Your mother, Lady Xu.
You... what do you mean?
Open her coffin.
The fire in the archive is quite odd.
It happened between the shifts of two magistrates,
also after the Xu family moved away.
It may have something to do with them.
Your Highness, do you suspect my mother didn't kill herself?
I don't know yet.
So, we shouldn't visit the Xu Mansion first.
In the coffin are your mother's remains and corpse.
Tan Hong may lie.
But your mother will not, right?
I agree.
But, Your Highness,
may I inspect my mother's corpse?
I assure you that I'll inspect her corpse as I do to other bodies.
All right. You can do that.
Thank you, Your Highness.
Tomorrow, I'll ask my men to prepare some necessary things.
You can get ready, too.
Brother, where have you been?
You didn't come back for dinner.
Did you have it out there?
Yes. I had dinner with Jing Yi in the Yamen.
Magistrate Zheng is quite clingy.
I know you like to be quiet.
I didn't invite you, then.
Did Chu He tell you something?
Chu He?
No.
What would he tell me?
He...
It's hard to explain.
I'll tell you later.
What?
I'm used to a casual life in the army. But you love to be clean.
If I don't have a bath, I'm afraid you can't fall asleep.
Brother, don't feel restrained by me.
I don't. I feel comfortable as long as you do.
Go to sleep. I'll be back after a bath.
All right.
Brother, may I use some of your soldiers tomorrow?
Sure. What for?
You'll know tomorrow.
Jinyu, did you ask Leng Yue to keep an eye on Jing Yi?
Leng Yue's keeping an eye on Jing Yi?
Yeah. Before I came back,
I saw Leng Yue peeking furtively outside Jing Yi's room.
I thought you asked her to do that, so I didn't stop her.
What are they up to?
What? You didn't ask her to do that?
Then, why did she peek at Jing Yi?
I guess Leng Yue came with me, under my mother's order.
I think Mother is vigilant about Chu Chu
and she asked Leng Yue to keep an eye on her
because Leng Yue is also a girl.
Leng Yue was with Chu Chu all the way here
and never let Chu Chu stay out of sight.
Now, she's keeping an eye on Jing Yi, instead of Chu Chu.
She possibly does it, because of Chu Chu, too.
Leng Yue...
But it looks like Miss Chu has nothing to do
with the Jing family.
Vice Minister Jing.
Greetings, Vice Minister Jing.
Deputy Magistrate Tan, it's you?
When I was at the capital for the civil exam, Senior Jing helped me.
I'd like to work for your family.
Send the two drawings back to the capital.
Rest assured.
I'll have them sent as soon as possible.
Jing Yi.
Jing Yi!
Why are you here?
Why are you in such a desolate place in the middle of the night?
I saw a man behaving furtively at the gate of the Yamen.
Then I followed him.
But he was gone when he came here.
Did you see someone when you came?
No.
You really followed someone here?
What else?
I thought you came out in the middle of the night to flirt with some girl.
It's such a desolate place. What girl can I flirt with?
What did you say?
Nothing.
I mean I shouldn't flirt with any girl.
All right. It's too late.
Let's get back to sleep.
General Xiao! Your Highness!
Anything unusual?
General Xiao, nothing is unusual.
Only nearby people have come to have a look.
As ordered, we told them that
the mansion's wall collapsed because it had been in long disrepair, and we guarded this place in case people got hurt.
Good job.
Last time, we didn't check carefully in the middle of the night.
Now that Father left this place willingly and left a corpse,
there must be something else in this room.
You wanted to borrow soldiers to search this room?
No.
You mustn't come in!
Let me in. I come to see His Highness!
General Xiao ordered that no one could come in
without permission from him or His Highness.
Let her in.
Let her in!
Yes!
What's the rush? What happened?
Nothing. Nothing.
When I woke up this morning, I didn't see you.
I... I thought...
You thought I broke my promise and took another coroner to open the coffin instead of you?
Your Highness, it's not that I don't trust you.
I just... I just...
I'm sorry.
What coffin?
Everything's still in preparation.
Brother, you'll know later.
Are you looking for Sir Witch Doctor?
Has the room remained the same since he left?
Yes.
So, Sir Witch Doctor never planned to come back again.
No matter where he has gone, I will find him.
What will we do now?
Look around for some clues.
Chu Chu. Brother. Don't take it as a job.
Based on how much you know him, look for anything
that may be related to him or about his whereabouts.
Brother.
What's this?
It's... Chess!
Chess?
Baoying Chess.
It was quite popular in the Northern Zhou Dynasty.
You can call it Chess.
Chess?
[Elephant]
Chu Chu, have you seen this before?
I saw Sir Witch Doctor polishing the stones.
But there weren't any characters on the stones.
Did he teach you to play chess?
No.
Brother, when you searched the room,
did you see anything like a chessboard?
No.
Brother.
Here it is!
It's flexible.
Let me try.
[Chess book]
It's... It's like an end-game.
Brother, let's try it.
[End-game]
I simply asked for one-day sick leave, but you caught me at home.
If it weren't for complicated business in the Ministry of War
and I not knowing what to do, I wouldn't dare to come and disturb you.
When you first worked in the Ministry of War,
you got bullied with reason.
When you wanted to apply strict measures, they also wanted to deflate you.
You're Commandery Prince An's teacher and my disciple.
It makes sense when they fear you.
Speaking of Commandery Prince An, since he gave me the copper coin,
he hasn't contacted me again.
I'm really worried.
But I don't dare to send him a letter, without consideration.
I win.
What... What does it mean?
I don't understand, either.
Is there any clue?
Well, I'll try again with the white chessman.
All right.
Commandery Prince An is always considerate.
When there's no news, it means good news.
At the court, no one is better than him in solving criminal cases.
He'll solve the illegal coin case sooner or later.
I worry that he hasn't reported this case yet.
Considering his temper, I'm afraid he'll make trouble.
I win.
I've never improved my skill in playing chess.
Sorry, Sir.
You don't have poor skills.
You simply worry too much.
You should give up unnecessary concerns.
Or when you're lost in worries, you'll lose more than gain.
I'll keep that in mind, Sir.
It's getting late.
I'll leave you alone.
It's a draw.
No one wins or loses?
Yes.
Jinyu, what does it mean?
[Rook]
[Knight]
[Elephant]
[Pawn]
[Rook | Knight | Elephant | Pawn]
What are you doing?
When the last game ended,
these four chessmen were in the same four squares.
What have you got?
Father wouldn't take the trouble to leave a useless end-game without a reason.
There must be some secret I haven't figured out yet.
Your Highness, everything's ready on the mountain.
[Xu's Tomb]
The ninth day of the first month, the first year of Emperor Wenzong.
Father, am I correct?
Yes. You're right.
The ninth day of the first month is my birthday.
Is it her birthday, too?
No, it's not her birthday.
It was the day she died.
She died on the day you were born.
It's your fate.
Fate?
It...
It means she's different to you from others.
Come on, Chu Chu. Kneel.
Burn it for her.
Tell her that today is your birthday
[Xu's Tomb]
and you're happy.
Today's my birthday.
Grandfather bought me a new dress.
Brother wove a little rabbit for me.
I'm so happy today.
Father, is it all right?
Very good.
Mother, I've come to worship you since I was little.
But this is the first time I've come as your daughter.
I'm sorry, Mother, for I have to disturb you.
I want to know who you are, who my father is,
if you suffered injustice,
and if you were wronged.
These things matter a lot to me.
I hope you can understand.
Mother, don't worry.
Commandery Prince An is the best judge in this world.
I work for him.
As long as we inspect your corpse, we'll know
what you want to tell us.
Mother,
please bless me for everything if you see it in Heaven.
Your Highness, open the coffin.
Did we really ask Miss Chu to inspect her mother's corpse?
Don't worry.
No matter what you do, your mother won't blame you.
On the death anniversary of Prince Consort,
you visited Her Grace for His Majesty.
[Jiangshan Hall]
Was everything all right?
Fortunately, I arrived in time.
Otherwise, Her Grace would have been annoyed by Qin Luan again.
I forgot to ask you.
You have never gone in this hall, have you?
[Jiangshan Hall]
No. I simply replied before the screen.
Everything in this hall concerns the safety of our nation.
No one can enter, but confidential officials.
You're now the Minister of War.
You can certainly enter the hall.
You no longer need to reply before the screen.
[Jiangshan Hall]
Your Majesty, Military Commissioner of Qianzhongdao garrisons
is an important fastness in the Southwest.
But Leng Peishan is quite old.
A successor should be picked as soon as possible.
Xiao Jinli is the son of a national hero
and he's the son of Princess Xiping.
He can be the best candidate.
Xue, you're now the Minister of War.
What do you think?
Your Majesty, I think Senior Jing makes sense.
You also recommend Xiao Jinli?
Yes.
Look at you.
You're known for being detached and not seeking fame.
Unexpectedly, shortly after you become the Minister of War,
you begin to gang up on me?
Please understand, Your Majesty.
I don't dare to gang up on you.
Then, what do you mean?
In the Army of Qianzhongdao, Xiao Jinli is never the best candidate
to take over Leng Peishan's post, in terms of qualification,
military exploit, or even rank.
Your Majesty, considering qualification, military exploit, or rank,
Xiao Jinli is never the best candidate.
But speaking of stabilizing the nation and winning people's support,
Xiao Jinli is the best choice.
Stabilizing the nation and winning people's support?
What do you mean?
Your Majesty, the Leng family has a deep foundation in the Southwest,
we can't underestimate their power.
Especially Leng Peishan.
He has tens of thousands of picked soldiers.
By annihilating bandits and helping the poor,
he's quite supported by local people.
So far, a great many people respond to his call.
Southwestern counties are far away from Chang'an.
If it goes like this,
I'm afraid he'll control the Southwest.
Your Majesty, Senior Jing means that
General Leng has been doing his duty, but he's getting old.
I understand what he means.
Yes.
Jing, Xiao Jinli's mother Princess Xiping is Leng Peishan's niece.
If the Leng family wants to reign independently,
isn't promoting Xiao Jinli exactly what they want?
Think about it, Your Majesty.
That year, Emperor Wenzong married Leng Peishan's sister,
simply to restrain the Leng family.
Now, his sister is dead.
Princess Xiping is his only niece.
She can barely restrain the Leng family.
But if Xiao Jinli can take the power of the Leng family,
things will be different.
Princess Xiping is his mother.
When his mother and brother are in Chang'an,
how can he act wildly?
You make sense.
But Leng Peishan will understand what we have planned.
I'm afraid he won't easily agree.
Your Majesty, I have a satisfactory plan, but it's not very frank.
What is it?
Leng Peishan is old and his single son died at a young age.
He has no family but his granddaughter Leng Yue.
She's nearly as old as Xiao Jinli.
They also grew up together.
If she marries Xiao Jinli, Leng Peishan will cultivate Xiao Jinli
with earnest efforts.
In this way, you can maintain your relationship with Leng Peishan
and remove the trouble in the Southwest without sending any troops.
It doesn't sound very frank.
But when it can protect people from war,
we must choose the lesser one of two evils.
I can't let them get married.
Senior Jing.
Senior Jing, the plan doesn't sound right.
It's right.
It's not a perfect plan.
But it's already good enough when no troops are needed.
But don't you always say that you're a close friend of Prince Consort
and you'll defend Princess Xiping and her sons, no matter what happens?
If General Leng really wants to reign the Southwest independently,
and he knows this, Commandery Prince An and General Xiao
will be in great danger.
What dangerous condition will Princess Xiping be in?
Have you thought about their safety?
Minister Xue, don't forget.
My son is with Commandery Prince An now.
He can't be safe unless His Highness is.
Only His Majesty, you, and I know this plan.
His Majesty and I won't let Leng Peishan know it
before it's time to strike.
As long as you keep it secret, they'll be safe.
Yes. I understand.
Your Highness, yesterday my father said
my mother hit the wall and died with obvious bruises on her forehead?
Yes.
But, Your Highness, when I checked her skull,
there wasn't any bone fracture on her forehead.
Instead, there's a fracture on the back of her head.
There're ruddy bruises on both ends of the fracture.
So, she was hurt before she died and she was badly wounded.
When the back of her head was wounded, she would certainly die.
Do you mean she not only hurt her forehead when hitting the wall but also wounded the back of her head?
No. She didn't hit the wall.
She was hit by something blunt intensively.
You mean...?
Your Highness, my mother didn't kill herself, she was murdered!
Timing and subtitles brought to you by The Imperial Coroners @ Viki.com
♫  Nothing can stop me  ♫
♫  From missing you all the time  ♫
♫  The moonlight appears, cold in the late night,
as the world changes  ♫
♫  Only with you by my side can I embrace my yearning for you  ♫
♫  When I close my eyes I meet you once again  ♫
♫  I'll gently brush your hair by your ear  ♫
♫  Life is long, with love and regrets in this world  ♫
♫  With you by my side, no matter how far I go,
we'll never be apart  ♫
♫  With your smile, in this moment, let me
cherish this lifetime  ♫
♫  Only for you, I have to worry about the end of this life  ♫
♫  I’m still young, with my love not yet realized for you, but I'm
willing to be here for you till the end  ♫
♫  You can rely on me in this lifetime  ♫
♫  Hope to spend this beautiful lifetime together  ♫