Timing and subtitles brought to you by The Imperial Coroners @ Viki.com
Long live Duke Chang!
Xue Rucheng ordered a man
to fake a miracle
[Duke Chang retakes the stolen country]
and assigned Zhou Han to case the joint at the Xiao family's Ancestral Hall.
Then he sent Xu Rugui to the Three Judicial Offices.
He went through all these efforts.
He must be up to something.
[Xue's Mansion]
[Wonton]
They made me eat a ball.
The trick must lie in what Xu Rugui ate.
You will all die when the time is up.
Your Highness, Chu Chu...
What happened to Chu Chu?
Chu Chu.
How's it going?
It's all right. I made it.
Is this what you took from his stomach?
What's with this ball?
That's gluten.
The outer layer is mixed with castor bean poison
and the inside is mercury refined with gelsemium elegan.
Your Highness, it's exactly the same as you expected.
Your Highness, what's wrong?
His Majesty is generous.
He allowed you to get married in the palace.
You need to enter the palace today to get prepared for the wedding.
Your family can't come to Chang'an now.
Madam Jing will take care of everything for you.
Just listen to her arrangements.
Leng Yue, please send Chu Chu into the palace.
Your Highness.
Don't worry, we will win.
That scum!
It's fine that he set me up.
How dare he use an insidious trick on Chu Chu!
He poisoned Xu Rugui and sent him over as scheduled.
He knew you would let Chu Chu examine him.
He knows that if Xu Rugui dies in Three Judicial Offices,
I'll let Chu Chu perform an autopsy on him because I can't trust other people.
When Chu Chu cuts open his stomach,
the poisonous gas would diffuse and kill Chu Chu!
Chu Chu, you, and the emperor.
Kill three birds with one stone.
Yes, that's exactly what he wants.
The coroner will burn gleditsia sinensis and atractylodes lancea
before performing an autopsy to drive away evil spirits.
When I come in to check her, I would also be poisoned to death.
According to the rules I set before,
if the deceased died of some unknown disease or poison,
to avoid others from being harmed,
the deceased can't be kept in the mansion and must be buried within four hours.
If I'm buried, my spirit tablet will be sent to the ancestral hall immediately.
In order to appease the royal family members and the examinees gathered in Chang'an,
the emperor would go to the Ancestral Hall of the Xiao family in person.
Then his chance will come.
Each step is interlocked. He is malicious and thoughtful indeed.
Fortunately, Chu Chu was bold but careful enough to see through his trick.
Your Highness, in such a situation,
he will definitely attend your wedding two days later.
Send out the invitations for me.
I'm going to meet someone.
[The Imperial Coroner]
[Episode 36]
Wu Jiang! I will lose my temper!
Go ahead. I want to see it. Come on.
General Wu, just treat me like a fart and let me go.
Cut it out.
All right, let's talk.
You are going to break my hand.
Your Highness.
I happen to have something to talk to you about.
No problem. Can you let me go first?
Let you go?
Come with me.
Grabbing me makes me look bad.
Go.
Your Highness, something went wrong.
What? They are still alive?
Yes.
That female coroner has entered the palace to be prepared for the wedding.
Commandery Prince An is preparing for the wedding in a big way.
Looks like Commandery Prince An has seen through the trick on Xu Rugui.
Xiao Jinyu. He insists on me attending his wedding.
I'll go as he wants.
General Zhou, where have you been?
I ate something wrong and my stomach really hurts.
Look.
Your Highness.
You have followed me all the way here.
We've been biding our time for years,
waiting for a chance to kill the tyrant,
let the rightful emperor rule Tang
and save the people who are suffering.
Now, this tyrant uses the world as bait to entice me.
Then I'll show him
how I will take down the world in just ways.
The time when my army arrives in Chang'an
and takes down the tyrant is when we succeed.
I swear allegiance to Your Highness!
I... I swear allegiance to Your Highness!
Long live Your Highness! Long live Your Highness!
[Three Judicial Offices]
- Jinyu.
- Jinli?
I really missed you.
Jinli, I'll have to let Chu Chu come back from the palace
and perform an autopsy on me if you don't let me go.
I have heard everything about Xue Rucheng.
My people said Jing Yi sent the wedding invitations
to all the officials in Chang'an with great fanfare
to make sure every man of Xue Rucheng will see it clearly.
Rest assured. When we join hands, we can eradicate him for sure.
Just wait to get married to Chu Chu and look for your wedding night.
Congratulations that you have someone you like.
What? What nonsense are you talking about?
Luo Yan, the deputy leader of Zhenyuan Escort.
[Zhenyuan Escort]
I haven't had the honor to meet this deputy leader,
but I've seen the token on you.
The leader of Zhenyuan Escort also has such a token.
It's a token of the leaders of Zhenyuan Escort.
You came all the way back to Chang'an and have changed your clothes several times.
But you still take it with you.
It's enough to prove her importance in your heart.
The evidence is obvious enough.
Are you going to say she is not the girl you like?
All right.
I'm glad you can still make fun of me.
You and Xue Rucheng have a deep relationship.
I was worried you would...
Thanks to Chu Chu.
Jing Yi was right.
If I missed the Coroner Qualification Test and missed Chu Chu,
I would regret it for my life.
It's just I still feel guilty about letting her take risks with me.
You two. When we were in Qianzhou, she also told me this.
She was afraid she would get you into trouble.
You two didn't get each other into any trouble.
But you did give me a lot of work.
It's too hard for me. After this is over, I'd better hurry back.
For real, Jinyu. I've been feeling unsure about it.
At this point, does Xue Rucheng really just count on such a few people
to help him usurp the throne?
No matter what he will do,
as long as he makes a move,
he will make arrangements.
As long as he makes arrangements, there must be traces left.
As long as there are traces, I can find him before he makes another move.
I don't understand the move and arrangement you are talking about.
Just tell me what you need me to do.
Go back and accompany Mother.
She didn't say anything, but she must be worried now.
She didn't say anything because she doesn't want to distract me.
You have been away from Chang'an for so long.
She misses you a lot.
Go back and spend more time with her.
And also strengthen the defense of her mansion
lest these bandits should do something to Mother.
I'll let you know if I have any plans.
All right, I'll listen to you.
I will go back now. I'm leaving.
I had been worried about Commandery Prince An's marriage all day long.
I didn't expect that they would get married
after a trip to the Southwest.
Looks like young people shouldn't stay in one place all the time.
They need to go out.
We don't have a daughter.
I never expected I would give a bride away one day.
Let me ask you.
What kind of dowry is popular in Chang'an now?
His Majesty is gracious.
He specially allowed Chu Chu to get married in the palace.
I have to make sure that the wedding
is good enough for Commandery Prince An.
What do you think?
Forget it.
It's the business of women. You know nothing about it.
Why would I ask you?
This is the latest popular color in Jiangnan.
[Wedding]
Look. It looks opulent but unassuming.
It's perfect to make
His Highness's wedding rope with it.
It's not good.
This material looks all right on Jinli.
But Jinyu is whiter than him.
Let's use the material I have.
Yes.
Mother.
I just got back and you brought me to try these things.
You picked and picked.
In the end, you picked the first one you like.
You wasted all these efforts and wrapped me up like a zongzi.
(A traditional Chinese rice dish made of glutinous rice stuffed with different fillings and wrapped in bamboo leaves)
That's because you won't cooperate.
You keep saying good and no problem when I asked you.
Okay, it's my fault.
Listen. No matter what, Jinyu has a wife now.
But look at you.
How is it about me all of a sudden?
Of course, it's about you.
You stay in the Southwest Army all the time.
You can't meet any girl and the girl can't meet you either.
When can you get married?
I mean, Mother. It's Jinyu who will get married.
Why are you measuring me?
I need to make you some new clothes.
The emperor finally took back the thought of letting you marry Yue.
While you are still in Chang'an, I'll find a good wife for you.
Jinyu's wedding will be full of guests.
Dress yourself up. Maybe some girl will fall in love with you.
Mother, you are making me sound like a cucumber on a vegetable stall.
Will someone want me if I look fresher?
Don't make jokes.
- Aunt.
- Yue.
General Xiao is handsome and talented.
He will still be shining even if he wore a sack.
Aunt, don't worry about it.
When did you become so sweet?
Shouldn't you be preparing for Chu Chu's dowry?
Why are you here to make trouble?
Who is making trouble? Aunt asked me to come.
All right, you fight every time you meet.
I've forgotten the important thing.
That's because of you.
It's my fault again.
This is the heirloom of the Xiao family.
When I married your father,
your father gave it to me in person.
Yue, give it to Chu Chu.
Shouldn't you give it to Jinyu first and let Jinyu give it to Chu Chu?
Here, Yue.
I'll keep this one for you.
When you meet someone you love,
I will give it to her by myself.
All right.
Come on.
It's so pretty.
This is the most beautiful dress I have ever seen.
Of course. This was chosen from thousands of materials and styles
by the maids in the palace. Madam Jing supervised it in person.
You will be the most beautiful bride in Chang'an.
I heard from other people
that the bride's dress is the most beautiful clothes in the world.
I never saw it before.
Now I know what they said is true.
It's really beautiful.
You've never seen a bride before?
The people in your town don't get married and hold weddings?
They do. But I'm a coroner.
I used to be a coroner.
I was considered unlucky even when I passed by someone's door.
A wedding is an auspicious event.
How would they want to invite a coroner?
I didn't understand these things when I was a kid.
Once I saw people get married. So I came up to take a look.
As a result, I was driven out before I saw the bride.
My brother even had a fight with them for that.
He got his head busted and rested at home for a few days.
In the end, my father took a lot of money and apologized to them.
It was then that I knew the child of a coroner
is different from other children.
Chu Chu, don't worry.
You are the daughter of a general now, a descendant of a loyal general.
After marrying Commandery Prince An, you will be Commandery Princess An.
No one will bully you again like that.
I know it.
But I still hope when they stop bullying me one day,
it's not because I'm a general's daughter or Commandery Prince An's wife,
but because they don't bully any coroner in the world
and the person who used to be a coroner.
And I'm not bullied as one of them.
What the coroner does is a good thing to punish the evil and uphold the good.
What's bad is people's prejudices.
But I believe these prejudices will disappear one day
and turn into tenfold and hundredfold respect.
I also believe there will be such a day.
But...
But what?
But... if it weren't for the emperor to grant us the marriage,
I think Princess Xiping would never have found a coroner like me to be her daughter-in-law.
That's what you worry about?
I almost forgot about it if you didn't mention it.
This is the heirloom of the Xiao family.
- Princess Xiping asked me to give it to you.
- Really?
Of course. It can't be more real.
Princess Xiping worries that you'll think too much about it.
Now that she gave you the heirloom,
it means that she has seen you as her daughter-in-law.
You got the witness and the evidence now.
Why should you still worry about it?
Thank you, Miss Leng.
Rise!
Go!
Do you hear that? Be quick. Hurry up.
Fall!
This is a grand scene.
General Zhou, is that the emperor?
Are you blind? Who else can enjoy that?
Yes, General Zhou.
I just came from Qianzhou.
I don't know the people in Chang'an.
Are you sure it's real?
Why don't you go down, open the curtain,
and ask the emperor to have a smile for you?
I'm from the Shence Army. Now I'm here keeping watch with you.
And you don't believe me.
How about this? You stay here. I'll quit.
Don't. Sorry, General Zhou. Don't be angry. I was kidding.
As long as it's real.
I'll take a few people to the backyard.
Go on and keep an eye on them.
Play it by ear if anything happens.
Okay.
Let's go.
Greetings to Your Highness.
How is it going?
Rest assured, Your Highness. Besides here, other troops have also been arranged.
How is Princess Xiping's mansion guarded?
It's just as normal.
Looks like they are just happily preparing for the wedding.
Your Highness, Xiao Jinyu is using his wedding as bait. He also invited the emperor.
There is no way they would let up their guard.
Have the royal family members and the officials arrived?
Yes.
General Zhou saw them go in.
All of them are there.
Your Highness, it's abnormal. I'm afraid there is a trap.
Keep probing.
Yes.
No need.
Our Commandery Prince An is doing well.
With all these clues provided by you,
if he can't find this place,
doesn't it mean what you taught him all these years has all been forgotten?
Where is Xiao Jinyu?
[Enjoy all blessings]
Go!
The bride steps over the fire,
all the evil spirits will be sacred.
The new couple steps over the saddle to live a peaceful life.
Congratulations, Your Highness.
- Congratulations, Your Highness.
- Congratulations.
Princess Xiping has arrived!
Congratulations.
Greetings to Your Grace.
Today is the wedding day of Commandery Prince An. I hope I'm not late.
You finally came.
Once a teacher, always a father.
Today's your wedding day. How can the king not come?
Look. I also brought you a pair of gifts.
Xue Rucheng, let my son go!
Xue Rucheng, what do you want to do?
How can you call yourself a king in that look?
How dare you!
This is the fifth son of the late emperor, Duke Chang.
Come and pay respect to His Highness!
I'm the rightful emperor.
The tyrant stole my country and sacked my mansion.
I'm here today to follow Heaven's will.
Those who submit to me will be forgiven and made high officials.
Those who are against me will be punished by me according to Heaven's will.
What kind of rightful emperor are you?
Your real name is Xue Tang.
You were just a slave in Duke Chang's mansion,
Duke Chang's reading partner when he was a kid.
How dare you make trouble in the name of Duke Chang!
Do you plead guilty?
I can't believe you said that.
When Duke Chang's mansion was in trouble, you weren't born yet.
I am the rightful son of the late emperor.
The blood of the Li clan runs in my veins.
Duke Chang left Chang'an because of smallpox when he was young.
All the old officials know it.
Do you think changing
[Young Duke Chang, Young Xue Rucheng]
the medical record of Duke Chang
can conceal the fact that you are an impostor?
[Imperial Medical Service]
You think I don't know what you are playing?
Do you think forging some medical records
can make lies come true?
You must be dreaming.
The medical records can be forged,
but scars can't be faked.
The smallpox is extremely dangerous.
Once infected, the chances of surviving are very small.
Even if you survived by luck,
it would leave scars on you that are difficult to eliminate.
Xue Tang, can you find one scar on you caused by smallpox?
Those who took a bath with him, think about it.
Your Highness, well...
Jinyu, think about it carefully.
The two of them grew up with you since childhood.
Even if you don't care about your life, are you going to let them die?
Jinyu.
Jing Yi, listen up!
You are a descendant of the Jing clan.
You shall never submit to a rebel!
Of course!
The descendant of the Leng clan won't submit to a rebel, either!
But I'm afraid you don't have the nerve to take my life.
Their lives are in their own hands.
Your Highness, ask Jing Yi and Leng Yue to arrest Xue Rucheng?
Your Highness, don't worry. I will tie him up and bring him back to you.
No, let him tie you up and bring you to me.
Let him tie us up?
Why is that?
Xue Rucheng has been biding his time for so long.
We don't know how many men he has.
I have counted it.
The number of the rebels sneaking into Chang'an in disguise is only 30% of the estimated number.
According to the news,
there are soldiers and horses heading for Chang'an day and night.
I think that's Xue Rucheng's trump card.
Exactly. We need to let him feel that he has the upper hand.
Then he will show all his cards.
Only in this way can we wipe out all the rebels without leaving any potential threat.
Okay, I'll listen to you.
But Xue Rucheng is frantic now.
What if he will hurt them?
Mother, in order to enter Princess Xiping's mansion,
Xue Rucheng will keep us alive.
How are you going to get free?
Don't worry. I have planted someone in the rebels.
Zhou Han?
He will find a chance and do something to the ropes.
Then you can escape when you have a chance.
Hurry! Hurry!
Your Highness!
- Yue.
- Wu Jiang.
- Yes.
- Yue.
- Escort Her Grace into the inner hall!
- Jing Yi.
Your Grace, let's go.
Good. I taught you well.
You are really good.
Once he enters Princess Xiping's mansion,
his people outside will attack Chang'an to respond to him.
It can build up the momentum for his rebellion
and attract the forces in Chang'an at the same time.
Senior Jing has reported it to His Majesty.
There will be soldiers lying in ambush to deal with them.
Commandery Prince An, not good.
They took the emperor away.
Xue Tang, how dare you!
Xiao Jinyu, I watched you grow up.
I know clearly what you are up to.
You sent Jing Yi and Leng Yue with some men to kill me
because you knew that even if they failed,
I would still keep them alive as hostages.
I really taught you well, didn't I?
I should thank you.
Step aside!
- If it weren't for them two...
- Step aside.
- I wouldn't be so sure.
- Don't move.
That I could get such a precious opportunity for General Zhou.
- It's you?
- Yes.
The person sitting in the emperor's carriage and leaving the palace
will be Chu Chu.
Chu Chu?
To scatter the forces in Chang'an,
Xue Rucheng ordered the rebels outside the city
to attack Chang'an on purpose,
so that he can take the chance and abduct the emperor.
I have asked Zhou Han to follow Xue Rucheng's orders.
I will leave most of the soldiers in the front hall.
[Gate Front Hall]
Xue Rucheng will order Zhou Han
to sneak in from the side gate when the backyard is unguarded
[Side Gate Hengxiang Pavilion
and go to the Hengxiang Pavilion.
Chu Chu will be there disguised as the emperor.
Zhou Han will take Chu Chu away.
Your Highness, Xue Rucheng wants to kill the emperor.
If you let Chu Chu disguise herself as the emperor,
whether she will be recognized or not, she can still get killed.
There are so many eunuchs and maids in the palace.
Some of them even practiced martial arts.
Why don't you find someone else?
Why do you have to let Chu Chu take the risk?
I want to do it.
Xue Rucheng is sinister and cunning.
He always has a backup plan.
But I'm afraid he used all of his strength this time
and is prepared to
die together if he fails.
That's right. I got some accurate news from Zhou Han
that there is a candle Xue Rucheng carries with him at all times.
It could be his last resort.
I trust His Highness and understand him.
We can cooperate really well.
Hold on.
I was also there when the emperor granted baths to the officials.
I remember you were white and soft.
There were no scars or marks on you.
You are not Duke Chang. Who on earth are you?
I told you his name is Xue Tang. He was a studying partner of Duke Chang.
He is not Duke Chang. He is the fake one.
Don't you talk nonsense!
His Majesty has issued an imperial edict
that the Duke Chang case will be handled by the Three Judicial Offices.
Considering many of you were deceived by this crafty man,
those who surrender after knowing the truth will be sentenced leniently.
Those who still follow the rebel, Xue Rucheng,
will be executed!
[Token]
Your Highness, I've been deceived!
I surrender!
I surrender, Your Highness!
Bros, what are you waiting for?
Following the fake Duke Chang will get you nowhere.
Surrender now!
- I surrender, I surrender!
- I surrender!
Take them down into custody.
No need. I'll go by myself.
Xue Tang, your time has run out.
Let Chu Chu go. I'll leave you a whole body.
We don't know whose time is up.
You let a female coroner put on the emperor's dragon robe.
That's rebellious!
You should worry about how long you will be able to live.
Stop trying to stir things up. His Majesty has approved it.
His Majesty wants me to tell you
that the prestige of the Emperor of Tang comes from diligence and love for the people.
It's not something a crown or a robe can represent.
People like you who only have selfish desires
and have no caring for the nation and the people
are doomed to be abandoned by everyone.
Are you not afraid that I will kill her?
If Chu Chu dies, you will have no more bargaining chips.
I will never let you go even at the cost of my life!
Well, well, Xiao Jinyu.
You even made use of the woman you love for your own career!
I'll make you remember it today.
You gave her life to me in person.
It's you who kills her!
Hold on!
Let me replace her.
Jinyu.
Xue Tang, instead of burning your bridge,
why don't you let me replace her?
You know that I can't fight at all.
Taking me as a hostage can get you a way out.
I'll replace her. Okay?
- Jinyu.
- Your Highness.
I'll replace her.
Your Highness! Your Highness!
- Chu Chu, go back!
- Your Highness!
- Step back! Or I will kill him!
- Chu Chu, go back!
- Your Highness!
- Step back, or I will kill him!
Step back, or I will kill him!
Get off me. Your Highness!
Your Highness!
From what I know about him,
only letting him catch Chu Chu
can make him believe that I'm at the end of my wits.
Taking me as a hostage can get him a way out.
Therefore, he will agree to replace Chu Chu with me.
But in this way, you will end up in danger alone.
Back off!
Back off! Or I will kill him!
At this point, can you tell me the truth?
What did you say?
You used to treat me like your little brother, like your son.
Except that you wanted to benefit from the influence of my mother and Senior Jing,
have you ever been sincere to me?
Sincere?
I just wanted to make use of
your upright personality
to disturb the forces of all parties in the imperial court.
Credit
The mechanism on the door was designed by me.
I know its range and angle best.
I'll lead him there and ensure he gets hit.
Jinli is secretly practicing it in the mansion right now.
I'll cooperate with him.
We can definitely kill him.
Senior Jing, please take care of the emperor.
Please rest assured, Your Highness.
We've been weaving the net for catching the bandits.
Now the net is hanging over these rebels.
It's about the time to pull out the net.
We need to work together to give them the final blow and take them down.
Thank you all for risking your lives with me and trusting me.
Well...
Your Highness, why are you doing that?
We are brothers. There is no need to say thanks.
That's right.
Just give me back the salary... you deducted this year.
That's all you care about.
Just like your father.
I didn't say anything.
Here is His Majesty's edict!
"Commandery Princess An, Chu Chu of the Yun clan,
has the talent to be a coroner.
[Chu Chu
She helped Commandery Prince An
[Chu Chu]
solve strange cases and help the living by performing autopsies on the dead.
She is a talent indeed with a kind heart and superb skills.
I crave talents.
Today, I grant Chu Chu of the Yun clan the identity as a coroner.
She is allowed to assist Commandery Prince An
to investigate cases and punish evil.
Respect this!"
[Respect this!]
♫ The start and the end ♫
♫ Describe in detail ♫
♫ What stays in my eyes ♫
♫ I don't want to ♫
♫ What is lost ♫
♫ May you be foolish ♫
♫ I can't have it when I seek for it ♫
♫ However hard I try ♫
♫ Lies are everywhere ♫
♫ In the parallel world ♫
♫ Its wry face ♫
♫ Uncover the incomplete book ♫
♫ Before it comes to an end ♫
♫ In the parallel world ♫
♫ A good show is on ♫
♫ I don't want to ♫
♫ In madness and obsession ♫
♫ Make flesh and blood ♫
♫ Trapped in life ♫
[Three Judicial Offices]
Jinli, it's early in the morning, you are...
Well, I can't explain it to you in a few words.
Take a look by yourself.
Your Highness, take a look.
The chickens came out from the eggs.
Do you like them?
Yes... I do.
Jing Yi! That chicken flew away!
Catch it!
Jing Yi, what kind of bad habit is that?
What do you know?
This is called flying side by side.
[The End]