Timing and subtitles brought to you by The Imperial Coroners @ Viki.com
The superior of Li Zhang should be the so-called Duke Chang.
Your Highness, mercy!
You mean General Leng?
What?
Is General Leng involved in this?
I was just ordered to investigate the case of illegal minting,
then the evil spirits thing happened.
It's too strange
and the timing is coincidental.
[Leng Peishan]
Is there any news from Zhou Han?
Where did he take Xu Rugui to?
Xu Rugui was taken...
Zhou Han got Xu Rugui?
Wait, Master. Hold on.
Yeah.
Zhou Han only said
he planted his men among the soldiers of the Shence Army
who escorted Xu Rugui.
But he didn't mention that he got Xu Rugui out.
What?
Master, that's a test.
You are testing me, right?
You think Zhou Han is incompetent,
so you secretly sent a professional to take Xu Rugui away. Right?
Idiot!
Master, what should we do now?
It has been Xiao Jinyu
who is vying with me for Xu Rugui.
Xiao Jinyu let Xue Rucheng
take Xu Rugui away.
Now those who got Xu Rugui hurt Xue Rucheng.
It's definitely not Xiao Jinyu who did it.
I'm afraid they are coming after us.
But who is so bold as to go against us?
Except for Xiao Jinyu and his people,
who else dares to go
against me like this in Chang'an?
Do you mean it's the group of people under the banner of Duke Chang?
But why would they go against you?
What are they up to?
They are under the banner of Duke Chang now.
What do you think they are up to?
The vast lands of Tang?
Land?
Master, since the An Shi Rebellion,
the emperors come and go, but the Division of Eunuchs is always here.
No matter who ascends the throne
we are still the ones in charge.
I think you have lived a life of ease for too long.
You don't even know what death means.
Now, Xu Rugui is missing.
Our heads might fall off our necks anytime.
Do you understand?
Listen. Get your act together.
Someone will come to us soon.
Yes.
That's all you can say. Idiot! Idiot!
Master, watch your hands.
[The Imperial Coroner]
[Episode 27]
Don't cry out. Be quiet.
I'm afraid she is clumsy and she will singe my skin.
Your skin is thick enough. It won't hurt to singe it a little bit.
There are burn marks.
This is the bark of beech willow.
Put it on the skin and bake it over a fire,
there will be marks like bruises.
And you can't wash it off or wipe it off by hand.
It can only be wiped off with wine.
On the day I arrived in Chang'an,
I saw a fraud using this method to cheat people out of their money.
This is amazing.
Let me see it.
The mark looks like a real one.
But after he gets in the army, the army doctor will check his wound and it's hard not to be touched.
It's still different from a real one.
Please hold on, I haven't finished yet.
Chu Chu, here is the fresh croton you want.
You came back just in time. Give it to me.
Why do you need this?
What's wrong?
It feels...
warm and tingling.
Not bad.
It's exactly the same as the real one.
Miss Chu, it's my first time to know that coroners can fake wounds.
Actually, coroners don't do this.
Those who want to frame others came up with such a trick.
Some people try to cast aspersions on others
and try to rob them of their money,
they would use the beech willow bark and croton juice to fake a wound and go to the office to file a suit.
There have been several cases of such false accusations in the office of Magistrate Zheng.
There are some talents among the folks.
Your Highness.
With the swelling, it looks like a real burn mark.
Not bad.
It can fool ordinary doctors.
I'll take a walk.
Vice Minister Jing, hold on.
If you want to pretend to be a wounded soldier with a broken leg,
only one injury is not enough.
Your Highness, how do you want Vice Minister Jing to break his leg?
It's just a broken leg. Is there any difference?
Of course, there is.
If you land on your face, there should be injuries on your face.
If you land on your side, there will be injuries on your arms.
But the injuries on your face
should be mixed with some real scratches to make it real.
Arm.
Those who are in the base of the Military Commissioner don't know what I look like.
General Leng has never seen me before.
I'm safe.
What's more, how can I get married
if I spoil my appearance?
Jinli, I need you not to tell anyone in the army
about Jing Yi pretending to be a wounded soldier and entering the infirmary.
Only a few of us can know it before we find out the truth.
Otherwise, Jing Yi will be in great danger.
Okay, I'll listen to you.
But why does Jing Yi have to pretend to be a wounded soldier?
Didn't you say that the army is strictly governed
and they don't slack off even when they are resting?
Yes. After such things have happened, I guess it's stricter now.
Therefore, among all the soldiers, those who are most relaxed
and have time to gossip and chat
are the wounded soldiers in the infirmary.
This matter happened very strangely.
We have to take information from all sides
so as to find out the truth as quickly as we can.
But even if he pretends to be a wounded soldier,
can Jing Yi make it?
Why can't I make it?
If I have trouble, I'll ask you for help.
Don't even think about it.
There is one more thing.
Leng Yue. Miss Chu. There are regulations in the army
that normally women are not allowed to enter the barracks.
This time, General Leng wrote a letter to invite Commandery Prince An to come,
it should be fine that you two follow him.
But you still need to be careful.
Eunuch!
Eunuch Qin.
Eunuch Qin, I've been to the antique store
and checked the accounts and access records.
They are just some ministers who like these kinds of things.
There is nothing wrong.
Are you a cow in the horoscope?
I am not a cow. I am a pig.
Then, why do you need me to whip you up to take a step forward?
If you can't find out anything from the list,
can't you figure out another way to do it?
There are so many people going there.
Some go there more often and some go there less often.
At least you should...
know who goes there more often and who goes there less often.
Yes.
General Zhou, get some people to keep a good eye on the antique store.
There can be no let up.
If you make any mistake and ruin my business,
don't blame me for being ruthless to you.
Yes. By the way, Eunuch Qin.
I found something about what you ordered me to do a few days ago.
After some investigations, among those who left Chang'an,
some are dead and some are missing now.
I only found two people who are still alive.
One is a former maid from Princess Xiping's mansion.
The other is a former nanny.
I've made some arrangements
and the two of them are on their way back to Chang'an.
They will arrive in Chang'an soon.
Good.
Remember.
I want them alive.
Alive. Alive.
Eunuch Qin, take care.
Who are the bandits that are so bold
as to attack a minister in the capital?
The wound is superficial.
I'm grateful for His Majesty's concern.
I'm sorry to have bothered you.
Don't neglect your wound.
Now it's easy to get smallpox.
You haven't gotten smallpox before.
If you are infected at this age, that will really put you
in a dangerous place.
I'll give you some medicine for preventing it.
If there is nothing important for you to do,
you'd better rest in your room.
See Doctor Zhang off.
Yes.
Doctor Zhang, please.
Manager.
How's he doing?
He was seriously injured.
After a long laborious trip, his condition is not optimistic.
Decoct the wild ginseng and feed it to him.
Manager, that's the best wild ginseng.
He is so lucky.
Well, do you want to change your life with his?
No, no. I'll decoct the wild ginseng for him.
Don't worry, Manager Chi.
I will save Xu Rugui's life for His Highness.
This person is very important.
You mustn't let anything happen to him.
After we achieve the great cause, I'll ask His Highness to reward you.
Eunuch Qin! Eunuch Qin! You can't go in there!
Eunuch Qin! You can't go in!
- Eunuch Qin! I didn't know you would come. Sorry.
- Our master is not feeling well.
Your place is a little shabby.
Well, well. Look.
There is a sour smell of a useless scholar everywhere.
What brought you here?
I heard that you were injured.
By the will of His Majesty, I'm here to check your condition.
I'm grateful for His Majesty's concern.
The wound is superficial. I'm doing well.
Where did you get hurt?
It's this arm.
Where?
The emperor wants to know your condition.
I need to examine your wound, so I can report to His Majesty.
Am I right?
Yes.
His Majesty said Minister Xue accomplished nothing
during your trip to the Southwest.
You are an unusual talent in Tang.
His Majesty really doesn't know
whether you went to the Southwest to work
or to make a sightseeing tour with the money of the government.
I failed His Majesty's grace.
I deserve death.
Why are you still alive?
I have no complaints.
What a pity. His Majesty is lenient.
He doesn't want your life.
You won't die.
But you will be fined the salary of six months.
Do you feel wronged?
I'm grateful for His Majesty's grace.
Yeah, I forgot.
You don't need to worry about your livelihood.
As long as Commandery Prince An is still breathing,
he will reward you with something to eat.
You are so lucky to have such a good long-living student.
Thank you, Eunuch Qin.
Look what a coward you are.
I really should invite Princess Xiping to take a look at you.
Minister Xue, have a good rest.
I'll leave.
Take care, Eunuch Qin.
Bastard.
I won't keep you alive after I make it.
Manager. As you ordered,
the birthday gift for Eunuch Qin is prepared.
[Birthday]
Please have a look.
Good.
Very good.
Manager, Qin Luan is an old eunuch who has been through three dynasties.
Can we make him believe that we have Xu Rugui with just one Ruyi?
Even if he believes it, he may not be willing to cooperate with us.
Eunuchs are slaves of the royal family.
They are just assuming the majesty of the emperor.
They don't care who the emperor is.
We only need to let Qin Luan know
that the world is still ruled by the current emperor.
Xu Rugui is an important witness who will threaten his power
in the Division of Eunuchs, even his life.
But if Duke Chang ascends the throne,
Xu Rugui will become an important link
between the Division of Eunuchs and him.
After we make this clear to him, Qin Luan will weigh the pros and cons
and choose to cooperate with us.
[Qianzhou Army]
Greetings to General Leng.
You may rise.
Jinli, you are finally back.
You have become stronger now.
- General Leng.
- Thank you for the efforts.
Commandery Prince An.
This matter happened so suddenly. Sorry to have troubled you to come here.
I didn't expect you to be here so soon.
I'm truly grateful.
Please don't say that.
I'm General Zhao Jie.
I'm General Hou Bin.
Greetings to Commandery Prince An.
You may rise.
This is...
This is my coroner.
Greetings to General Leng.
To my surprise, your coroner is a girl.
This girl is...
A charwoman.
Leng Yue!
This is the granddaughter of General Leng.
Sorry for being disrespectful.
What's respectable about the granddaughter of General Leng?
General Leng.
This little soldier wears our uniform,
but he doesn't look like one of our men.
General Leng, this is a Qianzhou's soldier
rescued by us from a group of bandits on our way here.
He was severely injured and we were in a hurry to come here.
So we changed his clothes and brought him here for treatment.
I saved him. Sorry for bringing you trouble.
Take this Qianzhou's soldier to the infirmary for treatment.
Yes.
Come with me.
Commandery Prince An, please.
General Leng, please.
Please.
There are more people with malignant sores recently.
We need to get more medicinal materials for malignant sores
or we'll be running around looking for medicinal matterials when we run out of them.
Okay. Make a list for me.
- Okay.
- I'll go and check the storeroom.
If there are not enough crude drugs, I'll ask someone to buy more.
- General.
- Guys.
-  General Xiao, when did you come back?
- I've Just arrived.
Listen. This is a Qianzhou soldier I saved on my way here.
He is severely injured and has had quite a scare.
General Leng asked me to bring him here for treatment.
I'll send him back after he gets better.
It's scary to be a soldier.
I heard that Qianzhou's soldiers are as weak as chickens
and as timid as mice.
Today, I finally see one alive.
I think he is half dead.
All right.
Watch your words. Don't you feel shameful?
You two, stop standing there.
Help him to bed.
It hurts. It hurts.
Your Highness, please don't mind
[Assembly Hall]
the poor conditions here.
No need to say that.
In your letter, you summarized what happened here in a few words.
Can you elaborate on the whole situation for me?
Hou Bin.
Yes.
You tell him.
Your Highness. About half a month ago,
something very strange happened in the army all of a sudden.
From time to time, there would be some soldiers who would suddenly go crazy.
Some of them are less ill.
They would just go crazy and talk nonsense that no one could understand.
After they woke up, they became normal again.
But they forgot everything they said and did when they went crazy.
Some soldiers are more seriously ill.
They killed themselves in madness for no reason.
That's why General Leng presumes
that there are evil spirits behind it?
Your Highness. As for the evil spirits,
it was an idea of mine and General Hou.
I really don't know how to deal with it.
A few days ago, General Yunhui, Xu Ping,
jumped into the fire in public and was burned alive in front of us.
Everyone was startled by the scene.
If we don't find out what's happening here,
I'm afraid there will be a big mess.
Besides, he did look like he was possessed by an evil spirit.
All right.
I wrote the letter.
It's my presumption.
Since Commandery Prince An is here now,
I think you also want to find out the truth.
General Hou.
Yes.
How many people have gone crazy?
How many people committed suicide?
About seventeen or eighteen people have gone crazy.
Three people committed suicide.
Do you have a list or any statements?
Yes. General Leng ordered me to take statements of all the witnesses
and survivors.
I will present you the papers later.
Where are the bodies of the deceased?
They are placed in a camp.
Chu Chu, go and take a look with Leng Yue.
- Yes.
- Hold on.
Your Highness, Miss Chu is your coroner.
She needs to do autopsies.
But Leng Yue is just a girl goofing around.
I don't think it's proper to let her get involved in this case.
What's improper?
Are you afraid even a girl goofing around like me
can see through your lie?
Nonsense!
Leng Yue.
Don't be rude in the army.
General Leng, since we agreed
that the priority is to let me find out the truth.
Then please let my people do their work.
General, please rest assured.
Even if it were witchcraft, evil can never beat good.
Zhao Jie.
Yes.
Take them to the mortuary.
Miss Chu. Miss Leng.
Please.
[Assembly Hall]
Your Majesty, please enjoy the Zisun Tea from Huzhou.
Qin Luan. Your birthday is in a few days, right?
Yes.
I'm truly grateful that Your Majesty still remembers my birthday.
You have been serving me for a long time.
How can I not even remember that?
Since your birthday is around,
you will need to buy some auspicious things.
I will reward you with a hundred taels of gold
and allow you to celebrate your birthday outside the palace.
Thank you for your grace, Your Majesty.
What's more, you have been the head of the Division of Eunuchs for some time.
I'll ask someone to draft an edict and promote you on your birthday.
Thank you, Your Majesty.
I will repay your grace with my earnest efforts.
Jinbao, keep a close eye on him.
Let me know immediately if you have any news.
Yes.
Your Highness.
- Your Highness.
- You may rise.
Chu Chu, how did it go?
It can be basically determined that the three deceased men
were drowned, strangled, and burned.
The first man had strangulation marks above his pomum adami (Adam's apple). His hyoid was broken.
[Neck Strangulation marks]
He died of strangulation.
The second man had a bulging belly.
There was a small amount of blood foam deep in his nose and mouth.
He was drowned.
The third man's limbs were scorched black and curled.
There was soot in his mouth and nose. He was burned to death.
There is no trace of struggling and fighting before they died.
General Zhao said there are
witnesses who saw them killing themselves.
But I can't tell it from their bodies.
I don't know if they really committed suicide.
Your Highness, the generals and soldiers
all saw them committing suicide.
Does Miss Chu not trust my words?
I can swear with my life that every word I said is true.
It's not that Miss Chu doesn't trust you.
As a coroner, she can't draw a conclusion
from the things she doesn't find in the bodies.
Please try to understand.
I was in a hurry to defend myself.
Sorry for my rudeness.
Your Highness, even there are witnesses who saw them committing suicide in public,
there is something strange with this.
Why do you say that?
Among these three men, the lowest officer is still a sixth-rank military officer.
The three of them must all be good fighters.
If they want to kill themselves, there are many quick ways to do it.
Why would one of them strangle himself,
the other drown himself in the tub,
and the last one of them jump into the fire and burn himself alive?
These ways are painful and troublesome.
Why didn't they just use their swords?
I think even they killed themselves, they didn't do it voluntarily.
I think General Leng also has doubts about it.
That's why he asked Commandery Prince An to come.
He has doubts?
He has doubts that they didn't commit suicide voluntarily?
Of course, he would say that.
Didn't he say there are evil spirits?
They didn't commit suicide if they were possessed by evil spirits.
Chu Chu, what's wrong?
Nothing. When Miss Leng said the ways they died are painful,
I feel that something is wrong.
But I don't know what it is.
Your Highness, can I carry out an autopsy?
Autopsy?
To cut them apart?
Your Highness, well...
General Zhao, everything concerning the investigation
will be decided by me.
Thank you for bringing them to the mortuary.
If you have other official duties, you can leave now.
In that case,
I'll leave.
Go ahead and do it.
I'll have someone send you the approval letter later.
Thank you, Your Highness.
It should be them to thank you.
Be careful.
Don't worry.
Leave us.
Yes.
- How's it going?
- Your Grace, it's been verified they found two people.
One is a maid who once served you in the mansion.
The other is a wet nurse from the palace.
The two of them have left where they live and are on their way to Chang'an with them.
Who is looking for them?
Not clear yet.
I heard from the guards who investigated it that they left the palace.
Could it be...? Qin Luan?
Anyway, we can't let two of them enter Chang'an.
Yes.
Take a look.
Good stuff, take a look.
Hurry!
Do you want to die?
Someone stole treasures from Princess Xiping's mansion and fled.
We are here to search all the suspicious vehicles.
It's Princess Xiping's order.
I dare not disobey.
Please, Madam.
They are from Pingkang Residence. I took them out last night for a party.
Madam, please don't mind.
Madam, take care!
How is it going?
We stopped the carriage.
Our people had been following them all the way.
But somehow they changed the people in the carriage.
There were only two prostitutes inside.
What?
Guard them well.
Master, the procuress took them down and got them settled.
What a surprise.
Master, the rumors turn out to be true.
Xiao Jinli and Xiao Jinyu, one of them was adopted,
the other is her biological son. It's pity that the former servants in Princess Xiping's mansion
don't know which one was adopted.
I don't care which of them was adopted.
What I care about is where the adopted son came from.
Send people to find out all the newborn babies in that year
that might be adopted by Princess Xiping.
It's a little too hard for me.
How many babies were born in Chang'an City in that year?
How to find them out?
Do whatever you can.
Think about it.
If Princess Xiping wants to adopt a child, she can do it above board.
Why would she take so much effort and do it secretly?
There must be something strange about it.
The child adopted by Princess Xiping
must not be from an ordinary family.
Either it's Princess Xiping's close friend or relative,
or it has some relationship with Xiao Heng.
Maybe he is another survivor of the rebellious party.
I remember the wife of the rebellious party's leader, Chen Ying,
was close with Princess Xiping.
She died of dystocia back then.
But wasn't the child never born?
Wasn't that female coroner pulled out from a dead woman?
Go to check the Chen family first.
Find out the truth.
Then we can convict them of deceiving the emperor.
This is a good idea.
Master, you are impressive.
You are wise indeed.
How are you doing, Jinyu? Are you used to living here?
We got everything in the barracks.
But it's just cold at night.
I got you extra bedding.
Just tell me if you need anything else.
Don't make yourself uncomfortable.
Every time you wrote a letter to us,
you said you were living well in the army
and it was no different from home.
Why would I feel uncomfortable here?
Did you lie to Mother and me?
I give up. You can live here as you want.
I've checked the things you asked me.
During the days before we went to the mountains with Li Zhang,
they did send a team of soldiers to Qianzhou to buy supplies.
What supplies?
Some commonly used medicinal matterials.
I confirmed with Wu Chen, the secretary in charge of military supplies.
He said there was such a thing.
There is a shortage of medicinal materials in the changeover period.
The nearby county doesn't have much medicine.
They are afraid buying too many medicines will affect the life of the people.
So they went to Qianzhou to buy them.
Has this team of soldiers come back?
Not yet.
This is the list of soldiers sent out.
[List]
Secretary in charge of the military supplies.
He should be the one who can contact the people of the local office most frequently, right?
Yes. Are you suspecting him?
It's impossible.
Although he is in charge of buying supplies, he has no power to deploy troops.
He reports these things to General Leng.
General Leng will use his discretion and assign the task to the next person.
He can't decide who will be sent out.
Timing and subtitles brought to you by The Imperial Coroners @ Viki.com
♫  Nothing can stop me  ♫
♫  From missing you all the time  ♫
♫  The moonlight appears, cold in the late night,
as the world changes  ♫
♫  Only with you by my side can I embrace my yearning for you  ♫
♫  When I close my eyes I meet you once again  ♫
♫  I'll gently brush your hair by your ear  ♫
♫  Life is long, with love and regrets in this world  ♫
♫  With you by my side, no matter how far I go,
we'll never be apart  ♫
♫  With your smile, in this moment, let me
cherish this lifetime  ♫
♫  Only for you, I have to worry about the end of this life  ♫
♫  I’m still young, with my love not yet realized for you, but I'm
willing to be here for you till the end
♫  You can rely on me in this lifetime  ♫
♫  Hope to spend this beautiful lifetime together  ♫