Timing and subtitles brought to you by The Imperial Coroners @ Viki.com
Feng Manor's mourning hall suddenly caught fire.
His Highness disregarded the danger and rushed into the fire to rescue me.
And he spoke up for me before Minister Han.
Thankfully, I didn't betray His Highness's trust.
I found out that the ministers who seemingly died because of accidents
were all killed by the same method at Rugui Tavern.
I also found His Highness's little secret.
However, I'll keep it for him.
[Xiao Jinli]
Shelves with categorized files.
[Princess Xiping]
[Yan Ming]
[Xiao Heng]
These are monitoring records.
How daring!
This is...
[25th Princess Xiping Manor's Banquet]
Princess's Manor.
[Jing Yi]
[Xiao Jinyu]
His Highness.
Your Highness, what are you doing?
I'm drawing Xu Rugui's portrait.
So we can issue the writ of arrest.
But wasn't today the first time you saw Manager Xu?
Can you draw his portrait
when you've only met him once?
[The Imperial Coroner]
[Episode 6]
Qin Luan.
Your Majesty, here I am.
I'm here.
Bastard! What's your problem?
Your Majesty.
Who taught this new guy?
He can't even pour a cup of tea properly.
Your Majesty, don't be mad.
He didn't learn manners well.
It's all my fault.
Why are you still here?
You're so annoying. Go away!
Your Majesty, don't be mad.
I'll clean this place right now.
[Qianzhou]
Qin Luan, where were you just now?
There are strands of beard stuck under your shoes.
Beard?
Your Majesty, these are not strands of beard.
These are my strands of hair.
Your Majesty, when you demanded my presence,
I was trimming the hair on my temples.
I guess I mistakenly stepped on it when I was changing my clothes in a hurry.
I'm sorry for the annoyance.
- Your Majesty, please forgive me.
- Forget it.
Thank you, Your Majesty.
Your Majesty, it's late.
The palace will host a tea gathering tomorrow.
The tea gathering.
I'd forget it if you didn't bring it up.
Go to Three Judicial Chief Ministries yourself tomorrow.
Pass on my order.
Xiao Jinyu must be present, no matter how busy he is with work.
If he doesn't come, you can kidnap him there.
If I don't find him a chance to mediate his relations with the ministers,
I'm worried that he may get swallowed alive one day.
Yes.
It's exactly the same.
Your Highness, you're amazing.
But...
But what?
But I still think that Manager Xu looks a bit weird.
Weird? How?
I can't describe it.
But I had such feelings when I saw him today.
I just find him a bit odd.
Don't rush.
Think carefully. Why is he odd?
What?
I knew!
His look is odd because it's like something that's pieced together.
Something that's pieced together?
Yes. People look different from each other.
But people born in the same regions share similarities in looks.
It's like there's a mold.
People from the Western Regions have a mold.
People from Lingnan Regions have a mold.
People from Chang'an also have a mold.
But Manager Xu's face isn't shaped by any of those molds.
His face looks as if someone shattered many molds
and took parts from those molds to piece together.
On my journey from Qianzhou to Chang'an,
I've seen people from every region,
but I've never seen a man who looks like this.
This is so weird.
What if his parents or ancestors are descendants from other regions?
That's not the case either.
For example, Mules are born from donkeys and horses.
Mules don't look exactly like donkeys, nor horses.
However, in every part of mules,
you can find features of both donkeys and horses.
It seems that the eyes of Lingnan people,
the mouth of the Northern barbarians,
the forehead of Jiangnan people, and the chin of Goryeo people
are all assembled on a face from people who're inside Shanhai Pass.
Xu Rugui might have disguised his look.
Disguise?
Leave the city at dawn.
There will be people waiting for you outside the city.
You'd better be smart.
You know what are the consequences if Xiao Jinyu catches you.
General Zhou, don't worry.
Today is the only time I met Xiao Jinyu.
Even if he has miraculous drawing techniques,
he can only draw my falsified look.
When my natural face was hidden,
Xiao Jinyu was still an infant in the cradle.
He definitely can't recognize me even if I stand right before him.
Cut it out. Can you not boast about yourself?
It's late. Hurry up.
What are the other orders from Eunuch Qin?
He ordered you to hide for a while.
If he has more orders, someone will contact you.
I'm at Eunuch Qin's service.
Xu Rugui is right-handed.
Yes. That's right.
Look at the way he walks.
He's trained in martial arts.
Martial arts?
I've never heard that our manager knows martial arts.
Your manager is used to putting keys in his left sleeve?
Yes. I always see him take out keys from his left sleeve.
Then what does he often store in his right sleeve?
Right sleeve?
I don't know that for sure.
I've never seen him take out anything from the right sleeve.
Lord Jing, why did you come back from the outside?
Xu Rugui is just like a rabbit.
He has dug up several exits to the dark chamber.
Wu Jiang and I have tried all of them. They all lead to the outside.
And this.
What's that?
You'll know when you see it.
Xu Rugui isn't inside.
But there's indeed a stove.
This was left next to the stove.
There are also many shelves.
Each section of the shelves has names on it.
There are my name, your name, and the names of many ministers.
And the things you're holding now.
You're worried that someone killed Xu Rugui to keep him silent.
But it seems more likely that he fled when he knew we'd search this place.
And he tried to burn the evidences,
but didn't put everything in the stove before he fled because he was in a hurry.
because he was in a hurry.
And I dug this out of
the stove.
[25th, Princess Xiping's Mansion Banquet]
- Wu Jiang.
- Yes.
Go back to Three Judicial Chief Ministries immediately.
Bring enough people to Princess Xiping Manor.
Ensure her safety. Don't leave before I come.
Yes.
Your Highness, what's the problem?
It's fine.
Jing Yi, does the chamber have a place that requires keys?
No. It's just a dark chamber. There's nothing more besides the exits.
Xu Rugui has a chain of keys that he habitually stores in his right sleeve.
If those are not for the dark chamber,
he must have another residence as a hiding place.
Another residence?
Where is it?
I don't know. I've never heard that our manager has another house.
This is the map of Chang'an.
Squares represent neighborhoods.
[The Map of Chang'an]
This is Rugui Tavern.
Jing Yi, identify the objects in this room.
Find out from which store the items were bought.
Steward, think carefully about Xu Rugui's daily habits.
Mark the places he visits regularly on this board with chess pieces.
Yes.
This is Huaiyuan Residence.
This is the East Market.
[Pingkang Yiyang Qinren the East Market Anyi Daozheng Changle Jinggong]
[Jiahui Yanfu Huaizhen Yonghe Yongping...]
He's active in this neighborhood, except this region.
[Yong'an]
This should be the place.
Your Highness, this place seems to be a small square on the chessboard,
but, in reality, it spreads across over 20 hectares.
Over a hundred families live there.
There was mud and rice paste mixture at the bottom of his shoes.
There must be a residence. This place seems to be closed to the house under construction.
Take this portrait and ask the neighborhood.
I'll look for his secret residence.
Handle things here.
Yes.
And, send people to each city gate.
Tell each guard leader in my name.
Tell them that there's an important suspect on the loose.
Ask them to carefully interrogate every person who enters or exits the city.
Those without an ID or with a suspicious one mustn't exit the city
no matter what seals, letters, or certificates they hold,
particularly those dressed as Shen Army members.
I got it.
Chu Chu, come with me.
General Zhou, once I leave the capital, please take care of my family.
Sure.
But how I take care of them depends on you.
I get it.
By the way, have you taken care of those killed Feng Jie?
I've taken care of them the old way.
General, don't worry about it.
General, please take this to Eunuch Qin.
Let's go.
[Serene Spirits]
- General Wu.
- Auntie Banxia.
- What's going on?
- I'll tell you the details later.
Where's Princess?
This is the place. Search!
Yes.
Your Highness, no one's inside.
They haven't left for long.
We're one step behind.
Your Highness, we found no one.
Your Highness, no one's here.
This smell.
- Your Highness, check this out.
- What?
- Look.
- What is that?
- Pickled cabbages.
- Pickled cabbages?
Yes, pickled cabbages from Qianzhou.
People from Qianzhou all like sourness.
At our place, every household knows how to make such pickled cabbages.
A special ingredient is needed to make them.
It's something like a broth.
Without it, we can't make good pickled cabbages.
Your Highness, don't you think
that Manager Xu and I might come from the same place?
It's possible.
Rugui Tavern has cooks who're from Qianzhou.
They hoard fish mints regularly.
And there are Qianzhou pickled cabbages in this house.
Even if Xu Rugui isn't from Qianzhou, he must have some ties with it.
[Heaven Opens The Doors]
- General Zhou.
- Open the door.
Why are you exiting the city when it's so late?
It's none of your business. Just open the door when I tell you to.
Someone died of pestilence in my battalion. I'll burn his body outside the city.
Wait.
Haven't you heard me?
General Zhou, any passing vehicle needs
to be examined after the gate is closed.
Hurry. We can't handle the consequences if we let Xu Rugui slip away.
Go!
This man had pestilence.
If he spreads it across Chang'an, you'll assume the responsibilities?
The city gate has its rules.
General Zhou, if I let you exit the city without permit,
when the superiors look for the ones accountable,
me and my brothers will be executed.
Who?
Let him inspect.
General Zhou, excuse me.
Open the door. Let them leave.
- Master.
- How is it going?
Master, don't worry. Everything is going well.
Great. Great. Go to rest.
Yes.
The stove is covered by dust.
It hasn't been used for a long time.
But the storage jars are clean and organized.
They're often moved around.
Master, what's inside?
Black beans.
- I'm sorry. I slipped.
- Don't move.
These beans seem to have been smashed regularly by hard objects.
Something was hidden in the jars before.
Grains can absorb moisture.
Only house owners touch these.
When valuables are hidden inside, they're hardly noticed by others.
This color and texture are familiar.
Yes.
It's Ruyi Pawnshop's unique tassel.
The killers of Rugui Tavern conduct their transactions
through Ruyi Pawnshop.
[Ruyi Pawnshop]
Xu Rugui rented pawnshop's lockers
and shared them with the killers.
[Rented the lockers]
They each hold half of the tally.
[Depositing...]
They complete their transactions without having to meet.
I hope we can catch the killers in time.
Vice Minister Jing.
Where's His Highness?
Your Highness.
Lord Jing, how did you find us?
I can't find Xu Rugui's house. But I can find His Highness.
Your Highness, I've taken care of the things at Rugui Tavern.
The officers who headed to Tonghua Gate
were intercepted halfway by men in black.
They didn't intend to kill
and retreated soon after hearing the whistle.
The officers arrived at the gate
only to find that Zhou Han, from Shen Army,
just led a group of people and left the city thirty minutes ago.
Did the guards search them before letting them leave?
They did. But they found nothing suspicious.
Such a coincidence.
These men in black seem to be there just to buy Zhou Han more time.
I'll go and check it.
Bring people to catch the killer who murdered Feng Jie and the others.
You must catch him alive.
Where is he?
This?
Ruyi Pawnshop.
Xu Rugui must have a tally which is from Ruyi Pawnshop.
Currently, the tally isn't kept at the place it's usually stored.
Xu Rugui might have just gone to
Ruyi Pawnshop to pay the killers today.
Rugui Tavern was closed down today.
Once the killer got the news,
he will retrieve the money immediately before he flees for life.
Take Xu Rugui's portrait with you.
Interrogate the owner of Ruyi Pawnshop.
And you'll know the number of their locker.
Keep an eye on it.
Whoever goes to retrieve money is the killer.
Don't worry.
And this.
[To Commandery Prince An]
Wu Jiang asked someone to deliver this.
I'll go ahead with my work.
Let's go.
The weather is dry. Things are flammable.
Chu Chu's birth date has been confirmed.
Her father's wife has been deceased for years.
The neighborhood knew Chu Chu as Chu Ping's daughter out of wedlock.
The identity of her birth mother is unclear.
Chu Family led a simple life in the neighborhood.
They only had close ties with a lonely witch doctor,
who left the region five years ago,
and is still missing to this day.
A witch doctor?
That's the one who told her stories about Six Gates?
Your Highness, we've arrived.
Greetings, Your Highness.
Rise.
Have Zhou Han and his team returned yet?
No, Your Highness.
They have five riders and a carriage.
Yes.
One of them rode a flat wagon?
Six people in total?
I know all of them.
They're indeed from Shen Army.
There was one corpse on the flat wagon.
The dead was dressed in Shence Army's uniform.
But his face looked unfamiliar.
It's said that he died of pestilence.
They were in a hurry to burn him outside the city.
Just one dead man?
Yes, just one.
No.
I mean there was only one corpse on the flat wagon?
Yes, indeed.
A flat wagon, a rider, and a corpse.
How can the tracks be so deep?
Have you checked under the wagon?
No.
My attention was caught by the corpse on the wagon.
This is a cover-up.
I'm afraid there was another person under the wagon.
Let them exit.
Your Highness, I'm sorry—
It's okay. This happened too quickly. It's not your fault.
Examine more carefully in the future.
I believe Zhou Han will come back soon.
Just let them get back to the city.
Don't say a thing. Just pretend you know nothing.
- I'll send someone to handle the rest.
- Yes.
He even figured that out?
It's midnight already. What happened?
Where's Jinyu?
His Highness is all right.
It's just...
His Highness is so busy with work that
he hasn't had a chance to see Your Grace.
His Highness misses Your Grace.
So he ordered me to come and strengthen the defense at Princess's Manor
to express his filial piety.
Why should he strengthen guards if everything is going well?
I know martial arts and I have guards.
Why do you come to my place when you should be protecting him?
I heard that the mourning hall of Feng Manor was on fire tonight.
Did Jinyu ignore His Majesty's orders and again make a scene at Feng Manor?
- I'll go and find him now!
- Your Grace, don't be angry.
Your Grace, Scholar Xue has told you that
you mustn't intervene with His Highness's work.
That's harmful to His Highness's reputation in the office.
His Highness has been always discreet since childhood.
Your Grace, you should trust him.
How can I trust him when he has caused so much trouble?
Your Grace, His Highness promised to come here after work.
Just wait a bit longer.
Your Grace, His Highness is a man of his words.
He promised to come here later. Then he will.
Why don't you sit down and think about how you'll scold him later?
Otherwise, it'll be like the usual days.
Before you can give a good talking, His Highness will have already changed the subject.
Then, you'll blame me instead.
Fine. Just leave.
You!
You're always on his side.
Master, you finally came out.
His Majesty...
It's fine.
How are things doing out there?
Master, don't worry. Everything is going well.
He has left the city.
It's finally dawn. This night is too long.
His Majesty said that he was afraid that someone may devour Xiao Jinyu alive.
Who do you think should be that person?
Devour Xiao Jinyu.
Devour?
Who?
[Tonghua Gate]
Commandery Prince An is right.
Chu Chu.
Go back and take some rest.
You've been busy working with me all night. You must be tired.
Thank you, Your Highness.
Are you coming or not?
I have other matters.
Then when will you come back?
Why are you asking?
I just find you rather pale.
Come back to rest when you're done with work.
Okay.
Wait.
I didn't have the chance to ask you earlier.
What's the embroidery on your handkerchief? It's a bone.
The fifth rib bone on the left chest.
Rib bone?
Why that?
Because it's the closest place to a person's heart.
When you put your hand on the bone's position,
you can feel your heartbeat.
That's my favorite bone.
Do you find it beautiful?
Yes.
Go.
You embroidered this?
If you don't like it...
Your Highness, there you are!
Where's Her Grace?
She's inside.
Jinyu, where have you been all night?
Come closer. Let me see if you're hurt.
No, Mother, don't worry.
You caused so much disturbance in the middle of the night.
Everyone was worried because of you.
If you don't explain everything clearly today,
I'll greet His Majesty and ask him to remove you from Three Judicial Chief Ministries.
Mother, calm down. You can interrogate me today.
I'll tell you everything honestly.
Wu Jiang, take the guards and leave.
Yes.
I've been busy all night. I didn't even have water.
Can I beg for a cup of tea?
Tea?
You won't even get cold water.
Miss Chu,
let me help you change the medicine.
No. No need. I can do it myself.
These are just minor wounds.
When I made baskets at home,
my hands always got scratched.
I never whined because of the pain.
You're so brave.
No, I'm not.
I'm nothing compared with His Highness.
Chu Chu. Chu Chu.
Chu Chu.
By the way, can I ask you for something?
What is it, Miss Chu?
His Highness has given us the order.
You can have whatever you want so long as it's not livestock
or growable seeds or seedlings.
I want a spoon.
A spoon?
Miss Chu, if you want to eat something,
you can ask the kitchen to cook it.
You don't have to do it yourself.
No. I'm not trying to cook.
I just want a spoon.
A spoon of this size.
This size?
Fine. Mother. I'm already full.
Eat more.
Look at how pale you are!
You must have stayed up late for days.
Banxia, go to the kitchen.
Bring out the calm stews if it's cooked.
Your Grace, didn't you just say you won't even give His Highness cold water?
Of course, I won't.
How can he drink cold water on such a freezing day?
Go and check it. Bring out calm stew if it's cooked.
Yes.
Mother, I'm here today because I want to ask you something.
You promised to let me interrogate you today.
You are to break the promise after lunch?
Now, you'll interrogate me?
Don't you want to know what happened last night?
Take a look at this first.
[Xiao Jinyu...]
[Lynched the remaining members of Chen Ying's party...]
[Xiao Heng escaped luckily...]
Mother.
Banxia. Guard the door.
Don't let anyone enter without my permission.
Yes.
Where are these from?
A tavern named Rugui Tavern in the city.
A tavern?
Why would a tavern investigate your father?
That's why I want to ask you.
Ask me? How can I know?
The man who made these investigation records has fled upon sensing danger.
My men are still hunting him.
These are what he has left behind in a sealed chamber at Rugui Tavern.
There were more records about other people.
They were destroyed by fire.
Among the few scrolls remained, there's one that's about father.
If I'm not mistaken, that man left this intentionally to me.
He left this to you on purpose?
Why would he do that?
[25th, Princess Xiping Manor's Banquet]
On last month's 25th, did you throw a banquet at the manor?
I invited Madam Jing.
Someone is spying on us.
So, I didn't allow Wu Jiang to explain everything clearly to you last night.
Mother, please forgive me.
The audacity!
Mother, don't be mad.
Tell me. Whay do they spy on me for?
They want to find out something from you.
What do they want to know?
Mother, I'm wishing you to tell me.
How can I know?
Mother, father passed away years ago.
His remains are buried under Chang'an.
Why are they going through all this trouble to spy on you, me,
and those who had ties with father?
It seems...
It seems that they're searching for his whereabouts.
Nonsense.
A few days ago, I saw the other half of this pendant.
Where did you see it?
It's in the hands of a girl from Qianzhou.
A girl from Qianzhou.
Is that the coroner you brought to Feng Manor to send your condolence?
Yes.
Then, she...
Mother, don't rush.
It's still under investigation.
No.
Ask your men to fall back. Order them to come back.
Kick that coroner out of Three Judicial Chief Ministries.
No, kick her out of Chang'an. You can't keep investigating this case.
Why?
Mother, about father, are you keeping secrets?
Now, the enemies are hiding in the dark. We're exposed.
This is unfavorable to us.
Mother, please tell me everything truthfully.
Master.
Mingde is here.
Hurry. Hurry. Hurry.
Put them down carefully.
Put them down.
You two. Leave. Go.
Yes.
- Close the door.
- Go ahead with your work.
Master.
Look. Everything is here.
Except those we've burned
and those you ordered to be left to Xiao Jinyu,
every other scroll is here.
Has Xiao Jinyu taken action?
Just as you've expected, Xiao Jinyu ordered his Chief Guardsman,
Wu Jiang, to lead a team of guards
and stand by at Princess Xiping Manor.
They only left when Xiao Jinyu himself arrived.
I guess our wise and assertive Commandery Prince An
is now shaking Princess Xiping's sleeves and begging for his father.
Prince Consort secretly reported the treason of Chen Ying,
the Military Commissioner of Jiannan, to the imperial court.
Prince Consort was tragically murdered by Chen Ying.
When I led Shen Army to suppress the rebellion at His Majesty's behest.
It was too late.
These are what I can bring back.
I'm sorry, Your Grace.
His Majesty is impressed by Prince Consort's loyalty.
His Majesty has decreed the conferment.
Your Grace, please take it.
- I've never imagined that you father would disappear like that.
- No.
So, father's current grave in Chang'an is a cenotaph.
Besides accepting it, what else can I do?
The Imperial Court at that time was so different from the current one.
The conflict between ministers and eunuchs were so heated.
When we heard your father's death in Chang'an,
Chang'an was caught in Ganlu Incident.
The North Yamen led by eunuchs were on a killing spree.
The South Yamen led by Prime Minister were slaughtered.
Even my father was confined in the imperial palace.
The conferment decree for your father was already ordered.
Leng Family, from the Southwest, supports me.
But if I insist to seek justice from the Imperial Court, considering the situation,
I would've already brought calamities on you and your brother before the justice could be upheld.
Mother, it seems that...father might still be alive.
Timing and subtitles brought to you by The Imperial Coroners @ Viki.com
♫  Nothing can stop me  ♫
♫  From missing you all the time  ♫
♫  The moonlight appears, cold in the late night,
as the world changes  ♫
♫  Only with you by my side can I embrace my yearning for you  ♫
♫  When I close my eyes I meet you once again  ♫
♫  I'll gently brush your hair by your ear  ♫
♫  Life is long, with love and regrets in this world  ♫
♫  With you by my side, no matter how far I go,
we'll never be apart  ♫
♫  With your smile, in this moment, let me
cherish this lifetime  ♫
♫  Only for you, I have to worry about the end of this life  ♫
♫  I’m still young, with my love not yet realized for you, but I'm
willing to be here for you till the end  ♫
♫  You can rely on me in this lifetime  ♫
♫  Hope to spend this beautiful lifetime together  ♫