Timing and subtitles brought to you by The Imperial Coroners @ Viki.com
Jing Yi pretended to be a wounded soldier and entered the infirmary.
With his secret inquiry and our public investigation,
we will find out the truth.
I don't believe these people committed suicide because they were
[Neck]
possessed by evil spirits.
[Strangulation marks] [Broken hyoid bone]
Nonsense!
I think he is probably behind the whole thing.
What is he up to
to get Commandery Prince An here?
Does he want to kill him?
Although he is in charge of buying supplies,
he has no power to deploy troops.
He reports these things to General Leng.
General Leng will use his discretion and assign the task to the next person.
He can't decide who will be sent out.
What about the other thing?
I've asked about it.
While I was away, some soldiers left the base.
Did they go back home?
They are deserters.
In fact, those people are not really soldiers.
They were bandits incorporated into the army.
When we send troops to suppress the bandits,
normally we won't kill them unless they commit any felony
or resist desperately.
As long as they surrender, they will be incorporated into the army
and be trained to replenish troops.
Most of the bandits know some skills to fight.
It's much easier to train them than to train those farmers.
Those who escaped were taken in this way.
Do you still remember their looks?
I don't have much impression of them.
Hou Bin led the troops during the battle when they were taken in.
After they were captured, they were trained by Hou Bin.
How long had they been trained in the base before they escaped?
- Less than four months.
- Less than four months?
They were only trained for less than four months and they just escaped?
Yes.
The first six months is the easiest time for them to escape.
After all, being a soldier is not as unrestrained as being a bandit.
Well, is there any problem?
[The Imperial Coroner]
[Episode 28]
Yue.
Why are you here?
Did you get hurt? Kid.
I won't be disabled. And I won't bother you anyway.
You... You... You... You kid...
How can you talk to your grandpa in this way?
Can you grow up?
Your Highness, Miss Leng presents herself.
- Let her in.
- Yes.
Your Highness.
I found something in that man's barracks.
You went to General Leng's barracks?
How did you get in?
[Has the chivalry of the Leng clan...]
Jinli, I need you to check one thing for me.
[Jing Mansion]
Master, our man monitoring Princess Xiping's Mansion came back and reported
that Banxia stopped Zhou Han's carriage at the gate.
It looked like she was looking for someone but didn't find them.
What's the news in the palace?
Our men reported earlier that they have found out
who are looking for the former servants of Princess Xiping's mansion.
Qin Luan made the order.
They not only investigated the former servants of Princess Xiping's mansion,
but also nosed into the rumors after Princess Xiping gave birth to twins.
Rumors?
Why would Qin Luan look into these things?
Keep a close eye on Qin Luan these days.
Let me know if you have any news.
Yes, Master.
The good news that you will be promoted to
the general director in charge of palace affairs has spread far and wide.
Everyone is sending their congratulations.
Take a look. There are too many gifts to be counted.
These people respect you a lot.
Look at this.
This is from the antique store.
The antique store also sent a gift?
You went to their place in person a few days ago.
They must think you are their protector now.
Then they nerved themselves to send you a gift.
It must be a big gift.
It's this one.
[Birthday]
A bronze Ruyi?
What?
Master, he sent you a bronze Ruyi.
What does this mean?
Bronze Ruyi...
[Birthday]
[Swan geese fly by, the red sun rising above the water. Waiting for...]
Didn't you see what's engraved on it?
There are two words missing.
Take a look.
Swan geese fly by, the red sun rising above the water.
Waiting for Rukui...
I don't understand.
What Rukui?
It's Rugui.
Don't you see two words are missing?
[Waiting for...]
The antique store sent this to me to let me know
that they have Xu Rugui.
If I want Xu Rugui, I need to see him soon.
Xu Rugui is in the antique store?
- Doesn't that mean they...?
- A bronze Ruyi.
What an implication.
It's time to meet these little brats.
What's the situation in the infirmary?
Those wounded soldiers are just pawns.
They have guessed more than what they really know.
Fortunately, when I played beetles rolling balls with them,
I got some news.
The first person who went crazy in the army is a wounded soldier in the infirmary.
Wounded soldier...
How is that wounded soldier doing now?
He is basically recovered now. I also sounded him out.
He really doesn't remember anything.
He insisted that he met something evil.
Is there anything else?
The rumors about evil spirits have spread out from the infirmary.
These wounded soldiers have nothing to do.
This bunch of dudes is really garrulous.
After you go back this time, remember to inquire about another person.
Who?
Wu Chen.
Wu Chen? The officer in charge of military supplies?
Yes.
Why do you want to investigate him?
Your Highness, there is an urgent letter from Chang'an.
[Qin Luan caught two maids dismissed from Princess Xiping's mansion long ago]
What's wrong? Is there any trouble in Chang'an?
There must be some trouble.
But I don't know what kind of trouble it is.
What do you mean?
Qin Luan somehow caught two maids dismissed from
Princess Xiping's mansion in the early years.
Wu Jiang worried something bad would happen in Princess Xiping's mansion,
so he observed for a few days
and found out Senior Jing is secretly investigating
the things happening during Princess Xiping's pregnancy.
During Princess Xiping's pregnancy?
Why would he investigate that?
Chu Chu, have you found anything special
after the autopsies of these three bodies?
I don't know if it's special.
After the autopsies, I found out the drowned breathed in more water
and the burned dead inhaled in more ash
than an average dead person would,
but not as much as a living person.
You mean... They were neither dead nor alive before they died.
Yes. That's what I want to say.
Neither dead nor alive...
I think they can be called living corpses.
A living corpse like me?
No.
Let me put it in this way.
If a person is thrown into the water or fire after he is dead,
he isn't breathing and he can't inhale in anything.
But a living person is different. He needs to breathe.
He struggles when he tries to breathe,
which will make him breathe in more.
But these two people are different.
Although they breathed in things before they died,
the amount they breathed in is much less than a normal person.
If you want me to describe what kind of state they were in,
they should be breathing normally until they died.
Is there anything suspicious about the man who strangled himself?
Feng Li is the strangest one.
Generally speaking, it's hard to strangle yourself,
especially in the way he did.
He wrapped a belt around his neck and his hands took
each of the ends.
It's even harder to strangle himself in this way.
Because once a person is strangled to a certain degree,
he won't be able to breathe because of the pain.
Then he won't have that much strength.
He can only strangle himself to death
if he pulls it really hard at first.
But that's not Feng Li's situation.
From the strangulation marks on his neck and palm,
and the fragmentation of his throat,
he didn't strangle himself to death at once.
He used the same strength until he strangled himself to death.
You are saying these three people
were in a state of extreme pain without knowing it?
Yeah, exactly.
What did they eat before they died?
Just normal meals. Nothing special.
Your Highness, I don't believe there is any evil spirit in this world.
But I've never seen or heard anyone who died like the way they did.
Were they really possessed by some evil spirits?
Well? Are you scared?
Who is scared? I'm not scared.
Even if they were possessed,
you can handle the living part, I'll handle the dead part.
As for those who are neither dead nor alive, we will handle it together.
I don't believe there is anything in the world that we can't handle.
If you are scared, you can sleep at my place tonight.
I think I'm going to read the statements sent by Hou Bin till dawn.
Rest assured to sleep at my place. I won't bother you.
I'll read them with you.
Your Highness, something happened to Vice Minister Jing.
What?
- Take me to him now.
- Yes.
- Hurry!
Go!
I'll kill you!
I'll kill you! Kill!
Put the sword down. I'll kill you!
What's happening here?
Go away!
Are you crazy?
What happened?
What's the situation?
General, this Qianzhou's soldier also went crazy.
He is just like the previous mad soldiers.
His pulse is fine.
Good.
Leng Yue, do you have any method to wake him up as soon as possible?
Yes, acupuncture will do.
Take him to my place.
I have something to ask him.
Someone, take him away!
Come on.
If you don't mind, can I go with you?
General Leng, please.
Please.
Why are you still standing here?
It's not the first time you saw something like this.
We got Commandery Prince An here.
He will find out the truth soon.
Act like brave men!
If other people know it, they will mock us for
being afraid of a little mad soldier of Qianzhou.
Well...
Did you not hear it?
Go back to your place!
Just leave!
- Yes.
Doctor Qi, clean this up.
What's more, hurry up and make a list for me.
Yes.
If you need any drugs, I will order them to buy them.
- I'll go to work.
- Okay. Take care.
Master.
[Vice Minister Jing entered the base with Commandery Prince An]
Jing Yi went to Leng Peishan's army with them.
It's said that weird things happened in the base of Military Commissioner.
There were soldiers and generals
committing suicide in public one after another.
Leng Peishan wrote a letter and invited Young Master Jing
and Commandery Prince An there to investigate it.
Looks like Xue Rucheng's trip to the Southwest disturbed Leng Peishan.
He took a step ahead.
Well, Young Master Jing and they...
Commandery Prince An never acted rashly.
Since he dares to go there with Jing Yi and his people,
he must have his own reason.
We need to trust them.
Tell our people in the Southwest that if Jing Yi has any order,
they don't need to report it back to Chang'an, just do what he says.
Yes, Master.
I need to think about it carefully.
It won't take long before
the court knows Commandery Prince An's visit to Leng Peishan's army.
This is the real trouble.
- It hurts! It hurts!
- Don't move.
Dog, you are finally awake.
Dog?
Where am I? Shouldn't I be in the infirmary?
This is my room.
Do you still remember what happened just now?
I remember it was dark.
They were sleeping and I was also sleeping.
Then I wake up here.
Do you have any strange feelings about your body?
My body...
The boards on your arms and legs were broken by you.
The wounds must hurt a lot, right?
Of course, it hurts.
It feels like my arms and my legs are broken.
And my neck hurts, too.
What's wrong?
You went crazy just like those soldiers in the army.
Crazy?
Did I go crazy?
I can't remember it at all.
What did I do?
You did nothing.
You just almost cut the wooden man in the infirmary into pieces.
Do you not remember it at all?
I, Jing...
I, Dog, swear with my life
that I really don't remember anything.
General Leng, he just woke up.
He is still a little confused.
There are too many people in the infirmary.
I'm afraid it will make him nervous and it won't help him recall the details.
It's better to let him calm down a little bit at my place.
I'll let you know if I find out anything later.
Okay. Thank you, Your Highness.
Keep guard at the door.
Don't let anyone come near us.
- Yes.
Jinli, you just saw it.
Those soldiers all went crazy in that way.
It's exactly how weird it is.
Yeah. To be frank, we can't blame the soldiers for being scared.
They just somehow went crazy.
It's really creepy.
Jinli.
Tell us the truth.
Who is that man who went crazy today?
What do you mean?
I told you he is a Qianzhou soldier we saved on the way here.
Jinli, we've talked about it for a while.
The way that little soldier talked and behaved is nothing like a real soldier.
Even the Qianzhou soldiers are slack in their training,
they should at least receive basic training.
Yeah. Who is he?
Could he be a spy from somewhere?
Stop your wild guess.
He is just a Qianzhou soldier I saved.
He is a raw recruit.
He used to be a poor scholar with some literary skills.
How else could he be bullied by the bandits like that?
What's more, even if he is a spy,
will Commandery Prince An not recognize it?
That's true.
Of course.
All right. Well,
we are a little incredulous because of what has happened these days.
This is just a casual chat between us.
We are definitely not doubting your precious brother's insight.
Yeah.
Hou, how is your injury now?
When did you get hurt again?
Just a flesh wound. It doesn't matter.
How does it not matter? Isn't it your flesh?
It doesn't matter?
I heard from Wu Chen that your injury hasn't healed yet.
You are even having malignant sores.
You don't even apply the ointment Doctor Qi gave you on time.
Are you trying to show how tough you are or are you just stupid?
All right.
I mean you two big men are even more naggy than my wife.
Think about it.
Did anyone approach you on purpose?
Or did you do anything that might have revealed your identity?
No.
I got it. The Vice Military Commissioner,
General Hou, came to the infirmary before the meal.
He didn't say anything, but he kept looking at me.
I think he is doubting my identity.
What about Wu Chen?
There is nothing strange about Wu Chen.
After we stopped gambling, he checked the medicinal materials with the old man Qi.
He didn't take me seriously.
I asked about him.
Usually, he takes care of military supplies.
Sometimes he drafts documents for the army.
He has no power to dispatch the soldiers.
The generals and soldiers rarely work with him directly.
They don't have much impression of him.
After Hou Bin left, did you eat or drink anything?
Do you think I'm that careless about my life?
I was really careful.
I was afraid they would put anything in my food,
I didn't take the medicine at all.
While we were eating, I pretended that I preferred the food of the person next to me
and I changed it.
I had some water before going to bed.
But that was the water of someone else.
I drank it after they all fell asleep.
Your Highness, could it be that their target was someone else?
I was so cautious that I overdid it and got myself poisoned?
According to our previous speculation,
someone led us to the army on purpose.
I think that person wants to kill us in one fell swoop.
But we are in the army now, why would he complicate it
and make a move against someone irrelevant?
We've been here for a while.
We are still alive and kicking.
Except me.
But there is no point in just making a move against me.
You also said I didn't do anything after I went crazy.
I was only cutting wood there.
Did he want to run me down?
Leng Yue, you also saw the symptoms of Jing Yi.
Is there any obscure poison or skill
that can make people go crazy like that?
Poison... Skill...
They won't feel tired or in pain when they go crazy.
Just like the way Vice Minister Jing was.
Normally, Vice Minster Jing would have cried out loud
if his hands got hurt like this.
I don't think you are complimenting me or comforting me.
Don't feel pain.
And can't remember anything afterward.
Apply this to him.
This is...
What's wrong?
I brought this medicine from Chang'an.
It won't be any problem.
Jing Yi, did you feel dizzy and thirsty when you woke up?
A little bit.
That's it.
Your Highness, it's datura flower.
Datura flower?
Datura flower is a good remedy for pain.
What's wrong with it?
But it's really expensive.
There are a few people who can afford it and know how to use it.
Normally the flower is used as medicine,
But every part of the datura flower is poisonous.
The seed is the most poisonous part.
It tastes sweet.
Normally people will have hallucinations after taking a few seeds.
If the toxicity is not serious,
the person will act normally after the hallucination.
You can't feel it through the pulse.
I saw it once in Lingnan Mountain.
Someone was selling something like Five Minerals Powder
made with datura flower and other medicines.
Hallucinations?
In other words, those who were poisoned went crazy
because they had hallucinations.
Yes.
If the hallucination varies from person to person, that can explain
why they went crazy in different ways.
The datura flower is precious and rare.
I'm afraid it was provided by Li Zhang.
Miss Leng, if people take such poison,
will they show symptoms right away or after a while?
It depends on the usage and the dosage.
If they take the seed, they will show symptoms after ten minutes at most.
In this case, the poison wasn't in the food.
There wasn't much food left in the stomachs of the three dead soldiers.
They must have finished their meals for a while.
It was definitely not just ten minutes.
Then is it water?
Probably not.
In the infirmary, the water for the wounded soldiers is heated in a pot.
If the poison was in the water,
those who drank the water should all have gone crazy.
How could you go crazy alone?
Then is it the bowl?
We won't know the fact if we keep guessing here.
I'd better go back to the infirmary and keep looking into it.
No way.
Someone wants to kill you and you still want to go back.
Your Highness, I think Jing Yi has gotten the information we need in the infirmary.
It's time to get him back.
Are you worried about me?
Yes, I'm worried about you.
All right, don't worry. I've gone crazy once.
Wake up wherever you go crazy.
I'm afraid of pain and death.
No matter what hallucinations I have, I won't kill myself.
Besides, Your Highness. I think it's not over tonight.
You have to be more careful.
We all need to be more careful.
How dare you sneak into my barracks.
Who do you think you are?
You are way out of my league.
You know I moved this?
Of course.
If I can't see through your little trick, how could I command
the vast army in Qianzhongdao?
My base would be penetrated by spies.
These letters...
Did I put those letters here on purpose for you to find them?
Well, didn't you show these letters to Commandery Prince An?
If Commandery Prince An can't even tell this,
then he doesn't have the ability to rule the Three Judicial Offices.
- Why?
Why not tell you
the reason I couldn't go back when your parents died tragically
in the Ganlu Incident?
That's because if the frontier general
leads the troops into the capital without permission,
it will be seen as a rebellion.
If I did that, the whole Leng Clan would be executed.
At that time, the patriarch put me on a leash
and locked me in the dungeon of the ancestral hall.
How could I tell you that?
I wrote letters to your father
on the anniversary of his death every year.
And I put the letters in a box like a woman.
Well, does it sound glorious?
Will it do any good to you?
Why didn't you tell me
that the doctor said you have...?
Kid, you can't trust a doctor's words.
If you don't trust the doctor, why did you write in the letter
that you will reunite with him less than half a year later?
I was fooling him.
Let me feel your pulse.
How did you fool the court?
General Leng is seriously ill?
No way. General Leng looks so strong.
I heard that he even had a fight with Miss Leng in the training yard this afternoon.
What kind of serious disease does he have?
A bone disease.
Maybe it's an old ailment he got when he fought wars.
During these years, he wrote letters to Leng Yue's father
on the anniversary of his death to send condolences.
He wrote in the letter that he hid his condition from everyone
because he worries that it will cause a disturbance in the army.
He is quietly preparing for his death.
Does Miss Leng know it?
She found these letters in General Leng's barracks.
I was going to let her check if there was
any clue about General Leng contacting Li Zhang
or about illegal minting of coins.
But she found a box of letters
that General Leng wrote to her father over the years.
If General Leng is seriously ill,
he shouldn't be the mastermind behind this.
Chu Chu, do you still remember
the two people who tried to kill Xu Rugui?
Yes.
I remember you said after the autopsy that they were both soldiers.
Your Highness, why do you mention this?
These people are also soldiers.
Jinli found out that before we went into the mountain with Li Zhang,
more than 20 soldiers left the base to buy supplies
under Wu Chen's order.
This is exactly the number of soldiers who showed up in the Prefect's Mansion.
But Wu Chen doesn't have the power to dispatch troops.
Therefore, it must be someone very powerful behind this.
What's more, from the traces of the scene in the wood house that day,
except for the Shence Army who came to kill Xu Rugui,
there was another group of people who wanted to capture Xu Rugui alive.
Your Highness, why do you think
it's General Leng who sent people to arrest Xu Rugui?
Timing and subtitles brought to you by The Imperial Coroners @ Viki.com
♫  Nothing can stop me  ♫
♫  From missing you all the time  ♫
♫  The moonlight appears, cold in the late night,
as the world changes  ♫
♫  Only with you by my side can I embrace my yearning for you  ♫
♫  When I close my eyes I meet you once again  ♫
♫  I'll gently brush your hair by your ear  ♫
♫  Life is long, with love and regrets in this world  ♫
♫  With you by my side, no matter how far I go,
we'll never be apart  ♫
♫  With your smile, in this moment, let me
cherish this lifetime  ♫
♫  Only for you, I have to worry about the end of this life  ♫
♫  I’m still young, with my love not yet realized for you, but I'm
willing to be here for you till the end
♫  You can rely on me in this lifetime  ♫
♫  Hope to spend this beautiful lifetime together  ♫