Timing and subtitles brought to you by The Imperial Coroners @ Viki.com
My mother was killed!
Please redress the grievance for her!
Who exactly is Lady Xu?
Xu Rugui kidnapped Chu Chu, but left her mother's hairpin.
What exactly does he want?
Who...? Who are you?
But everything was in a mess that day.
You may not remember my face.
Or perhaps you have remembered
someone who looked sort of like me in Rugui House.
You... You are...?
I'm Xu Rugui.
[The Imperial Coroner]
[Episode 16]
Why are you here again?
Xu Rugui kidnapped Chu Chu.
- What?
- Tell me. Did you find anything in Lady Xu's belongings?
Why do you care for this now? Go find Chu Chu!
I checked the area where she was taken.
This is what Xu Rugui left there.
It also belongs to Lady Xu.
What do you mean?
Xu Rugui must know something about Chu Chu's parents.
He left the hairpin, so I'll check on that.
Tell me. What did you find?
Or what is it that you know?
You... what do you mean?
Since we left the capital, you've been hiding something from me.
I didn't ask when you didn't want to tell me.
I may turn a blind eye, but do you think I'm really blind!
What are you losing temper at me? What have I done?
I trust you, like I trust the other me in the world!
I believe you won't hurt me,
but you must explain what happened today!
If Chu Chu is dead, I won't let go of you...
or your family!
Are you crazy?
Xiao Jinyu, don't you remember what Qin Luan wants?
Xu Rugui wants to kill us and catch Chu Chu alive! Alive!
Don't you know what that means?
It means, for the moment, Chu Chu won't be dead!
But if you keep losing your temper like this, it'll be too late!
Yes.
I stalked you to the Witch Doctor's house,
and I watched when you opened the coffin.
But it had nothing to do with Chu Chu.
I care for you only.
Before coming to Qianzhou, my father gave me another mission.
He was concerned that there were remnants of the rebels.
He thought you might ignore your safety,
so he asked me to keep a close eye on you!
[To Jing Yi]
These are letters my father sent me.
Read them.
Why did you do those things without telling me?
Why do you think?
Would you have brought me if there were real danger?
Would you tell me?
Chu Chu, don't be scared.
I'm trying to save you.
I won't hurt you.
I brought you here to protect you.
You stay away!
Didn't you ask me before where this place is?
I'm telling you. This is where your mother used to live.
My mother?
Finished?
It's my turn to ask questions.
How do you know it was Xu Rugui who left you this hairpin,
but not Chu Chu who dropped it?
I knew there were two groups, based on carriage tracks and footprints.
They went in two directions.
I found the hairpin in one direction of the tracks.
He knew I would ask my men to search the whole lane.
He deliberately put the hairpin under a basket.
I gave the hairpin to Chu Chu only yesterday.
If Xu Rugui knew the hairpin, he must have known
about Chu Chu's parents.
I'm sure he left me the hairpin for a reason
When I figure out his reason, I'll know what he's after.
When I know what he's after, I'll follow his trail.
Then I may know where he took Chu Chu.
Purpose... Hairpin...
If you're right, I can really find something from the remains.
It's authentic Sichuan embroidery on the clothes.
It's not from an ordinary embroiderer,
but an imperial embroidery workshop.
It's not what common people can use.
And this hairpin...
My mother has a large number of hairpins of a similar style.
It's said that girls and ladies of rich families
wore such hairpins to compete with one another
ten or twenty years ago.
But the more popular they are, the faster they become antiquated.
After it went out of fashion, the hairpins were no longer used.
Among the clothes and jewels,
there's only something special about the hairpin.
I think she wore the hairpins out of decency.
Decency?
Your mother is a princess.
So, she's always dressed up based on imperial rules.
She doesn't need to be concerned about decency.
You don't know that for ladies and girls from rich families
what they eat and the clothes they wear
are not decisions they can make for themselves.
For example, look at the hairpin.
When it was popular, wives of third-rank ministers wore it.
Wives of fifth-rank censors also wore it.
If wives of fourth-rank officials didn't wear it,
when with the other wives, they would be mocked.
Their husbands would be disgraced, as well.
She could afford Sichuan embroidery,
and she had to wear something for decency.
It looks like she was the wife of an official in Jiannan.
However, her husband didn't seem like an official in the state or county.
He should have a higher ranking.
Then he would have precious cloth from an imperial embroidery workshop.
He was more likely to be...
Military Commissioner of Jiannan.
You know my mother?
Of course.
Your mother is the sister of Xu Zongfang,
the master of the Xu family in Guanling County.
Her name was Yixiang. She was the third child.
When she was 18, she married a military officer Yun Yi.
He worked very hard.
As a result of his military exploits,
he became the vice general to Chen Ying,
who was the Military Commissioner of Jiannan.
In the 8th year of Emperor Wenzong, he rebelled with Chen Ying
and killed Censor Xiao Heng who had reported them.
Xiao Heng is the husband of Princess Xiping,
and the father of Xiao Jinyu and Xiao Jinli.
The emperor was furious and sent troops to exterminate all rebels.
Rebellion is an unpardonable crime.
Their families should have been killed.
But at that time, your mother was pregnant.
To give birth to you, she ran away overnight.
In the Southwest, a disaster that could ruin a family
was very likely to be the rebellion of the Military Commissioner of Jiannan.
Looks like Chu Chu's father worked
for the Military Commissioner of Jiannan.
And Xu Rugui knew that before.
If Chu Chu's father really worked for Chen Ying,
his daughter should have been executed.
- Could she be—?
- No.
Xu Rugui may have left me the hairpin
to make me suspect that Chu Chu wanted to run away to escape punishment
and that she arranged the kidnapping herself to do so.
If I check the case in the way he wants,
I'll really make Chu Chu desperate.
No way! You're talking nonsense!
My father can't be a rebel.
He never killed His Highness's father.
You're the criminal. I'll never believe a word you say.
Xiao Jinyu proposed to open the coffin.
Isn't that so?
I knew it.
Xiao Jinyu came to the Southwest to find his father.
Since he met you in Chang'an, he's been suspecting you,
spying on you, and checking on you.
He also tried to make you trust him,
because he wanted to find his father with your help.
Since you two met,
he's been holding on to your pendant, hasn't he?
I know it's his father's pendant.
He's told me everything.
Don't you understand now?
You're of no use to him.
Given how capable Xiao Jinyu is,
by now he must have figured out who your parents are
from examining your mother's remains.
There's a blood feud between you.
If you go back to him, you'll be arrested as a rebel.
Or he'll kill you in a fit of anger
to avenge his father.
He won't do that!
I don't believe you!
Anybody there? Open the door!
Xiao Jinyu always has dealings with criminals.
He thinks of the worst, in case of anything.
When he figures out who your parents are,
he'll suspect that you ran to escape punishment
or even that you planned this yourself.
What does Xu Rugui want?
He kidnapped Chu Chu, for my father.
He set the trap and used the hairpin, to make it seem like
Chu Chu was escaping punishment.
If I fall into his trap,
my father's secret may be exposed.
Then I'll check on Chu Chu and look for my father at the same time.
I can hardly handle two things well.
And I'll take action.
Then he can deceive Chu Chu and make her think she has no choice
but to seek refuge with him and depend on him.
Eventually, he will ask Chu Chu for some clues about my father.
Isn't he considering too simply?
Chu Chu investigated Rugui House
and saw him try to kill us at the Guanling County border.
Chu Chu knows very well what kind of man Xu Rugui is.
Even if her father was indeed a rebel,
she wouldn't believe it at all if he told her.
I won't believe you, no matter what you say.
His Highness never wrongs an innocent person.
He won't wrong me for what I haven't done.
No matter why you kidnapped me, I won't listen to you.
I won't tell you anything or do anything for you.
I know you think I'm a villain.
But you know what?
These past years, I was forced to do evil things.
Chu Chu, I never meant to hurt you.
Since I knew you worked in Three Judicial Offices,
I've been trying to get you out.
But Xiao Jinyu sent men to guard you closely,
I had no chance to save you.
Then when I knew you and Xiao Jinyu were coming to Qianzhou,
I waited for you at the border of Guanling County.
Unexpectedly, I still failed.
Today, when I knew he asked you to open your mother's coffin,
I didn't have a choice, but to kidnap you.
Chu Chu, I did this to save you!
I'm not as smart as His Highness.
But I'm not a fool.
I work for the government, but you're a wanted murderer.
I have nothing to do with you.
Why do you want to save me?
Xu Rugui knows this.
He must have something up his sleeve.
Something more important than Chu Chu's trust in me.
Is that possible?
One kind of trust exists without any condition
and it can't be broken.
Does that really exist?
[On the ninth day of the first month, Xu Zongfang's sister came to him.]
It's the original trust, between family members.
Your mother is my own sister!
You...
You're Xu Zongfang?
I'm your uncle!
No way. You must have spied on me.
You must have heard us.
I won't be deceived by you.
I don't have an uncle like you!
Don't tell anyone about Chu Chu's parents.
All right.
Hey! Where are you going?
When you're in the Southwest,
you must protect Commandery Prince An at all times.
Also, if you meet any remnant of the rebels,
send me a secret letter immediately.
Father, what do you mean?
It's about the rebellion.
If it can't be handled properly, there'll be big trouble in the court.
If I know ahead of time, I can make preparations in Chang'an.
This is what His Highness never understands.
Chu Chu...  this is our old house.
Maybe you've never been here before,
but you grew up in Guanling County, you must know Butler Tan.
He's right outside.
I can bring him in.
I don't believe you!
You...
[Good Luck and Harmony]
- Your Highness.
- You may rise.
Deputy Magistrate Tan, I hear your father was the butler of the Xu family in this county.
You're right, Your Highness.
How old are you?
I'm... I'm 30 years old.
Had you seen Xu Zongfang before he moved away?
Your Highness, I was born in the Xu Mansion.
Before the Xu family moved away, I met Xu Zongfang nearly every day.
Do you remember what he looks like?
I'm afraid I cannot describe his appearance well.
But if I see him again, I would recognize him.
Look at this carefully and see if this is Xu Zongfang.
That's him.
He looks older than I remember.
But that's him.
Did he go back to his mansion lately?
I'm sorry, Your Highness.
To be honest, Your Highness, I've lived in the office lately.
I haven't gone back home, so I'm not sure.
Take me there immediately.
- Yes. This way, please, Your Highness.
- Please.
It's impossible! Impossible!
Chu Chu, what must you hear or what do you want to see
before you believe I'm your uncle?
I'm your real uncle!
Chu Chu, I asked the captured killers.
They were ordered to catch you.
Catch me?
Don't worry.
I'll figure it out.
But you must remember.
If someone takes you away alive, you're of use to them
only as long as you're alive.
They may want to know something from you
or want you to do something for them.
Don't be scared.
You must let them believe they can convince you
and make them put time and energy in trying to persuade you.
Then you can be safe.
And then?
Then run away if there's any chance.
If there isn't, stall for time until I come.
I recognize Butler Tan.
But it doesn't mean this is the old house of the Xu family.
You could have found another house and brought Butler Tan here.
You make sense.
I won't believe you.
Unless... Unless you tell me how my mother died.
I'm telling you, don't try to decieve me.
I inspected my mother's corpse.
Butler Tan, no strangers are here.
Just tell her the truth.
Yes, Master.
Miss Chu, your mother Miss Xu came to Master
all the way from Jiannan to seek shelter.
She said her family suffered from a disaster.
Master found it a bit strange and then had me look into it.
That was when we discovered what happened to your father.
What? Rebel?
It's a capital crime that means all families will be killed!
We can't let her stay.
If the government knows, we'll all be executed.
Yeah, Master.
We'll be killed for sheltering a rebel.
But she's pregnant!
So what? It's the baby of a rebel!
The baby will be killed, anyway.
Tan Hong, hurry! Kick her out!
- Yes.
- Wait.
Wait for what?
If we wait, the government will know!
Stop yelling!
I...
I have a plan.
In order not to get the whole family involved,
Master asked me to handle the problem,
because he was a good friend of the former magistrate.
Sister! Sister, it's me.
Brother? Butler Tan?
You haven't slept yet?
What did you come here for?
Sister, I know you had a tough life.
But I have my own difficulty.
Hope you can understand me.
Brother, what do you mean?
You shouldn't stand.
Come and be seated.
Without telling Master, I killed your mother with the latch
and hit her head to the wall, pretending she committed suicide.
Miss Chu, I had no choice... but to kill her.
We couldn't put the whole family in danger, because of her.
Master didn't know that before.
Chu Chu...
I know. I'm sorry for your mother.
I was too scared.
In case soldiers tracked us down,
I moved the whole family to Chang'an.
To make a living, I did evil things.
From now on, I'll make it up to you!
It was you...
You all killed her!
You killed my mother!
I didn't have a choice.
Until today, no matter what I do, I can't bring your mother back to life.
But, if you want to avenge your mother,
I can let you do that.
- Which one is it?
- Here we are, Your Highness.
Your Highness, it's Chu Chu's voice!
Be quick!
Tell me. Where's Chu Chu?
In the room in the backyard.
Father!
Xu Rugui killed him to keep the secret.
Tan Gui, how many back doors are there?
Three.
Chu Chu!
Master, here's a letter from Xu Rugui.
[Xu Rugui]
He has succeeded?
Have a look.
The female coroner is Xu Rugui's niece?
Isn't she the daughter...?
The daughter of a rebel.
How will you deal with her?
How?
Isn't it right to catch the daughter of a rebel?
It's wise of you, Master.
How shall I reply to Xu Rugui?
Don't reply to him.
Go and find Zhou Han.
Also, ask him to keep a close eye on the Antique Store.
Yes, Master.
I don't think the Antique Store is a simple store.
What? Send someone to kill Xu Rugui?
Go on. Keep yelling.
Do you think others can't hear you?
But... why does Eunuch Qin suddenly want to kill him?
Well, Xu Rugui took his men to ambush Xiao Jinyu in Qianzhou.
Unexpectedly, Xiao Jinli arrived in time.
Xu Rugui ran away alone.
His plan failed. What could he do?
He wasn't convinced, so he followed them secretly.
Guess what he found out?
The female coroner is a rebel's daughter from the Southwest.
Isn't that a good thing? Shouldn't he be rewarded, instead of being killed?
What if he's caught by Xiao Jinyu and he tells him everything?
He's big trouble.
Why don't we keep him, instead of killing him?
I don't think he'll betray us.
We have his families in control, don't we?
He doesn't dare to betray us.
I'm telling you. Eunuch Qin wants you to kill Xu Rugui, at all costs.
Along with his family. Kill them all.
I see.
Will I also kill Xiao Jinyu?
Sure. Of course.
Look how strong you are!
Xiao Jinli protects his brother with his soldiers.
How can you kill Xiao Jinyu with your men?
Don't be anxious.
Right now isn't Xiao Jinli in Qianzhou with his men
in order to protect Xiao Jinyu?
But Xiao Jinyu will leave Qianzhou sooner or later.
Think about it. Once he leaves Qianzhou,
won't you have a chance to kill him?
I understand.
By the way, Eunuch said, when you find the female coroner,
catch her immediately and torture her.
You must make her tell you where the Witch Doctor is.
After you find the Witch Doctor, take back his corpse.
Don't let Xiao Jinyu find him before you.
Here's another thing.
Eunuch Qin asked you
to keep a close eye on the Antique Store.
Chu Chu? Chu Chu!
Chu Chu!
What happened?
Grandfather, what happened to Chu Chu?
Father, what happened to Chu Chu?
I don't know.
She has a fever.
Chu He, go get a doctor. Be quick.
No need. I had a doctor check on her.
The medicine is in the kitchen. Please boil it for her.
Okay. Hurry, go.
If Chu Chu is in danger, I won't let you go!
What are you talking about? Go boil it! Childish boy!
Your Highness, he's too childish.
Don't be angry with him.
I failed to protect Chu Chu. He should blame me.
I should apologize to you.
Don't. Don't.
Your Highness, what happened to Chu Chu?
I was so careless that a wanted criminal kidnapped her.
The person your men took to the woodshed?
Yes.
Leng Yue!
What are you yelling for! Noisy!
Where have you been? What took you so long?
I heard you fought with Xu Rugui.
Are you hurt? Are you hurt?
Aiyoo! I'm fine.
Let me check.
Must I beat you to prove I'm fine?
No need. I'm glad you're okay.
Who's he?
Where's His Highness?
He's accompanying Chu Chu in the room.
Is Chu Chu all right?
She's all right. She was just frightened.
Then she passed out suddenly because she was depressed.
Depressed?
She has had a lot on her mind lately.
Anyone would be depressed in the face of so many problems.
Xu Rugui, I'll see how long you hold on.
Your Highness. Your Highness.
Let me stay with her.
All right. Son, it's getting late.
Go make dinner.
All right. I'll make some food.
I'm sorry.
I underestimated His Highness.
What do you mean?
Don't underestimate the water drops.
When it keeps dropping, even a stone will be worn through,
not to mention his forehead.
You mean His Highness wants a hole in his forehead?
What are you talking about?
I mean don't underestimate the dripping water.
A man feels the weakest in darkness.
At this moment, when he can't see,
he'll feel more vulnerable.
Then we give him a repeated and fixed stimulation, he'll break down.
He'll tell us everything.
What you said even gives me goosebumps.
His Highness looks like a weak scholar and he talks very gently,
but he has cruel ways to torture people.
A weak scholar?
You didn't see how he went crazy.
Today, he pushed me to the wall fiercely and nearly punched me.
Looks like I've got more to learn from His Highness.
Learn what?
You can push me to the wall. But don't use water drops.
Why can't I?
When someone lies, I can use it.
I swear to you. I've never lied to you once.
Really?
Yes.
Let me ask you something.
What did you say to His Highness at the Yamen today?
I said a lot to him.
But I didn't complain about you. Don't worry.
Stop joking. Be serious.
After Chu Chu was kidnapped, His Highness immediately checked where she was taken away.
He then went back and asked you something.
Before saying anything,
he went to see Tan Gui with Xu Rugui's portrait for recognition.
Tan Gui recognized Xu Rugui and then we rushed to the Xu Mansion.
We found Chu Chu and caught Xu Rugui.
You also don't understand why His Highness can connect such clues, do you?
I don't.
We saved Chu Chu and caught Xu Rugui.
But why did Xu Rugui catch Chu Chu?
What did you say to His Highness that he managed to connect Xu Rugui to Xu Zongfang?
Also, isn't Xu Rugui Chu Chu's uncle?
Even if Chu Chu doesn't know, doesn't Xu Rugui know?
His Highness knows more than you have imagined.
But this thing concerns Chu Chu's safety. And some details aren't confirmed yet.
We can't tell you now.
All you must know is that His Highness has clever strategies
and all evil men are within his control.
All right, then.
You sound so mysterious.
I don't bother to know about your official secrets.
Why did you kick me so hard?
The medicine is ready. Hasn't Chu Chu woken up yet?
Go have some rest. I'll stay with her.
Don't bother. She doesn't want me to leave.
I'll put it here.
If it gets old when she wakes up, I'll boil it again.
Thank you.
Please get her a basin of water, a pot of liquor, and a towel.
She still has a fever.
She'll feel better if I cool her forehead.
All right.
What else do you want?
The person in the woodshed...
What's his relationship with Chu Chu?
He kidnapped Chu Chu.
Why did he do that?
I'll interrogate him later.
Chu Chu, you're finally back.
Let's go! Come with me!
If Xiao Jinyu comes, it'll be too late to run away.
Rebels!
I'm not! I'm not!
Your Highness, I'm Chu Chu. I'm not a rebel!
Chu Chu, don't waste your time on him.
He's coming to kill you.
No, he won't.
Children of rebels must be executed!
I was wrong about you.
From now on, we're strangers!
If you surrender now, you'll have an intact corpse for the sake of our old friendship.
Don't be scared, Chu Chu.
I'll take you away.
Ridiculous! Do you think you can run away?
Somebody!
No!
Chu Chu!
I am here.
Don't worry. Xu Rugui has been caught.
You're home and you're safe.
Don't be scared.
Your fever is down. Are you feeling better?
Thank you, Your Highness.
I had a nightmare in which...
which you abandoned me again.
Now that I promised you, I won't break my promise.
Chu Chu, remember.
No matter what difficulty you have, I'll try my best to help you.
I don't have difficulty.
I just had a dream.
Remember that even in your dream.
I'll remember.
Take the medicine.
Chu Chu, you're awake?
Are you getting better?
Much better.
Your Highness, Xu Rugui can no longer hold on.
All right. I'll go check on him.
Have something to eat before you go back for some rest.
All right.
Your Highness.
Your Highness, it's wise of you.
Xu Rugui, I guess you know who I am.
Make up your mind.
You have only one chance.
Once you tell even one lie, you'll spend the rest of your life
under the water drops.
What? After killing so many people, you're scared of mere water drops?
Your Highness, I confess.
I'll tell you everything! Everything!
Please, please stop the water drops.
I beg you! Please stop.
I haven't had dinner yet.
If you want to bargain, I can come after having dinner.
Don't! Don't! I confess!
Rugui House... It belongs to Qin Luan.
He ordered me to kill you and catch Chu Chu.
I knew that!
Tell me! Why are there illegal copper coins with Qian Printing?
Qian Printing...? Illegal copper coins?
I... I don't know.
I don't know. I don't know.
What about Duke Chang?
What Duke Chang? I have no idea!
Timing and subtitles brought to you by The Imperial Coroners @ Viki.com
♫  Nothing can stop me  ♫
♫  From missing you all the time  ♫
♫  The moonlight appears, cold in the late night,
as the world changes  ♫
♫  Only with you by my side can I embrace my yearning for you  ♫
♫  When I close my eyes I meet you once again  ♫
♫  I'll gently brush your hair by your ear  ♫
♫  Life is long, with love and regrets in this world  ♫
♫  With you by my side, no matter how far I go,
we'll never be apart  ♫
♫  With your smile, in this moment, let me
cherish this lifetime  ♫
♫  Only for you, I have to worry about the end of this life  ♫
♫  I’m still young, with my love not yet realized for you, but I'm
willing to be here for you till the end
♫  You can rely on me in this lifetime  ♫
♫  Hope to spend this beautiful lifetime together  ♫